<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.5" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Will Sanders China Adventure Blog</title>
	<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2</link>
	<description>Won't you join me for a crazy crazy China adventure?</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2008 17:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.5</generator>
	<language>en</language>
			<item>
		<title>The Plot Thicks</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=60</link>
		<comments>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=60#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2008 17:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will</dc:creator>
		
		<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=60</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This blog will have a surprise ending.  I guess it was a month ago that I went to Hong Kong, writting this from Xi&#8217;an by the way.  And a week before Hong Kong was the national holiday, and Alice and her husband and Xeng jing bing and I all went to mountain chicken head down [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This blog will have a surprise ending.  I guess it was a month ago that I went to Hong Kong, writting this from Xi&#8217;an by the way.  And a week before Hong Kong was the national holiday, and Alice and her husband and Xeng jing bing and I all went to mountain chicken head down in south Henan, just for the weekend.<br />
That was a nice weekend, Alice is my good friend and a teacher at my former school.  I have talked about her here before, remember?  She often tells me how jealous she is that I get to travel around the way I do, so I figured we would plan to have an adventure together.  First we were going to go to Huang Shan which is one of the five important Taoist mountains, but it was a holiday weekend and we couldn&#8217;t get train tickets so we instead figured on mountain chicken head.<br />
But I started to tell you about Hong Kong, got all sidetracked.  I will come back to Chicken head, first Hong Kong.  I also have to remember to tell you about my last few days here in Xi&#8217;an, I&#8217;ve been having a blast, and I promise if we make it to the end their will be a big surprise ending.<br />
So Hong Kong.<br />
Hong Kong is great, I mean it!  Imagine this: Hong Kong is one of the biggest and I would assume most econamically prosperous cities in the world.  Got to be, no?  It is huge, and the night sky line is dotted with giant glowing neon corrperate logos, some as big as foot ball fields.  And every single person is from every single different corner of this ever shrinking planet, and the streets are teaming with them shoulder to shoulder hustling and bustling, always on their way, always moving.  And their are so many museums and things for tourists to do, and the subway is so easy and fast that only an asshole with money to burn or to show off would have hubress enough to own and drive a car.  And the side streets really are links to times past, the narrow stone roads wind and vendors scream and food steams and banners strung up from one side of the street to the other wave in the wind, and in the morning you can see little old ladies doing Tai Chi in the parks and in the late afternoon you can see them in their shops or behind their street stahls asleep and every so often incense from a hidden way temple wafts through the tepid air.  It is a huge place and it makes you feel tiny and it is doublessly amoung the greatest of all metropolis&#8217;.<br />
Now imagine this:  Their is an island 20 minutes away from Hong Kong island by ferry, it is almost as big as Hong Kong island.  One would assume that human nature being human nature, that place would be covered with starbucks and mcdonalds, paved and covered, high rises and all the rest, right?  That is what I would have figured, but no, I would have been wrong.  Lantao island, which is (like I said) almost as big as Hong Kong island, is kept pristeen for hiking and camping, aside from the occasional fishing villiage that lines the shore, and always has I would think.  I took a bus to get to the giant Buddha statue and it took two busses over an hour to get to the other side.  Think about that, instead of developing they just left it the hell alone.  I really love Hong Kong.<br />
The big Buddha was maybe thirty feet tall on top of a mountain and it was way cool.  Somehow no matter where you stood in front of the thing the smile followed you.  Across the parking lot was a monestary which was recomended by George from Shangqiu.  George had lived there for a few days, I didn&#8217;t have that kind of time, I had to mess with sorting out my visa, which was the real reason for my trip.  The monestary was very calm and very peaceful, singing was in the air and a cool breeze rustled the leaves in the trees.  The Monks all smiled as I passed, and I could see how one could live in such a place.  It was so peaceful.  I had to stop and sit under a tree for the better part of ten minutes, just drinking in the scene.  Man, what a wonderful feeling.  I could show you pictures of the place but it wouldn&#8217;t make your soul thump, no man.  You just got to go to feel that.  And the place is so filled with love and quiet, I don&#8217;t know about you but growing up in a less than religiously active family kind of left me feeling strange and out of place in a church.  Like I might do the wrong thing, or fart loudly mid serman (and have to sit in my own pew, HA) or kneel when it is time to bow or duck or whatever they do.  I once took communion by mistake.  It was at a funeral or wedding or something and everyone else was lining up to go to the front and someone said I didn&#8217;t have to and I said that I didn&#8217;t mind as if they were worried about putting me out, so me not wanting to offend anyone by poo pooing their weirdo ritual I ate the cookie.  Does that make me Catholic?  I certainly hope not.  The point is that when in a temple on a mountain top filled with smiling monks I never feel uncool or out of place, and I know almost nothing about Buddism beyond the basic starter shit that you all know too.  I know I can&#8217;t see myself meditating, and aparently they don&#8217;t eat meat, which I enjoy doing.  So maybe I will just be a bad Buddhist, if it makes me happy to feel nice when I go to a Temple than I don&#8217;t see that I am hurting anyone, although I do feel like a poser at times.<br />
Buddha doesn&#8217;t seem to mind, why should you?<br />
So after the Monestary I took a trail that took me up the side of a mountain.  I didn&#8217;t go the whole way, it was really steep, but I did go really really far, and I sat on the side of a cliff, I hadn&#8217;t seen another living person in an hour.  On the other side of the valley below was another mountain, on top of that mountain I could see the giant Buddha where I had been earlier, now it was tiny.  I got to thinking about the old me, the guy who wouldn&#8217;t have really wanted to go tearing up a mountain alone.  dependent on other people&#8217;s help, sad, no direction.   And I got to thinking back on the whole year and a half I have had.  I thought about where I had been, and you know it occured to me that I am proud of myself.  I have backpacked through seven countries, and I did it alone on my own steam.  I don&#8217;t like to brag, but it is important for us to recognize that we arn&#8217;t neccesarily the shitty people we make ourselves out to be sometimes.  I am lucky sure, but I am strong enough to make it, the strength to endure as the Ramones song says.  That is what I was thinking all alone up there on that mountain, looking out across a valley at the giant Buddha.  After a while I walked down that cliff a little bit taller than I had walked up.  Then I saw bees and freaked out running, I don&#8217;t like bees.<br />
Yeah yeah, so the week before that I was doing mountain chicken head with Alice and her husband and Xing Jing bing.  Xing Jing Bing is a former student of mine from my days at the highschool and a current student of Alice&#8217;s.  I gave him the name, and it means crazy boy.  I called him that in class one day and the whole class stood and gave a screaming ovation in agreement.  That may have been the longest laugh I ever got out of a class of kids, I do so love making them laugh.  The train ride over was long but the Henan province is green and beautiful now, not all grey and brown and dead looking like it is in the winter.  This time of year it is green with yellow flowers, it looks like Monet&#8217;s take on a Chinese farm landscape.  So we were climbing the mountain, and it turns out that Alice has never been in the woods before.  Ever, no shit.  So she wanted to stop and play in the creek every five feet which was funny and we were in no rush.  A few times we went tromping off the trail into the forrest, she had such a great smile the whole time, I was mainly enjoying how much she seemed to be enjoying everything, she was a child on Christmas and it was a cool thing.  Gidy would be a good word.  Xing Jing Bing ran ahead of us up the mountain and we found him climbed all the way up a damn tree which was almost hanging over a straight cliff on the edge of nothing, his crazy ass had no idea how to get down, like a cat.  He had to jump and I caught him.<br />
The mountain itself was nice enough, but everyone said it looked like a chicken head and I couldn&#8217;t see it.</p>
<p>quick note, I am in a public internet cafe right now and the guy in the computer two computers down is totally looking at porn, but he keeps hiding it thinking nobody can see.  He just caught me looking and I laughed at him.</p>
<p>The next week I went to Hong Kong, and the week after that I was back teaching.  That week the first two days I had to give my kids a talk about some sad stuff that was happening, the second two days I brought cake and we had a big party.  I fed them all cake and then we had a talent show, anything the kids could do, even stupid talents, I explained that if anyone could fart on command then they were the grand champians of the whole school but nobody could, or would own up to it if they could.  I did have a few kids that could do some cool stuff, dancers, singers, Tai Chi, kung fu, one kid wrote me a message on a desk with cake icing.  They were really sweet.<br />
TERRACOTTA WARRIORS, COME OUT TO PLAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAY<br />
TERRACOTTA WARRIORS, COME OUT TO PLAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAY</p>
<p>This week I am in Xi&#8217;an, I came up for the long weekend with Wei, by good buddy.  Wei is the coolest guy I know in China and we will always be friends.  I hope he doesn&#8217;t mind if I tell you this, I don&#8217;t think he will, but Wei&#8217;s wife left him a couple of months ago, he loved her so much.  Wei was all broken up and came over to my house several nights, we drank beer over it and I tried to be a brother for him.  Over the past month he seems to have been able to rebuild his life.  He has strength I may never know, he seems almost OK with things now.  I admire him a great deal, the way he has kept it together, he is hurting though, you can see it the poor guy.  So we figured we would go to Xi&#8217;an togther.  The train left Shangqiu at 6 pm and arrived at 5 am,  we had seats instead of beds so I didn&#8217;t sleep but maybe one hour, Wei managed to get maybe three I guess.   When we got in at 5 we figured we would just say fuck it and go straight to the terracotta warriors.  We had that silly no sleep energy, and after a hearty meal of a big mac (the Mcdonalds in Xi&#8217;an doesn&#8217;t do breakfast) we were off and made the hour bus ride only to find out we were an hour early.  The sky was dark that morning, at 8 am foggy chilled wind whipped around and the temperature was dropping.  Birds were going bat shit crazy, shooting like bullets all around in a frenzy, tree tops were bobbing around like rowboats in rough sea and the sky was getting dark.  A storm was in the mail, Wei and I were both in tee shirts.<br />
Wei and I ran into the complex which had three large buildings just as the sky open up in freezing buckets.  Everyone else was running into the close one, but I could see one with a roof that was arched like an airplane hanger, this jived in my mind with pictures I had seen of the Warriors so I said we should go to that one first.  Well it turned out to be the biggest chamber and what&#8217;s more the place had one security guard, 6000 stone warriors, 70 chariots, god knows how many horses, and Wei and I.  Our own private army inspected by us alone.  This was a rush in itself, but the greater thrill was the sight of the warriors.  I mean these things really are amazing.  I knew they had different faces but they also have different body types, some fat, some skinny, some old, I saw a few that looked like teenagers, some tall, some short.  Some slouched slightly.<br />
And did you know that they know these 7000 warriors all together are just the tip of the iceberg?  They know that the pits close to the tomb are more impressive and of larger numbers.  Did you know that?  One reason they have not dug them up yet is they are still not quite sure where to dig, often burial mounds were built near a tomb to trick robbers.  Also there is the problem of the oxygen.  In 1974 a farmer was digging a well and found the statues by mistake.  They say that when they opened the chamber the statues were all painted but the sudden burst of air made the color fade within ten minutes.  They are waiting until the technology is up to the challenge, so I&#8217;m told.<br />
The warriors are guarding the tomb of  Qin dynasty Emperor Qinshihuang who started the great wall at age thirteen, and at the age of thirty seven was able to conquer the other six warring city states and for the first time unify China under a central government.  He created unified systems of law, weights and measures, and written language.  He also killed a lot of people and was known as an all around evil bastard.  For four decades after his death people were building terracotta warriors to guard his tomb, and what kills me is when they were finished they buried and hid the whole thing.  One of the greatest artistic achievements in man&#8217;s history and they didn&#8217;t want anyone to ever see.  To them it was all in honor of their fallen Emperor and about following his wishes, they performed this miracle for one person, following his orders to the letter, losing many workers lives in the process.  And all for a guy who was already dead.<br />
I just finished reading a really good book that my ace Carson sent me.  The book is called Stiff and it is all about the way our society uses dead people for science and it is about what will happen to our bodies when we are not alive.  In the last chapter the author talks about what she thinks she will do with her remains.  She leans towards something simple and points out that when a person&#8217;s last wishes are elaborate and complicated or expensive it is really a way for the dying person to ensure that they can still exert their will over their families even after death.  So if people are still making statues for me four decades after I check out then you can all say that I was just as much of an asshole as Qinshihuang, Emperor of the Qin dynasty.</p>
<p>Three months ago I was in Macao at the same hostel I have told you about, the one which I had given the fake name Septembers to, so as not to embarass the real people with the likes of me.  This last time was my fourth trip, I use it as an in and out point for other countries.  I was hanging around the hostel and luck presented me with these two new wonderful friends, they were a pair of young lovers from Burma.  I will say this but I would really like to stress that I am not just saying the following statement, rather, know that I am meaning it like a motherfucker: they may be the nicest people I have ever meet.  They were so sweet and immediatly wanted to become good friends with everyone they met.  That day they met me and friends we became.  The girl was named Nyi Nyi and was from a Buddist family and Nandor&#8217;s family was Muslim.  They are running off to study in another country and plan on getting married even though their families will not approve.  Nandor told me that Nyi Nyi had a secret wish to boast to her family that she had had a very great day in Macao and I promised I could make that happen, and the next day we could all three go to the China Embassy to sort out our visas together.  We went out that day and saw everything in that town, and I told them I could show them a great time because I happened to be the Prime minister of Macao, and so they called me prime minester the rest of the day.  We all laughed easy and had a day which proved highly boast worthy, at the end of which they took turns using the hostel computer to send all the photos I had taken home, boasting had comenced.  One night they wanted me to watch a movie they had downloaded on their laptop.  They said it was a movie about their country, so I said sure.  The movie wound up being Rambo 4.  If you are unfamiliar with Rambo and what he does I would refer you to parts one through three, part four is more or less the same thing but this time it&#8217;s in Burma.  He kills so many people, all soldiers from the Burma government, the best part is when Rambo uses a land mine to explode a whole entire mountain, shock waves are sent all around and he just barely escapes.  I asked them what they thought about Rambo doing this in their country and they loved it.  The Government of Burma is one of the worst bunch of bastards in power anywhere and Nandor and Nyi Nyi kept telling my how great Rambo (not Sylvester Stallone) was for making a movie which lets everyone know about their government.<br />
The next day we went to the China embassy early, I had gotten the letter the school had faxed to the hostel which requested that I get a worker visa for the next six months.  This is because the school didn&#8217;t want to spend the money on the right kind of teacher visa as I was only doing one semester.  So The friday before I had dropped off my paper work and now just had to come and get it, imagine my suprise when I picked up my passport to find a two month worker visa instead of a six.  More on that later.<br />
Meanwhile I hadn&#8217;t talked to Nandor or Nyi Nyi in the past Three months, but we have been emailing the past few days.  I just got word that Nandor has heard from his family and they are ok, but Nyi Nyi hasn&#8217;t gotten word from Hers yet, and it has been a few days.  If you pray please do so for these people, and the people of Burma while you&#8217;re at it.<br />
The other cool thing about that trip to chicken head mountain (jigongshan) was that Alice&#8217;s husband Jack had a friend who worked in a nearby hotel and spa.  We got the fancy treatment for free, yes we did.  We got to go to the pool, hot tub, suana, work out room (I lifted a little) room of comfy chairs with attatched TVs, archery range, and even a rock climbing wall.  So it turns out I can&#8217;t rock climb, maybe I was never meant to.  It was pathetic.  The best was on the bottom the guy with the rope was a skinny little Chinese kid, I fell of the wall at one point and my droping hoisted this dude in the air like a kite.  After that I went back to the pool.<br />
Alice and Xing jing Bing had never been swimming and didn&#8217;t know how.  I am glad to say that after two days I had them both doing a mean dog paddle.  Alice was funny, every five minutes she demanded that I watch what a good job she was doing and I would tell her what a good job she was doing and she would say &#8220;really&#8221; and I would tell her &#8220;really really good.&#8221;<br />
Ok, now back to Hong Kong.  I had to get up really early and catch a subway under the harbor to get to the line for the China Embassy one morning, which actually isn&#8217;t an embassy but it has some other funky name because Hong Kong is part of China.  At any rate I got there an hour early to find the line already around the corner.  I had a book but found myself vastly more entertained by people watching all the folks from different countries.  I was armed with my passport and a letter which had been written by my school just like before.  This was at the end of my two month working visa and I was now missing work to be here.  The coolest part was the school was paying for my train and my visa.  The guy who I work with at the school had said that they would do the hotel too, the day I left he laughed and said no, they would not.  He always tells people what they want to hear instead of the truth, always leaves one guessing.  But a paid trip to Hong Kong ain&#8217;t all bad, especially a week after a three day weekend climbing a mountain with friends.<br />
So they finally let me in the building and I went upstairs and got my id photo taken and after 20 minutes my number was called and I presented my papers to the lady in the window.  The paper made the her frown, she was not at all happy.  She looked very concerned.  The lady in the window was less than pleasant.  A little on the touchy side.<br />
The paper, it turns out, is pretty much just a piece of paper with a simple message in Manderin, &#8216;please give this man a worker visa for two months.  Thank you&#8217; and then an official stamp.  It had no date, it had nobodies name, it had no address, it had no contact email or phone number, it didn&#8217;t even have the name of the school, all of which were needed.  Any idiot could have typed this up, it proved nothing.<br />
The guy at my school has done this before, you know?  It is only illegal in the strickest sense of illegal, the term illegal itself has another connotation in China.  I just found out the small taxi&#8217;s made of motorcycles, the ones I take every day are &#8220;illegal&#8221; but it only means they have to pay the cops a fine when ever the cops want shake down money.  Hundreds of them whizz around the streets every day and nobody goes to jail or cares.  This worker visa instead of a teacher visa has worked before for our school, hell it worked for me two months ago.  Now it didn&#8217;t seem to be working.<br />
I told the lady in the window the line of bullshit just as I had been instructed.  I said I was a visiting scholar, whatever that means.  A worker visa is for like, say if you are building a bridge or something.  They look the other way, or always have before.  The lady in the window said this would not work.  She said I was either a teacher or a tourist, if I was a teacher I need a teacher visa and either way the maximum I could have was one month.  That is because of the Olympics, the stupid Olympics, they are cracking down and unless you are only going to Beijing for the games they don&#8217;t want you in the country, so the longest tourist visa is one month.  She looked at my soon to expire visa, a two month worker visa, that really got her mad.  She told me to step out of line and rewrite my form and get a tourist visa or nothing at all.  Friends, this was an &#8216;oh shit moment&#8217;.<br />
I paced, I freaked out.  It took me a half hour to find a coffee shop with a public internet and another half hour and three cups of coffee waiting for my turn.  I wrote to the guy at the school, it was a very careful dance on the line of not burning my bridges but diplomatically allowing them to know my concern.  I will not teach on a tourist visa, I told them.  That is just plain stupid illegal not wink wink illegal like the worker visa thing, and if caught they would ammend my passport and I might not get back inside China.  I said I wanted to go on teaching, my plan was to get the tourist visa just to reenter and have the school change it to the right teaching visa.  Now the line was endless and I spent the next five hours waiting.  I made friends with a dude from Turkey and we passed most of the time with good conversation.  He had to pick up his kid from school and was freaking out so I gave him my number, which was lower and only cost me ten more minutes.  But he was a nice guy and he really did need to get his kid from school so I didn&#8217;t mind.  So I applied for the tourist visa and arranged to pick it up the next day.<br />
I spent a lot of time wandering alone in Hong Kong.  A big city with nobody to share it with is a lonely scene.  I know because I am in Beijing now.  Man, it is weird just walking around, going to museums alone.  Eating alone, last night I wanted to hit up a bar, there were so many good looking ones, but a bar is just sad if you are solo, for me anyway.  I ate snake on a stick and nobody was there to tell me how gross it was.  I watched the Jet Lee Jackie Chan movie last night, which is good for the fighting and a few funny things.<br />
So I went back to my city, my Shangqiu with a one month tourist visa.  I wanted to keep teaching, I didn&#8217;t want to leave early.  The worst would be the students, my wonderful students who have worked so hard for me, surely the school would be able to fix this, no?</p>
<p>ready for the surprise?</p>
<p>Manuels at 8, Monday night, see you there.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?feed=rss2&amp;p=60</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>ENDLESS INDONESIA</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=59</link>
		<comments>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=59#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 14:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will</dc:creator>
		
		<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=59</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[CHINA ADVENTURE DISCLAIMER
CHINA ADVENTURE DISCLAIMER
CHINA ADVENTURE DISCLAIMER
The occasional choice swear word aside, I have always tried to keep this blog appropriate for the zoo going children, as my friend Danger Woman (super hero for the disabled and karaoke song bird of justice) would say. I have all sorts of people reading this thing, my mom [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>CHINA ADVENTURE DISCLAIMER</p>
<p>CHINA ADVENTURE DISCLAIMER</p>
<p>CHINA ADVENTURE DISCLAIMER</p>
<p>The occasional choice swear word aside, I have always tried to keep this blog appropriate for the zoo going children, as my friend Danger Woman (super hero for the disabled and karaoke song bird of justice) would say. I have all sorts of people reading this thing, my mom for example. The following adventure is all about Malaysian porn, my surviving a death defying jungle motorcycle crash, and eating psychotropic mushrooms inside a volcano. So here is the thing, if you are the sort of person (and I am talking about my mom, for example) who does not care to read about such things, maybe just skip this adventure all together. As for everyone else, if I don&#8217;t have your attention by now, I don&#8217;t suppose I ever will.</p>
<p>The following was copied from a now nearly destroyed notebook from the road</p>
<p>MALAYSIA</p>
<p>So next I did a few days in Malaysia, just to sort out my visa.<br />
Spending only a few days in a country is a bit of a tease, the Malaysian people are so wonderful. But it is almost as expensive as Singapore so I had to split pretty fast. I will tell you one highlight from Malaysia, here goes.</p>
<p>I went to a city called Malacca, once a major hub for sea trade back in the pantaloon and pirate days. Lots of cool old buildings with colonial influence. Also lots of museums, which I spent the day exploring. After going to the maritime museum, (which aside from being housed inside a big ship was not very interesting) I happened upon the customs museum, which was free. I am still not all the way sure why I should be at all interested in the customs house in Malacca, or why it deserves a museum, but free is free and they had air conditioning besides so in I went.</p>
<p>And most of it sucked, there was a huge room with pictures of the customs staff from the 20s, 30s, and 40s, each of which had an aristocratic white guy in a white suit with a white tie sitting center front. The white guys in each picture were flanked on all sides by a lot of Malaysian looking guys in uniforms, proof of how things must have worked when it was a colony of Great Brittan. Dullsville. Nothing was in English. Boring, stupid, dumb.</p>
<p>In the back they had a display of obviously plastic toy guns. I assume that this is the area where they show the kind of things that they confiscate at the border, but I am in a museum looking at a crappy 99 cent plastic cap gun display. Dullsville. Then further back was a wooden statue of a naked woman with her legs spread. Hmmmmm. Behind the woman was a room with a long slit window at eye level, like the door to a speak easy from an old movie, a red button was next to the window.</p>
<p>I pushed the red button.</p>
<p>The instant my finger left the red button a light popped on in the far right corner of the small dark room which I was peering into through the narrow slit window. Under the light I could just make out what looked to be centerfolds from smutty magazines of nude woman. A recorded voice started frantically narrating in Malaysian, the voice was really going for it, narrating like it&#8217;s life somehow depended on it. Very soon that light cut out and another light cut on in the opposite corner, this time they were all wooden statues of people having sex. Still more narration, I couldn&#8217;t tell what the man was saying about the statues but I could tell the he was really starting to come to a boil about the whole thing. That light shut off abruptly. You may think I am making this next part up but I do have pictures, in the center of the room a light popped on illuminating a tall three sided column with shelves all the way up. Sitting on each shelf was some kind of sex toy, dildos, anal beads, I couldn&#8217;t see what else, because as soon as this light came on, column started spinning in place at a high speed. I was mystified at the sight of this totem pole to perversion, this five foot phalus of spinning filth, this mighty Malaysian masturbatory monolith. And you could tell that the narrator was going absolutely crazy. The spell seemed in my memory to have lasted ages, but I am sure it was only a few seconds. When that light shut off a TV moniter in the back of the small dim room came to life, I was starring into the moaning eyes of a white woman on the screen. As the camera panned back I could see a number young men who may well have been causing the moans, actually I could only see the backs of their heads. 1970&#8217;s music had taken the place of the narrator, and after a few more seconds the whole thing all went dark and quiet.</p>
<p>I stood there like a fool, wondering if I had really seen what I had just thought I had seen. After pressing the red button five more times I concluded that I had.</p>
<p>The other cool highlight of Malaysia was that when I came to Kuala Lumpor which is a huge city, a group of young school students took me with them on the bus, across town, and helped me find the right bus to take, even though I am sure that they didn&#8217;t need to go anywhere near there. As I was thanking them I told them that they had really made me think very highly of their country. Then I took a four hour bus ride through amazing beautiful forests and jungles. I want to go back so much. But like I said, it was a bit expensive, cheap by US standards but steep for me, so I had to split.</p>
<p>SUMATRA</p>
<p>The boat landed in a port town called Dumai, a dusty undeveloped place with one or two story shop fronts along with a sparse landscape dotted with shacks, very little else going on. I paid a guy to take me to the long distance bus station, me hanging off the back of his motorcycle, which is a common taxi in South East Asia, especially the poorer parts. I think that for these guys the motorcycle is the single thing they own outside of their families shack and their clothes, and the motorcycle becomes a very important tool for transportation, revenue, as well as the hauling of large amounts of goods which is achieved through a precarious balancing act. Today, the cargo which was being balanced on the back of the bike precariously happened to be me with my pack pulling me backward as we speed down the dirt roads dodging the multitude of other bikes along with occasional chickens.</p>
<p>At the station I bought a ticket for Lake Toba, more on that later. The ticket office was a large concrete block room, empty aside from a desk in front and a wooden pick nick table. The locals were friendly enough and I had many hours to kill so I sat with them and passed the time of day. After a while, a Swede showed up also trying to get to Toba, and together we walked down the street to the bus station. While we waited, the Swede took the opportunity to show off his fancy bug zapper, which was an electrified tennis racket. He was so proud of this thing, and with little else to do we took turns trying to fry the fly&#8217;s, many locals watched with casual interest.</p>
<p>A guy approached us, a teacher at a local school, could we speak to his kids to help them practice their English? He explained that when he heard that we had gotten off the boat he had been running all over asking everyone trying to find us, and his school wasn&#8217;t far away and it would only take a little while. The Swede said no, we should stay put so as not to miss the bus. I said if the guy wanted he could go and get his students and we could talk to them right there at the station. Delighted, he ran off and a little while later two motorcycles arrived carrying 10 kids. They seemed a little shy and nervous at first but opened up with time. They were seniors, off to Jakarta next year, they were very sweet and just as nice as they could be. The Swede asked them about arranged marriages which made for an awkward moment, but they said it was common practice, and they told us that they really didn&#8217;t mind because they had total faith in their parents judgment. Different place, man.</p>
<p>It was so much fun talking to them, they reminded me of my Chinese students. Their smiles and laughter gave me a real kick, it was an energy that was warm and sunny, and it made me feel so happy for hours, like being high on goodness. The goodness filled me up and when something as powerful and unstoppable as the smiles of children from other countries hits you, you smile back.</p>
<p>HELL BUS</p>
<p>The bus from Dumai to Toba was all night, it sucked and sucked and sucked and sucked. Man, it sucked horrifically. The main transit artery of Sumatra is a two lane road, potholes and dirt. The game seems to go as fast as you can in the wrong lane, laying on the horn until the oncoming traffic becomes too much of an impending inevitable eventuality, then jump back into the safety of your lane with whole inches left to spare, and bonus points for making the entire bus damn near wheelie in the process, sending all lose items and people sailing and jerking around like rag dolls with whiplash. This all night chicken game went along with loud blasting Indonesian pop music (granted, it is a million times better than Chinese pop music) and no AC. The driver was a very sad man, I decided, obviously depressed to the point of suicide. I wondered why he didn&#8217;t just get it over with quietly at home, with a rope or poison or pills, I wondered why he seemed to be trying to take us to the other side with him. He was putting his foot on the floor on the turns. Anyone who has ever played any nintendo driving game as a child (F zero, Grand Turismo) knows the simple rule that you do not accelerate on the turns, that is common sense. He would have to slam down on the breaks in order to keep us from flying into a ditch which caused the whole world to come to a crashing hault. Who does that, blog believers, WHY? The best part of the all night suicidal bus ride came when we got to a mountain pass with no road. The solution had been to bulldoze dirt into a huge ridge that was not flat on top, so we went down a cliff of sliding dirt.</p>
<p>This was the only time the whole night the driver switched off the music, we went very slow. The driver may have been suicidal, but he wasn&#8217;t crazy. I noticed that every passenger sat on the edge of their seat, eyes wide. Half way down the slope on the bottom of the ditch we could see another bus which had landed wheels up. This sight did not instill confidence.</p>
<p>Later, I slipped a green army cap over my eyes and tried like hell to get some sleep, and in the dead of that night, while being violently shaken, my head bopping around like a baloon in the wind, in the endless night at some point, somehow, I found myself happily dreaming.</p>
<p>Soon after the Swede woke me up by shaking me, he wanted to know if I wanted some cookies. I most certainly did not. I was not very nice about it either. Insult was added to injury at 5:30 Am when the driver reached for the Rod Stewart box set, which blasted at us all morning. The only song they didn&#8217;t play was Maggie May, the only good Rod Stewart song I know of, aside from when he was with Faces.</p>
<p>Finally, early the next morning the bus stopped some place and they came and told us to get off and gave us our shit. This was clearly not anywhere near lake Toba, and nobody could speak any English and it really looked like we were now being kicked out in the middle of nowhere. Well, first thing the Swede went ape shit, hollering so the veins in his neck were bulging, his face getting all hot. I tried to stop him, and the more he hollered the more people they seemed to find who could not speak any English. Now they were trying to get us on a mini bus, and the Swede was arguing that we had already paid to go all the way to Toba and we would not pay again. I pulled one guy aside and talked to him, after a short while I realized that these poor people were trying to explain to him that this was just a transfer to a free mini bus that would take us the last two hours of the trip, it was included in the price and at no point had they tried to cheat us. If you are ever in a situation in another country were you are confused and lost and scared, don&#8217;t just start screaming, nine times out of ten if they are out to cheat you it is obvious and you see it coming and even still, the ones trying to cheat you are not necessarily bad people anyway, just poor people who don&#8217;t have many options. In any event you catch more flies with honey, it is often just a misunderstanding and if you get hot at these people they just shut down and become embarrassed and you wind up looking and feeling like an ass. So the Swede calmed down and we had our own little mini van the rest of the way, and by all rights I should have slept after my all night suicidal hell ride, but this leg of the journey took us up up up through mountainous jungle roads along cliffs and through canyons with amazing scenery and monkeys hanging out by the side of the road doing their monkey thing, and the sky was blue and soon we could see Toba. Ah Toba. The second I layed eyes on the place I was home.</p>
<p>But more on that in a second. first I have to tell you when we got to the city on the shore of lake Toba (we aimed to ferry to the island in the middle, you dig) we were tired and I was running around trying to find someone who would give me a not crazy rate on Chinese yuan. I came back to find the Swede sitting with a fat man who was so nice he wanted to give us a ride and tell us which hotel to go to. Here is the rub, this is a very common and obvious ploy. You get a ride to the ferry and then they follow you to a hotel and then when you get there the hotel owner has to charge you more money to cover this fellas finders fee. The reason I avoid this is the simple reason that one can never be sure how much it would cost without the fee and it eliminates the chance to shop around to find the best price or spot. Sometimes I am so tired or a place is so remote that I am grateful for the help, but Toba is very much on the map so I wanted to just do it by myself. The Swede was all about it though, the fat man told us that this hotel had a couple of Swedish girls staying there. This news came as a powerful revelation to the Swede. He proclaimed loudly, loud enough for everyone in the place to hear &#8220;Wow, that is so great. I really want to get a blow job!&#8221;</p>
<p>I managed to convince the Swede that we should just hoof it, it wasn&#8217;t that far and we were better off figuring it out for ourselves. As we walked the Swede began stopping at every single shop, regardless of what they were selling. He was suddenly on a mission to find some shit called 7 up revive. I have never heard of the stuff, but he had to have it. Every place he went he asked for 7 up revive, and each time they had no clue what he was talking about, and each time they desperately tried to make him happy with some other soda. Each time we walked away, each time they came after us trying to go down on the price, wondering what was wrong with the coke they had or with their store that we wouldn&#8217;t want to shop there. Every single place, very soon I found this embarrassing. When we got to the ferry port the fat man was waiting for us with a grin. We had missed the boat and had to buy a ticket with him, for a jacked up price no doubt. I could see a boat with people getting on, so I thanked the fat man for his time and kept walking. We got on the boat which hadn&#8217;t left after all, and then&#8230;&#8230;<br />
TOBA!</p>
<p>TOBA!</p>
<p>TOBA!</p>
<p>Ahhh, Toba. Lake Toba is so big that it shows up on the Sumatra map.<br />
It is a massive lake surrounding an island inside a super volcano. The encircling rim looms above and looks like a mountain chain, covered with a combination of ultra bright green lush short grass, jungle, as well as the occasional cascading waterfall. Toba was one of the largest volcanic eruptions in earth&#8217;s history, so I&#8217;m told. In the past few years they were finally able to piece together that a long misunderstood mystery ash that was popping up as far away as Iceland originated from the Toba eruption a few million or so years back. It is far enough above sea level for a cool breeze to stop the equatorial sun from murdering but still just right for swimming. This is the place, the greatest place I have ever been aside from my friend Caroline&#8217;s lake house in Georgia, which is mainly great because of memories of friends and barbecue. This is the place I needed, this is the spot, the place where the rest of the world is replaced with maybe going for a swim, maybe a nap in a hammock, or a beer. This is the place that makes you cry later in lament for being confounded with the curse of being stuck any other place on earth. This is a place where your soul smiles. You can not look in any direction in Toba and not see the most amazing scenery your heart or mind could ever take in, it makes the jaw hang. The blue of the sky is a brand new kind of blue, as is the brand new green of the surrounding hills. This is it, man. The air is full of happy and a guitar or a drum is never far out of reach, the tourists are the cool smiling friendly, undemanding kind, and the locals are even nicer. The days are endless and the nights are cool under a sky of deep stars and in the evening, in the distance, you can always hear the music of the Batak people. No shit. This is the place. This is the place. Oh god, this is the place.</p>
<p>The first three days I did nothing. I read a book by the lake, I drank beer, I swam, I talked to other travelers, I ate, I napped. This was my whole objective in the first place, just chill the hell out in paradise. I met a way cool musician from Germany named Peter Subway,<br />
(http://www.petersubway.de/deutsch.htm) he started in Berlin playing shows on the subways now he travels all over the world playing on trains. He is a regular at an island I made it to a little later in my trip called Pulau Wei, and was on his way to Jakarta. He told me that the trains in Jakarta are moving market places with local musicians, he was going to go and jam. And I met a 19 year old white kid from California who had been riding his bike (push bike yall) from Istanbul. His crazy ass had been through north Iraq, he said that at that time the north was fairly stable, but still. He had also been through Pakistan, he said that the nicest people in the world were in Pakistan. He also told me that he had tried to go through Iran but they wouldn&#8217;t let him in. Next he was going to Malaysia, then through Thailand to Laos then China to Hong Kong, then home. It occurs to me that I would at some point love to travel this way, me and my bike across a country. I need to get into better shape first though. Me and this kid went climbing up the mountain one day to the water fall and I found a real difference in climbing speed between me and a 19 year old who had come from Istanbul by bike.  Can you guess who was stopping and panting blog believers?</p>
<p>I wound up staying at a place called Liberta on Tuk tuk (the name of the island in Toba). Just in case you found the willsanderschinaadventure while doing a google search on Liberta guest house, let me tell you that it is among the nicest places I have ever stayed. I was paying $2 American a night for my own private bungalow with bathroom and cold shower. Cold shower is normal, as hot shower would be silly in the heat of Sumatra. It is run by a guy named Moon, a hell of a nice guy. He is mentioned by name in the Lonely Planet. He spent his days playing chess with anyone fool enough to challenge him and a lot of times many of us sat and watched the games in the shade taking refuge from the afternoon sun. One day I found myself eating pizza by the chess table, Moon and a Frenchman were in fierce battle.<br />
The Swede was quickly bored by the chess game and left, returning promptly with the bug zapper which nobody cared about. He provided endless commentary on the size of the mosquitoes he was nabbing, one was small, one was big, one had stripes, one was a fly. We did our best to ignore him, so he started waving it over the chess board. The Frenchman swatted one on his leg, the Swede protested that the man should have used his wonderful device. We ignored him. He pouted and left, rejected and sad. Nobody cared about his bug zapper, even though it was so clearly important. Poor guy.</p>
<p>I met a guy from Manchester named Mark, we became fast friends. He had heard about a local wedding on the other side of the island and we crashed. The locals didn&#8217;t seem to care, it was outside and we stood in the corner watching the scene. One man was leaping around with his eyes all rolling around in his head in a trance like one of the faithful at a pentecostal snake handling poison kool aid drinking tongue talking ho down babtist type church. Everyone in the place was drinking Tuack, which was my first exposure to the stuff. Tuack is a bright yellow and thick potent wine that ferments on its own in the tops of palm trees. They actually don&#8217;t have to do a single thing to it, just pull it out of the tree and put it in a plastic bag and serve. More on Tuack later.</p>
<p>That day I remember that Mark and I wandered around the island, and wherever we went young girls called to us from their shops like sirens pulling Greek sailors to the rocky shore, but damn if it didn&#8217;t work. We went in these places and hung around making the girls giggle. We hung around buying beer and food but in the end we realized that none of the girls wanted anything from us further than our business. That night we went clubbing at a place called Brandos, which only had two woman on the dance floor. We went to a place called Ellios where I had a girl rub herself all over me for me to buy her drinks. After I bought her a beer she proceeded to ram her big butt into my crotch. We danced for a while, I think that is just how she gets drinks, and I suppose that she does this every night with somebody, still I didn&#8217;t care. After I left that night I heard later she started trying the same thing with Mark.</p>
<p>The next day Mark and I hung out at the guest house and wrote a song on his guitar about his dead Grandmothers nipples, which was very amusing to the both of us. That night I hung out in my favorite spot on the dock next to the water with a book, just relaxing. That night Mark went out to the clubs again looking for girls. He couldn&#8217;t find me so instead he wound up taking the Swede, who apparently creeped out the girls and was a weirdo, the way Mark tells it. And Mark told me he had followed the Swede around all night in his quest for 7 up revive, this time, lo and behold he actually found a bottle. He was so happy he turned it upside down and downed it in one go. After doing so, he complained to Mark that 7 up revive made him feel sick.</p>
<p>Some days Mark and I wandered around the island, rice paddies and hills with small villiages. Always chickens clucking around, water buffalo, and always small children. All the English these kids seemed to know was &#8220;Hello&#8221;, &#8220;Bye bye&#8221;, and &#8220;Fuck you&#8221;. I don&#8217;t think they really understood what any of it means, they would smile and say &#8220;hey mister, Bye bye, hello, money, money, fuck you, hello, bye bye&#8221;. And I would smile back and wave and say hello and bye bye, what else am I going to do? I doubt they knew what they were saying, maybe they just hated us, either way they were way cute. Mark and I were walking at one point and a little girl who was playing in her front yard waved her little hand and smiled and said &#8220;hello&#8221;, then her much younger brother, maybe 2 or 3 came running out of his front door butt naked and poking his penis with one finger calling &#8220;hello&#8221;. So we laughed about that one for quite a while.</p>
<p>EVIL KNIEVIL I AM NOT</p>
<p>One day it occurred to me that it was high time I saw the rest of the island, which is around 50 KM around, so around eleven I rented a motorcycle off Mr. Moon. Moon&#8217;s bike was a bit more expensive than some of the locals who were hanging out, but I didn&#8217;t care because I knew Moon and I trusted Moon. I trusted his smile and I trusted his breakfast and I trusted his chess game and I trusted that the motorcycle wouldn&#8217;t crap out on me mid day, and I trusted that he wouldn&#8217;t trump up some unforeseen preexisting problem with the thing and then try to charge me for it, I have seen that happen. He gave me a xerox copy of a hand drawn map of the island (which I trusted as well) and he gave me a smile and told me he would put the rental on my tab, not to worry, so off I went.</p>
<p>I was zooming along the coast, I decided to head to the North, the folks hanging around in the hammocks told me that following the road to the South was no good, the roads that way were shit. I was cruising along, the mighty lake on my right side, the mountain on my left. Perfect. I saw empty guest houses which would have been full in the Toba hey day, which I understand was around 97. Since then people have forgotten Toba, terrorists in the North and the bombings in Bali, the Tsunami, shorter visas all helped deal the death blow to Toba&#8217;s draw, now it is blissful and empty of tourists and the guest houses and hotels that still dot the shore are abandoned, landmarks from another time. I saw while I drove through an endless street market with endless stalls and endless bodies running to the street calling to me, &#8216;come in, come in&#8217;. I kept driving. It was easy to picture that one day not so long ago this street was filled with families from Europe, Dad with a belly pack and obnoxious straw hat, Mom with her lonely planet guide book, the kids running around as kids do, now a ghost town, just me and Moon&#8217;s motorcycle speeding through and not slowing. I went to the hot springs, but didn&#8217;t get in. Hot springs are rarely nice, sometimes, but not often. These had been pumped into a dingy looking swimming pool and the smell of sulpher was killing me. I did see a huge iguana cross the path while walking up.</p>
<p>So I kept going, for a time I went along a road that didn&#8217;t go anywhere, then doubled back.  Next I shoot up up up up the mountain to get to the top of the plateau in the middle of the island.  Along the way I had to stop often to survey the world of green on which I now was standing on top off.  At the bottom of the mountain were the shacks and buildings the locals had put together, beyond that was the shimmering lake, and beyond that was endless green that rolled its way all the way out to the horizon.</p>
<p>The top of the mountain was mostly farm land, it was such a large area one quickly forgot that this was a mountain top.  The lake was a bit on the small side, especially in comparison with the rather gigantic lake surrounding the entire area, a lot of farms and the occasional ox.  It was just about that time that I noticed my gas gauge was just above the red.  I stopped and asked some locals who looked at the gauge and when I told them I was heading for Tuk Tuk they smiled and said I had enough.  So onward I went.   The map I had showed the road to Tuk Tuk becoming a wavey line, this seemed to coincide with when the road became dirt surrounded by jungle.  I figured this must be the last leg of the road and it didn&#8217;t look very far on my map, if I was in fact where I thought I was so I kept going.  Soon it became clear that this was never intended to be a road for vehicles of any sort, I had make it through huge sections of deep mud, which was a warm spray all over my legs and face from the tires spitting, the whole bike was bouncing along, sliding and bounding and skipping in the mud, trying not to go so fast that I lose control or so slow the tires start to spin out, the best thing seemed to be just to fucking gun it, a few times I found myself almost thrown into the bushes.  The first of these were short but they became longer and more ridiculous the further in I ventured.  Now it was seeming like I was running along a dry creek bed, the gravel underneath was slippery under the tires, but it seemed crazy to turn around now, I was finally getting past the mud areas and I didn&#8217;t want to have to go through that again.  But some stone cold realities were not going away, my knuckles could feel each of these facts as they gripped the throttle tight, just as sure as they could feel every bump and stone.</p>
<p>One:  It was late in the day, maybe 4:30 or 5, I was running out of daylight, and I was going further and further into the jungle.</p>
<p>Two: I was running on fumes at best, only a matter of time before I am pushing this sucker.</p>
<p>Three: The guys who told me to come this way and that I needn&#8217;t worry about gas were clearly assholes.</p>
<p>Four:  I was about to sleep in the jungle.  Alone, without water or food.<br />
I was getting noplace fast.  I stopped and got off the bike, just to curse a little.  When I was done I decided to scout off the path down the hill to see what&#8217;s what.  I climbed into the bush, promising myself that I would not lose sight of the bike, trying to make a lot of noise to scare away snakes and god knows who else.  Soon I started seeing what looked like a break in the tree line where it seemed like the whole world dropped off.  That must be the edge of the mountain, which I reasoned meant that I was not going to find a path down the side as I had been hoping.  I remembered a very slight trail I had passed up the road a piece that could very well be leading off in the direction I wanted, so back up through the bush I climbed and made it back to the bike, a little dirtier with a million bug bites, but now with a slight tinge of hope.  I turned that sucker around a doubled back up the road for a good ten minutes, gambling everything that I could make the trail and that it would be my salvation.</p>
<p>Good news, that trail lead me out of the jungle, the tree line ended and the road was semi paved, lots of potholes and loose gravel, but all in all an improvement.   I was on top of a mountain, man it was spectacular in every direction.  Now I could even see Tuk Tuk, a tiny speck in the distance.  Soon I even saw a local kid on a motorbike, I flagged him down.  Now, he didn&#8217;t speak much English but I showed him my gas gauge and he understood and motioned for me to follow.  He took me around the corner to a barn where a guy came out with a couple of soda pop bottles full of gas, I think a 2 litter was less than a dollar and I was good to go.  Two problems solved, now which way do I go to get home?  Once again the kid wanted me to follow.</p>
<p>He lead the way down a steep steep hill road, it was almost going straight down the mountain.  I would not be stretching if I told you it was like a 70 to 75 degree angle, and the road was half paved, half potholes and all the way covered with very loose rocks which ranged from gravel to baseballs.  My throat was in my balls and I rode the breaks which was causing my back tire to start spinning and bouncing all over as the rocks shot out from under, I felt like I was sliding head first.  Soon I felt the back tire loose the road altogether and it shot forward to the left side, for a split moment which is frozen in my memory for all time the whole bike was leaning all the way over to the right and for just a second I realized that there was no way to play this that wouldn&#8217;t end with me whipping out down the side of this mountain,  and I realized that something very shitty was about to happen and that at the very least it would hurt.</p>
<p>I landed on my right side, skidding with the bike on top of me.  I didn&#8217;t skid far, a few feet maybe, I wasn&#8217;t going very fast.  But try as I may I couldn&#8217;t get the thing off me.  I must have hollered when it was happening because the kid saw me and came running to help.  He lifted the motorcycle off me, my right arm was bloody, by right leg was skinned from the top of my foot, (inside my shoe, still can&#8217;t really figure that one,) all the way up my thigh.  I walked with a limp and cursed a little more.   Yeah yeah yeah, I was lucky I didn&#8217;t kill myself and I know it.</p>
<p>It occurred to me that it had been several hours since this had been fun just before it occurred to me that the plastic case for the headlight on the motorcycle was cracked and had a hole.  This made me feel like a total fink.  Mr. Moon had trusted me, I had clearly let him down.  This hurt far worse than my physical injuries, and on top of my guilt I wondered how much of my trip budget would have to go to fixing his motorcycle.</p>
<p>Now on top of everything else I had to get back on the fucking thing and continue, now with fresh wounds giving credence to my fears.  It gets better too, around the corner from there, and about 300 feet down the road stopped, and when I say stopped, I mean man, it stopped.</p>
<p>Shit.  It looked like a mudslide had taken the road into a deep gorge, straight up and down cliff and then far across the gorge another cliff with the rest off the road.  I sat on the cliff looking down into the abyss and you know what I did?  I laughed and laughed and laughed.  I was trapped on top of this mountain in this island worse than Giligan, what the hell was I going to do now?  What is worse that a motorcycle going down a 70 degree rock slide slope?  How about going back up.  No way this was the way down, no way at all.</p>
<p>Soon the kids brothers appeared out of nowhere and wanted to carry my bike down the cliff.  I said no at first but gave in quick, I was so beat and hurt and just wanted to find a way out.  They took the bike down a trough of mud that cut along the cliff, I followed and found my feet submerged in what would have made perfect grey sculpting clay up above my socks.  Each step slid me further down the cliff and deeper into the clay, soon I was knee deep, and I watched these two kids carry this motorcycle through all this with almost no effort.  Once on the bottom the kids revved the throttle and rode across the canyon to the other ravine.  Next one climbed along side the bike, straight up the cliff, with one hand on the edge of the cliff and the other on the throttle of the bike.  The other kid ran up the cliff behind, or I should say directly under the bike trying to hang onto the seat to make it go the right way.  This was the damnedest thing I have ever seen and if I had a camera it would be on youtube.  After they made it to the top with a revving and kicking motorcycle I had no excuse not to follow up the cliff, now covered in bug bites, sweet, blood, mud,<br />
and fury.  The two kids asked for a high price hoping I wouldn&#8217;t bargin too far down, I didn&#8217;t bargain at all, I didn&#8217;t have it in me. I paid them more money than I had paid for anything so far in Indonesia, but all in all after what they had gone through risking their lives and pushing this bike all the way through the mud and up the side of a sheer cliff, I decided they had earned ten dollars.</p>
<p>The whole way back I was worried sick about the bike, and I felt like I had let Moon down and I was worried that he would charge me a lot of money to fix it.  When I got in, I dragged myself into his lobby and asked the kid at the desk for him.  They got him off his hammock and with deep regret I showed him the bike, and he couldn&#8217;t have cared less.  He seemed to think his brother had done that to the bike ages ago and was more concerned with my cuts.  He gave me a jug of homemade stuff to put all over myself, it was thick and had a label with some Butak looking guy who seemed angry about something.  I used the stuff and granted, my cuts healed fast, but in the middle of the night I found my leg and arms covered completely with ants so I had to take a shower.</p>
<p>PSYCHODELIC VOLCANO, and the papers want to know whose shoes you wear</p>
<p>The night before the motorcycle day I had once again found myself drinking at Bagus Bay, where the 21 year old Batack bartender, Fernando had taken to calling me bruduh.  That night I was drinking with a rather tall and lankey muppet of a person named Haiky.  His eyes had a weird way of always being too wide, as if always expressing supreme enthusiasm.  Haiky is a cab driver from Finland.  When I asked him how a cab driver from Finland could afford to go all the way to Indonesia he almost screamed &#8220;I sell weed!&#8221;  At this point I floated the question of Mushrooms, as I had been toying with the idea but hadn&#8217;t found anyone to trip with.  Weed and shrooms are grown on the island and the signs on the walls of most restaurants reassured me that things were cool.  The sign on the wall of Bagus Bay read<br />
&#8216;Mushrooms:  go to the moon.  Tea or omelet.&#8217;  So Haiky and I agreed on the next day.</p>
<p>The next evening I limped into Bagus Bay with fresh cuts and local ointment all over and found a group of people waiting on us.  A nice couple from London had agreed to come along for the trip and so had Fernando, the 21 year old bartender who called me &#8216;bruduh&#8217;.</p>
<p>I might as well mention here that I had not done drugs of any sort for a few years.  My standing drug addiction involves mushrooms taken once every two years with friends and in a cool place.  This seemed the perfect place and it had been just about two years since I tripped at Carolines lake house with Blake and Amy, I asked for mine in tea form.  We all carefully watched each other as we drank the shit down, it was putrid brew indeed.  At the bottom of the cup was a pile of greenish muck, which I opted to eat as well, nobody else did.  That may account for why I was tripping so fucking hard later and they weren&#8217;t.  I call it getting your money&#8217;s worth, blog believers.</p>
<p>And that night Peter Subway went and got his guitar and he spent what must have been all night hour after hour (I am kind of hazy on a cohesive timeline for what should be obvious reasons) playing a concert for us until his fingers bled.  The highlight of the show for me was when I was really peaking, peter went into space oddity by David Bowie, and man, I was Major Tom.  Here is the part I was feeling the most from the whole song</p>
<p>This is Major Tom to ground control, I&#8217;m stepping through the door,<br />
and I floating in the most peculiar way, the stars look very different today</p>
<p>That was cool.  I will never be able to hear that song again without thinking of Toba and that night. And for a long time I found myself outside alone laying in the grass on my back starring at the moon, which seemed to have the face of an ex girlfriend, and all around the moon the clouds formed landscapes of mountains and cities and circular geometric patterns, and the moon was so so so bright it was blinding.  At one point I worried, really worried that I might get a moon burn.  And as I layed out there I started to want to hang out with Mark, Mark this guy I had only known one week had become my best friend and as fucked as I was I wanted to hang out with Mark who was this cool guy from Manchester, but I couldn&#8217;t seem to tear myself away from the moon.  Soon I heard Mark calling me, he had wondered where I was and I told him I had been off hallucinating so I went in and listened to Peter Subway with everyone else for a long time, Peter Subway fucking rocks, by the way.  The man is a jukebox, there was no way he could be stumped all night he played and sang, then at one point Mark started singing about his dead grandmothers nipples just to fuck with me.  The local girls asked me how I was doing and I said &#8220;I&#8217;m fine, thank you, and you?&#8221;  Which is what my Chinese students always say whenever you ask them that question, and everyone laughed at me, but it was cool.  And Peter Subway knew how to play a song by T-rex.  Then I was playing on a series of different sized drums along a line in descending pitches like a xylophone of bongos, after a while I realized it was night time and I asked if I was keeping people up and they said maybe I was so I felt bad about it.</p>
<p>I found myself on the dock with Haiky, the Finish taxi driver and we dipped our feet in the water off the dock which felt so fucking good and we starred up at the stars and the moon and Haiky agreed that the moon was so amazing and we played with piles of seaweed which was laying around, and it was so interesting and I told him about China and about living there and about how my life was really great and about all that really mattered to me anymore was happiness and he agreed with me and we laughed like idiots and he looked just like a fucking muppet.</p>
<p>As the night wore on we all wound up in the wee hours sitting around a table slowly coming down with Peter Subway (god bless him) still playing and singing for us.  And as we all came down we felt immense euphoria and glee and our smiles were stupid and our eyes were heavy. We sang along with every song he played, oh and the British lady had discovered Tommy the dog early in the evening and the entire night she sat there smoking with one hand and petting Tommy with the other, by the time I wasn&#8217;t tripping anymore I noticed that Tommy looked like just about the happiest dog I had ever seen.  I noticed that Fernando started cleaning the place and working, which didn&#8217;t seem right to me so I cleaned the place for him and told him to sit, that he was not working tonight, and he sank back into his chair and called me bruddah.  So cleared the empties off the bar and washed it and went around dumping the ashtrays and everything else.   And I sang blister in the sun with Peter and it was the sort of odd situation where one didn&#8217;t feel at all strange singing in front of a whole room full of people, I usually don&#8217;t sing, but I like doing it so I don&#8217;t know what is the issue and why I shouldn&#8217;t.  And we started drinking wine and started getting drunk, and Mark disappeared with a local girl, and just before the sun came up we all gave each other teary eyed hugs, strangers a few days before, now brothers and sisters, soon we would make the pretense of emailing each other and maybe if were are lucky we may see each other years from now, someplace.  I would like that anyways.</p>
<p>MEDAN</p>
<p>Next I went to a city called Medan, hoping that I could just show up and find teaching work as I was running out of money, but no such luck.  I stayed at the be all and end all of shit holes.  In another blog I had to change the name of a place I stayed in Macao and of the owner in case someone found it by chance on the internet I didn&#8217;t want to hurt their business.  I will tell you the real name of this place, it actually deserves infamy, in fact, if nobody has ever died in this shit hole I am surprised.   The place was called Rona&#8217;s guesthouse formally sputnik and it cost a dollar a night and when Rona showed me the room it was a stall with exactly two things, a thin mattress on the floor, and a fan.  When she showed me the room she said &#8220;It&#8217;s got a mattress ,and a fan, and everything.&#8221;</p>
<p>The front porch was the headquarters for an ever vigilant garrison of international drunks, too ugly to get laid or tolerated elsewhere so they all wound up here.  Their leader was an old man from Australia who never wore a shirt and looked just like Abe Vigoda.   He repeatedly hollered things like &#8220;Fuck the world, mate, that&#8217;s what I say.&#8221;  Always followed by bellowing laughter, and the locals all laughed hard when he called them Orangutans,  but I noticed that they weren&#8217;t laughing quite as hard the next night when he was still saying it.  He was still laughing though, and how.  Oh, and there was also a young guy who seemed to worship the Australian who kept lighting his own farts for the Australians approval, which never seemed to wean. I tried to talk to someone else and the Australian wouldn&#8217;t have it. Some guy tried to tell me about his trek through the jungle and the Australian hollered, &#8220;Jungle, why would you want to go there?  I lived for six years in the Jungle, I almost got eaten by a tiger.  Fuck the jungle, that&#8217;s what I say mate.&#8221;  He was the kind of man who would have made excellent food for an animal, but displayed little more worth.</p>
<p>So Mark and I bounced and found an alley way where the locals drank Tuak, the bright yellow palm tree wine, and we did that for a few nights and got ourselves fucked up, lord.  The local folks seemed pleased that we had found their little alley, not many foreigners do I take it, and we were treated like guests.  They told me that just one farm harvests all the tuack daily for all of Medan and they get a hundred US a day, which actually doesn&#8217;t come to all that much when you consider the labor they have to hire for the job as well as the trucks and everything else.  But one dollar will get you a kool aid pitcher full and that is plenty for you and a friend.  Tuack gives no hangover and no headache, and when you are really gone it is impossible to notice, it is not until the next day when you calculate that your behavior was making no sense.</p>
<p>One night the locals started fighting, one guy left.  They made a call and a dude showed up on a super nice motorcycle, big dude.  When he showed up the trouble seemed to go away, we figured he was local mafia enforcement.  Mark actually asked him, are you Mafia?   Which would get your ass shot with the real thing in America, so the movies tell me, but the guy smiled and thought we were funny.   I heard a story from a local over Tuak about the mafia boss in Sumatra, a man named Onu.  I actually heard that name around a few times, Onu is known from the North all the way to the South.  A man told me with certainty in his eyes that Onu can not be killed by bullets, and if you shoot him he will laugh and then shoot you.  And if you are trying to kill Onu,<br />
he will turn into a chicken.  I am not making this up, Onu the mafia king of Sumatra is said to be able to turn into a Chicken at will. Tony Soprano couldn&#8217;t do that.   In the alley in Medan Mark and I had really deep drunk discussions on the subject of our life, really deep shit, and I walked away thinking differently about some things in my life.  It reminded me of drinking at the railroad tracks with my friends in the ATL.  We wondered the streets looking for girls or alcohol, or tuack.  Finally we parted ways, I stayed around a few more days and ran into Haiky which was cool.  Then as we were leaving he tried to rip me off, this is after I spent an hour trying to wake his sorry ass up off the floor of the bathroom in the morning at Rona&#8217;s so he wouldn&#8217;t miss his plane, but I don&#8217;t want to tell that story, he didn&#8217;t rip me off by the way, but he tried and it pissed me off and he was trying to be sneaky about it.</p>
<p>Next I went to an island called Pulua wei which was amazing and well worth another entire big blog but I don&#8217;t feel like it.  And then the snows his south China so I couldn&#8217;t go back and I went back to Toba a second time and was greeted like a returning hero.  Fernando was so happy to see me, and some dog had puppies and Fernando named one of them Will after me, which makes me more happy than I can say.  This weekend I got to go to Hong Kong to sort out my visa mess, and I guess I will wind up telling you about that.  But now it is late and I want to get this finished so I will now put it up without a single proof read.  If you bothered to read all this mess, I thank you.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?feed=rss2&amp;p=59</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notes from the road</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=57</link>
		<comments>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=57#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2008 06:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will</dc:creator>
		
		<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=57</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Landed in Singapore, I guess it was a week ago now, seems like longer.  Singapore was a very strange place.  Just a bit too clean and way too modern to have any business in South east Asia.  It was here that the fucker American piss ant kid got cained for spray painting [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Landed in Singapore, I guess it was a week ago now, seems like longer.  Singapore was a very strange place.  Just a bit too clean and way too modern to have any business in South east Asia.  It was here that the fucker American piss ant kid got cained for spray painting a car a few years ago, lousy little so and so.  It is here that it is illegal to chew or sell gum, ride your bike in the park, litter, jay walk, murder people in or out of a rage, detonate fire works, and while I think some one was pulling my leg I heard tell of a fine for neglecting to flush after a number two.  The rest of them are real and levy heavy heavy fines or worse, so they say it is the safest country in the world.  Calling Singapore a country is like calling Rhode Island a state, really just a technicality but size wise it is smaller than greater metro Atlanta, I would guess anyhow.  cleaner too, and safer.</p>
<p>I stayed at a backpacker hostel called Betel box which was a cool spot run by hip funky kids in their 20&#8217;s who would often sink beers with us in the common room.  The dorm I was staying in was a large room with 10 bunks holding 20 people, all of whom now know that I snore, or so I understand.</p>
<p>Among the people in my dorm were a couple from India along with their five year old servery developmentally disabled son.  His limbs were too small for his frail body and useless leaving him confined to a baby stroller where his mother was spoon feeding him when we first met.  He was also ;mentally disabled but it was hard to tell the extent without being able to speak his language.  I talked to them for a long time, the boys father told me that he had been offered a good job in Boston where he could get good medical care for his son but his application for US visa was denied.  So here they were, having traveled to Singapore to find a doctor and a job and a place to stay and a new life in a strange place and for hope that their son may get just a smidgen better if he were to get the right treatment they couldn&#8217;t find in India.  They had given themselves one week, after which if still empty handed they would go back to India.  The boys father seemed to glow with such optimism  he talked of his problems with a broad smile which refused to be defeated.  He seemed to be a rock for his wife, she looked like she need it.  I heard myself telling them that my mother used to work with kids like their son, as it came up in conversation.  Their faces lit up and he almost jumped up and down as he told his wife who sprung out of her chair.  I tried to calm them and explain that my mother couldn&#8217;t really do anything to help them but he said it would be so good to talk to her about their son and I gave them her email.</p>
<p>That night I hung out in the common room striking up conversations with the other back packers and struck up conversation.  There was one guy from Austraillia in town for two weeks to study mui thai boxing, a couple of kids from Wales, some Aussie girls.  A bunch of us went the next day to the little India section and then wandered around  looking at Hinu temples.  We got lost for a while in the down town area trying to find a street that wasn&#8217;t fucking there.  As we were looking at the map, there was a very real flash of a moment, just one tick, one little pop in time before which the air was filled with air as opposed to massive heavy sheets of crashing water, where as after the afore mentioned pop we were instantly cursing the heavens, soaked to our skin, and running like hell for shelter which wound up being a veranda roof of a nearby building.  We were stuck there for quite a bit, lost and wet, having to speak up to one another over the screaming rain which was punctuated with scatter shot thunder all around.  Monsoon season you know.  I went running off to scout where to go, came back drenched only to realize that everyone else had decided on a nice, safe, dry cab to the very posh, very pretentiously historic raffles hotel, fine I said.</p>
<p>Very instrumental white people used to hang around out in the Raffles hotel all the way back to the Dutch colonial days, I think.  Dutch east India movers and shakers would sit around and smoke cigars, talk about trading spice for beads and about how fine it was to be so white in Singapore in those days and they barked orders at the help and laughed at how funny it was to see them wearing the proper clothes of non-savages.  They also sipped a drink called the Singapore sling, which was invented here at the Raffles hotel and has the appearance of a five star gourmet frilly umbrella drink that wouldn&#8217;t really get you drunk and cost too much money.  I was right about the money part and we all passed, so I can&#8217;t comment on it&#8217;s buzz quality.  One glass of that shit cost more that two nights at the backpacker hostel, so we all had the cheapest thing they had, English tea which came with little silver tea pots and finery.  Somebody went to the john and came back raving about how nice it was, so soon there we were soaking wet in tee shirts under a glowing chandelier talking about going to the toilet and about shit and we all giggled ourselves silly much to the chagrin of the staff of the Raffles hotel.  Next time you want to seem smart to your friends and annoying to your bartender just order a Singapore sling and say &#8220;from the Raffles in Singapore, don&#8217;t you know.&#8221;  Fake British accent is optional, but well worth the effort I would say.</p>
<p>So we drank that night and a few backpackers left and a few more left and we all had the same conversations with each other about where we had been and where we were going and what country we were from.  There was a German girl who just seemed completely rude to everyone, and another German girl who was way cool.  This one decided that the next leg of my trip would involve her and a dude she had met at a conference that week.</p>
<p>They were stuck in Singapore for the weekend, having been there for over a week on a conference.  I turned out to be a fortuitous option, you see I was on my way to an island off the coast of Singapore where I was catching a ferry to Sumatra Indonesia, this was as far as my plan went.  So they figured we could all hang out on said island for the weekend and they could escape Singapore with it&#8217;s hustle and bustle and chill the fuck out on a beach, and I figured that I could hang out too.  The connection island, Paluo Bantam, is a shithole from what we had heard and read, so we opted for the close by Paluo Bintam.  The half hour ferry took almost two hours, and we landed in a very remote looking city.  They were surprised to see us and everyone started in with their desperate offers of taxis, and hotels for us.  The customs was a desk where they asked Ines how long she was staying, she said two days and they took our passports, and asked for ten dollars american each.  I ponied up and waited, when my passport came back it said 7 days, which was not good.  I asked for a 30 day visa and they explained that I should have said so, they only thing to do now was to turn around and go back to singapore and come right back.  I didnt want to do that and just decided to have a good time and figure it out later, I still had 7 days.</p>
<p>We hired a car to take us to the east end of the island where all the cool shit is supposed to be.  We finally made it to a guest house that was a network of long pier walkways that stretched far out over the water.  At the end of the walkways were the bungalows, hanging over the ocean.   We stayed up all night, drank every drop of tiger beer they had under a limitless star filled sky, the water so perfect.  We laid on the dock and talked endlessly about how happy we were to be there, how perfect our lives were at that moment, and we talked about other things too.  Danial is a few months from a PHD, his thesis concerns the cleaning radioactive water, so I picked his brain for a while about alternative energy and about climate change and the future.  I asked him if he thought we were all fucked.  Good news, he says we are not fucked, and he is a smart guy.  so that is good news, no?  And he talked about his girlfriend and we talked about traveling and there was a family from Malaysia who were staying there and fishing all night, they smoked some fish on sticks and brought them for us.  It was a great night.</p>
<p>Next day we mostly slept, I laid in a hut over the sea and read a book, sipping beer and eating peanuts.  Day after that, we all got up early and rented two canoes and paddles out to a nearby island to go snorkeling.  We walked around the island, untouched and heaven by the way.  The water was so clear and a slight breeze made the blazing sun forgivable, momentarily.  We went to the middle of the ocean where there was a sand bar in the middle which we could stand on.  The edge of the sand bar were coral reefs for snorkeling.  Lots of clown fish (little nemo) and cool black spikey things and schools of fish, the occasional eel.  We were about twelve feet up, so you could hold your breath and dive straight down and look around.  that afternoon we went to go to the port city where I found out the boat to sumatra was leaving the next morning so I stayed at a guesthouse there called Bongs.  Bongs is in the lonely planet and located (no sign mind you) in an sub alley off another alley, which seemed to be filled with a combination of police drinking around a card table and prostitutes.  At bongs I met a chap from Amsterdam and we went for lunch.  As we were leaving the guy who ran the place asked if we liked music and wanted us to quiz him, name any song.  On the wall he had a picture of Madanna and I said like a virgin which he knew and we told him how smart he was, he looked disappointed.  a dude took us to a place where they started pilling trays of food all over the table.  We tried this and that, the guy was eating too.  The bill came and was close to $14 American, they were charging as much for each small bowl of food as a whole meal anywhere else, so we had been had.  I sat there refusing to pay.  Finally we put down $8 which was still way too much but enough so we could leave without trouble from the locals, who all knew where we were staying.  My new friend and I then took a boat to a nearby island to see some ruins of Muslim forts and mosques, which was ok.</p>
<p>That night we drank beer.  the old man who ran the place once again asked us to quiz him and so we did, started easy and he knew everything.  Then I said, ok, what about Telegram sam.  Figured I would test him, without thinking, through heavy accent he said T rex.  I sat up, amazed.  The guy from Amsterdam said I wanna be your dog and he said Iggy and the stooges.  This guy really did know his shit.  so for hours we all tried to stump each other.  He asked me who wrote the song come on feel the noise and (like an idiot) said quiet riot, he corrected me.  FYI it was slade.  Then we tried movies and I ruled but he did manage to get me once, I had forgotten that Nichole Kidman was in Days of Thunder.  Not the kind of info I store.  But still, this guy was so cool, his favorite all time was Zepplin and I told him that John Bonham was my hero.  So if you are into music and on the island Paluo Bintam, check out Bongs, kind of a shit hole but good fun.</p>
<p>So next I looked at my choices.  The US embassy In Sumatra is in Medan, which puts me in good position to go to a lake in a volcano crater, which is on my list. I am here now, actually.  The problem there is what if they just say they can&#8217;t extend my visa and I have to leave and come back?  Than I would have gone to the south end, spent all day and night in a bus, just to have to leave.  So on the night before I decided I would just say fuck it and head to Malaysia.  Which I did.</p>
<p>more later<br />
w
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?feed=rss2&amp;p=57</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Birthday</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=56</link>
		<comments>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=56#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 02:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will</dc:creator>
		
		<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=56</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It was January 7, 2007,  The fateful day when my plane touched down at Beijing International.  I landed confused and befuddled.  Disoriented and ill suited to meet the calamity of my new everyday facing me, pessimistic about my odds.  One short year later I am stronger, wiser, and just a little [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was January 7, 2007,  The fateful day when my plane touched down at Beijing International.  I landed confused and befuddled.  Disoriented and ill suited to meet the calamity of my new everyday facing me, pessimistic about my odds.  One short year later I am stronger, wiser, and just a little less fat.  I&#8217;ve lived had good days, sad days, great days, plus some regular ones too.  I&#8217;ve been sick, concussed, lost, misunderstood, beat up, smitten, and hung over.  I&#8217;ve taught, traveled all over the darn place, I climbed mountains, rocked out, and my only regret is that my Chinese still sucks, but getting better slowly.  I met good people, had good food, I had weird shit too, and it ain&#8217;t over yet by a long shot.</p>
<p>It was over one year ago that Marcus started this website for me.  Back then, I remember he asked if I wanted to sign up for the one year or the two year deal.  I laughed, no way I will even be there one whole year, just do one, no problem.  Well, earlier this week the domain expired, and Marcus fixed that shit with a quickness.  I was momentarily scared that the site was gone, but Marcus fixed everything.  He is the man you guys.  So in the meantime happy birthday to all of you that have been reading my diary this year.  Keep the emails coming.</p>
<p>I am writing by pen in a notebook (originally) on a four hour bus from Guangzhou to Zhuhai.  I took a 20 hour train from Shangqiu, the same trip as the one I wrote about in the post car 13, this time with a bed which made all the diff.  China by train is really quite pleasant when you have a bed.  I traded the bottom bed with a girl for the middle of the three bunks.  The bottom bed is considered more desirable by the Chinese, but by day becomes the bunk on which everyone sits and chats on.  It is for this reason that I much prefer the upper beds where I can relax with a book, laying around all day, watching China slug by from the window.  So it was nice, aside from the girl on the bottom bunk making a cell call in the middle of the night waking everyone up, including the baby who once awake, made her adorably screaming presence known for the duration.</p>
<p>So after that bus ride to Zhuhai I made it to Macao.  I can&#8217;t remember what I told you about Macao the last time but this is my third trip and also my third time at Septembers bunk hostel.  Septembers is a two bedroom apartment at best with 2 double bunk beds in one room, one double bunk in the other room, and a third double bunk in a utility closet.  The big dorm from where I am now writing, has not been redecorated since the days it was a little kids room, still sporting cartoon puppies frolicking on the wall and glow in the dark stars on the ceiling.  The place is owned by a dude from Bangladesh named Joe.  My first stay here a girl in the dorm had left her passport on the China side and Joe, being the knight in shinning armor type, arranged for his brother to pick it up and bring it to her.  He also spent ten minutes trying to convince her she really ought to have sex with his brother for his trouble.  Only fair, reasoned Joe.  That was where I met Ben, an ex big deal entertainment lawyer from New York (he reped 50 cent among others) who one day said the hell with it and threw a party where he gave away all his stuff and has been traveling for the past several few years.  He was a gambler and we hit the casinos.  He told me he used to own a Cadillac he kept in Los Vegas and a Cadillac just for Atlantic city.  We all were talking about the fact that Macao beats Vegas in gambling revenue,  we couldn&#8217;t figure it out.  Ben came back the next day after winning enough to pay for his whole week in Macao, and he reported that  from what he could tell, Chinese people could not gamble, hence big winnings for the casinos in Macao.  He was playing black jack and said he saw people with a four showing and they wanted to stay and keep betting.  There is no other card that you could have that would make that a good hand.  So according to 50 cents old lawyer, Chinese people can&#8217;t gamble.</p>
<p>That was the same week I came in with a cheap bottle of bum wine and split it with Joe.  When I told him I was American he took the opportunity to praise George W Bush Endlessly, which I didn&#8217;t know how to respond to.  That is the only time that has happened.  Weird.  That was on the way to Thailand, I went back through Macao on my way home from Thailand a month later.  That time in Macao I met up with an Australian dude who has been traveling Asia for the past ten years chasing woman.  We went out hitting bars but ultimately we had no luck, nowhere to take them, was his point.  Can&#8217;t take them to the bunk hostel.  That time I stayed at Septembers Joe had drastically overbooked.  I get the feeling that Joe doesn&#8217;t turn away business.  I wound up sleeping on a cot next to the front desk, crammed next to another cot.  Right now (when this was first written by notebook) a cot sits next to the bunk comfortably cramming 5 in this tiny puppy room.</p>
<p>Earlier tonight I was talking to Joe, I asked him about the old man who was there the last couple of times I was there.  This was an old Korean guy who always sat smoking in the corner with his shirt off, always watching American professional wrestling.  I thought he worked there.  Joe told me that the old man didn&#8217;t work there, he was a gambler who&#8217;s family had told him he wasn&#8217;t allowed to go to Monaco  for gambling anymore.  He had a real problem and was losing all their money.  He had actually been missing for several months and finally his family found him, sitting in the corner of Septembers Hostel smoking and watching wrestling all day, gambling all night.  I mentioned what I had heard about Macao making more money off gambling than Vegas.  Joe gave a sage nod and said he had heard that too.  Then he said &#8220;The Chinese are naturally good gamblers.  It is in Chinese peoples blood.  Like eating human flesh.&#8221;  I asked him to repeat, and he talked of times in WWII during the Japanese occupation, times of awful famine.  He said in those days people ate their babies, &#8220;turned their babies into soup&#8221; I believe were his exact words.  And so, according to Joe Chinese people are good at gambling because eating babies is in their blood.  I told Joe that I had had dog in China, but never baby soup.</p>
<p>Joe is a good guy, he likes to talk, and he wants to help.  And I will gladly stay there on my way home at the end of the vacation I am now on.</p>
<p>I am in Singapore at the moment,  last night I met up with a  posse and tonight we are going to a night safari in the Singapore Zoo.  Georganna and Andy tell me that the Singapore zoo is amazing.  I can&#8217;t wait.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?feed=rss2&amp;p=56</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#8217;m living on a Chinese rock</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=55</link>
		<comments>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=55#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2007 16:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will</dc:creator>
		
		<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=55</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ First Part
Yesterday morning was cool.  I got up and got on skype and through the miracles of my webcamera I was able to attend a party in Atlanta live via satillite.  This meant I could see so many people I love that I haven&#8217;t seen or talked to in a long, long time.  It was [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="center"><strong> First Part</strong></p>
<p>Yesterday morning was cool.  I got up and got on skype and through the miracles of my webcamera I was able to attend a party in Atlanta live via satillite.  This meant I could see so many people I love that I haven&#8217;t seen or talked to in a long, long time.  It was a super hero dress up affair (we are nerds, nerds, nerds) in honer of Chuck&#8217;s (who was dressed as the Red Skull) and Adam&#8217;s (some obscure DC Hero, Hour man) birthday&#8217;s.  I told Big D that he made a better Hulk than Lou Farigno, no small statement, and I told Ryan Burke that he was a better Professor X than Patrick Stewart, along with Amy Bugg as Moria Mctaggish they easily won the couple costume prize, and Todd&#8217;s Captain America was dead on amazing I thought.   Amy Lovell (Tank Girl) told me about how her daughter is in her school&#8217;s production of my favorite Shakespere play Julius Ceaser, Eric Dimmers (as Eric Dimmers, a bonefied super hero in his own right) is canoeing from the Ocefanoke to the gulf via the swany river, and Sydney (Batgirl) said she was a blog believer from way back, which was super cool to hear and made me feel really good.  I just called Chuck to tell him how cool it was to talk to everyone and to see you guys too.  Unfortunatly my computer went blewie (as this bad bad bad shitty computer is prone to do) so if I missed talking to anyone I am sorry.  It was ok though, going to a party in America on a Friday night for me means getting up on a Saturday morning and drinking until early afternoon.  Which I did, then proceeded to sleep until about 6 last night, when I got up and ate and went out drinking with some guys from the metal band I have joined.  More about them later I think.  First I have to tell you about how close I came to being at this super hero party in person.</p>
<p>About a week ago, maybe a little over a week now, May told me that the school had decided not to extend my contract.  This news came with assurances that this measure was decided on a purly budgetary basis, which I have no doubt to be true for three reasons which may be ennumerated as follows:</p>
<p>1. I am a very expensive pet.  My pay tops most of the leaders of this school, and as cold as it&#8217;s been around here I have had the heat running pretty much all time.  Plus I live rent free and I get full pay on holidays, nevermind the airplane tickets to and from.</p>
<p>2. I was hired by the old head master, whom I have found to be a wonderful man who has taken me out to diner with his family twice.  I have every confidence that the charges of corruption and misappropriation of funds which lead to his dismissal were trumped up bullshit.  But I can see how the new headmaster would want to distance himself from me as I was hired by the old regiem.  I can see how the new guy would stick me on the list of his former counterparts many misappropriated funds, which is sure funny, I don&#8217;t feel misappropriated.</p>
<p>3. The new headmaster must be making his decision based on the budget because niether he, nor any of his flunkies, or anyone for that matter has ever sat in on one of my classes.  I would bet everything I have and any one of my toes that the new headmaster has never even spoken to a student.  If it happened I wasn&#8217;t there and it must have been by accident.  In the unlikely event that he does wind up talking to one of my students he will find that they love me, he doesn&#8217;t know that.  I had a vague idea about that but didn&#8217;t know how much until a few days ago, but we will get there too.</p>
<p align="center"><strong>The second part</strong> </p>
<p>So now it is the other end of the month, the day after Christmas, I wrote everything above a while ago and put it aside because I have been busy busy busy as they say.  Here is what I was busy with, in no particular order.</p>
<p>So like I was saying, May told me that I wasn&#8217;t getting my contract renewed, but she did already have a job all set up for me at the Primary school here in town.  They were offering more money, as it turns out the Primary schools are not provided for by the Chinese government the way middle and highschool are so they are more buyers market and therefor a higher paying position.  Nicer place too, I understand.  This was the same school that my friend Gina used to work at, and I was not thrilled about the things she told me about the job and I was not at all thrilled about the little kids.  But more money is more money.  And I held out for the garuntee of full pay on the holidays so I could travel to Singapore and Indonesia.  So we had a meeting where we sat down and agreed to giving me full pay on the holidays and a higher salery (not as high as Gina, but Gina specializes in small kids and I am new to it so I figured that was fair) and a super duper place to live, and a full ticket home, remeber this detail blog believers, I will come back to it later, that is what we like to call a subtle plot point. </p>
<p>So now my working and residence visa was running out in the middle of the month and I was a triffle miffed that they waited until the week before this happened to tell me that I was being let go, as they say.  So now I had to act fast and had no time to shop around.  I even went to the local college where my friends worked that week and they said they wanted to have me but they couldn&#8217;t renew my visa in time.  So I was stuck with the choice of this primary school or heading home.  And for a few days it looked like I was going stateside.  I got myself all mentally preped, I figered the timing was perfect, I could make the super hero party in disguise and hang around while they tried to call me via the computer only to jump out and yell surprise.  The cheers in my head, the hugs, the toasts, I would be welcomed as a hero I figured.  A few days later it occured to me that this would mean leaving China, and I just ain&#8217;t ready and that&#8217;s that.  So I chickened out and opted to stay here and do the primary school thing.</p>
<p>The last week here I didn&#8217;t teach, because screw them that&#8217;s why.  I was still a triffle miffed about the short notice plus I wanted to get ready to go.  Wednesday that week I went to the English team (unite English team) which was started by the students.  They are so cute, about 20 of them get together once a week and practice their English.  It was put together by a great kid I named Phil (they love it when you give them English names) and a girl named Rose.  Sometimes when I go to the English corner at the college to see my friends the English Team follows me, loaded down two to a bike.  I do a lot to help their team when I can because I think it&#8217;s cool that they are doing it, and they seem to like when I come to their practices.  That week I chose their meeting to make the announcement that I would be leaving the school.  I explained that the school didn&#8217;t want to spend the money so I must leave.  A few of the kids looked like I had punched them in their guts.  One guy put his head on my shoulder, and we stood that way for the whole practice.  Every once in a while a student would say &#8220;I don&#8217;t want for you to go&#8221; and I agreed.  So then word started spreading and I started getting knocks at my door, everyone wanted to know if it was true.  The next day a student and I made signs in Chinese saying that that night would be the final English corner.  As we hung them around the school, huge mobs of kids gathered and read, some walked away in indifference but some looked very sad.  It&#8217;s no lie, these kids looks as though my leaving was causing them grief.  Many kids asked me about it, some went out and came back with fruit or candy, or little santa clause nick nacks. </p>
<p>That day one of the knocks on my door brought a girl who was one of the first kids brave enough to seek me out back when I first arrived. She gave me a present, let me tell you about this thing.  It is an album of pages, maybe thirty or fourty pages, each page has a form on the front with questions filled in like, name, English name, birthday, talent, favorite singer, ect.  Each page is filled in by a different student who also decorated it a different way, often with photo booth pictures of themselves glued in and little messages written in the margins.  The back is for the student to write a little message to me, here are a few worded exactly as they appear, written by Chinese high school students.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hi, I am very sad when I heart you will leave us.  I have a lot of words to say but don&#8217;t know how to say.  I am very glad to know you.  You are my best teacher.  Please don&#8217;t forget me, ok?  I will remember you forever.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;teacher: I&#8217;m sad to hear you are going to leave us.  Because we all like you very much.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I am very happy because you teach my English.  And I think you&#8217;re very smart and funny.  But today, you will leave, it make me very sad.  I wish you can come back and teach our English.  Miss you everyday.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Never give up.  I love my teacher.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I was your student last term and I like your class very much.  I know a lot about your country from your class.  My dream is to be an English teacher.  I wish you will be successful!!  And you will be very happy.  Best wishes for you!!!  I like you forever!  Merry Christmas!&#8221; </p>
<p>&#8220;You are my teacher but I often feel you are our friend.  We like you because your class made everybody laugh.  Your impression are very funny (sometimes) I wish you happy everyday.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I hope you are happy forever.  I believe you, nothing in life is to be feared, it is only to be understood.&#8221;</p>
<p>For the record, I don&#8217;t do impressions, so I am not sure she is using the right word here, but you get the gist.  I held this thing in my hands and the two kids who presented it to me waited with smiles as I read each one, trying not to break down right there.  Keep in mind that this is the day after I broke the news that I was leaving, they must have had to bust their asses to get this thing done that fast.  So far one of the nicest, coolest fucking things anyone has ever done for me.</p>
<p>That night was the English corner.  This is a Thursday night tradition around here that I started to get the kids working on their English, plus it is a fun way to hang out with them away from the classroom.  That night I took my camera and spent the first half hour taking pictures of them.  Trying to get everyone proved futile, there were damn close to a hundred kids there at one point, give or take.  When the camera went away kids started getting bummed out about me leaving.  I had a few kids crying, I got a lot of hugs that night.  A few of them had written letters to me, my favorite had a drawing of me teaching that looked like one of the crazy drawings I always do on the blackboard.  At the end I was hugged over and over again by an endless train of kids for five minutes or so, which was hard because my arms were now filled with a various asundry of nick nacks and fruits and candys that had been awarded to me as gifts over the evening. </p>
<p>The English team were all there in force, and we tried to take a group photo but everyone else kept jumping in and in the end I told them a time when we could all meet the next day to do pictures.  So the next day I met them with my camera and they led me outside the school gate to a nearby semi scenic 12 foot tall fake mountain, where we met up with the professional photographer they had gone out and hired for the occasion with their own money.  They then gave me a bag with, hell, I don&#8217;t know, maybe a few hundred paper cranes of different sizes, each with a message written across the wings.  The messages say things like &#8216;happy everyday&#8217;, &#8216;best wishes&#8217;, &#8216;merry christmas&#8217;, and &#8216;we love you&#8217;.  The lump which had at this point formed in my throat was growing with malignancy and my eyes started to water, just a little.  And we took took the group photo I had promised them.  Then we took individuals, and were interupted by the bell.  They had to go to class so we didn&#8217;t get everyone, which was a bummer.  I tried to pay but was grabed and held back forcefully by 20 something highschool kids.  A few days later (as if it wasn&#8217;t already enough) I was given copies of all the pictures.</p>
<p align="center"><strong>The third part</strong> </p>
<p align="left">A little while before attending the super hero party live via satillite I was introduced to a bunch of dudes who like to play music.  What had happened was George (the other American) took me to a spot down the streat from his college where these dudes hang out.  The spot is a shopfront with concrete walls which are covered with the coolest teenage metal head graffiti imaginable.  One wall has &#8216;dead metal&#8217; scralled across it with a skull, next to the skull is the profile of a guys head with a mohawk, spiked ala 1970&#8217;s England.  On the guy&#8217;s skalp are the words &#8216;PUCK&#8217;, signifing that these dudes are all about puck rock music.  What really caught my eye was a picture of none other than the great Cliff Burton.  This impressed me to no end.  None of these dudes seemed to speak English, and they seemed a little annoyed at our presence, but George sat down and told them to play funk, which they did.  After a while George seemed to go into some kind of Hippy trance (George all over) and the guy seemed to be getting sick of it.  Thirty minutes later it was my turn and for the first time in a year I sat down behind a drumset.  A kid grabed a guitar and strumed what came out sounding like crunchy metal effects box sort of a thing.  Did my ears decieve me?  He started playing &#8216;enter sandman&#8217; by metallica, I haven&#8217;t played that fucking song since it was big when I was in high school, but it came back like riding a bicycle.  Then he started playing metal riffs and I started pounding the toms and crashing the cymbols with increasing speed, suddenly the five kids hanging out looking bored were 10 kids who didn&#8217;t look so bored.  I came back the next day, and the day after that, and on the third day we had ourselves a band, with our first gig set for Christmas eve, our band is called &#8216;Belief&#8217; and we seem to cover Chinese Metal songs.  I promised the guys that I would be at practice everyday for the following two weeks leading up to the gig.  It is an amazing thing, they barely if at all speak English and I barely if at all speak Chinese, and we can play and understand each other fine.  Sometimes its tough, you try listening for a cue to come back in based on a lyric in Manderin, but its good.  The very lovely Pamela comes and translates sometimes, and brings her two friends.  They sit in the corner and giggle, and sometimes we all sit around and drink together.</p>
<p align="left">The way they explained it to me, nobody in Shangqiu likes metal the way they do, everyone just likes Chinese pop music.  They told me that they wanted to play their music even if nobody will ever listen much less pay them, because this is the music in their hearts.  They love Slayer and Metallica and Pantera, and a bunch of Chinese Metal bands that they are getting me into.  It is a cool thing, a bunch of kids holed up in their little fort of a shopfront, throwing middle fingers at the world or anyone who is too good for their metal.  We hoisted bottles and they called me brother.</p>
<p align="left">One night last week we were playing the set the whole way through without stopping and the guitar player fucked up in a spot where he always tends to fuck it up.  I got up and went to the john, and when I came out everyone was outside screaming at each other.  I could tell it wasn&#8217;t good and getting worse.  The singer started punching the guitar player in the face, I grabed the singer and carried him away, then tackled him flat ass over tea kettle on the sidewalk and layed on top of him screaming &#8216;NO&#8217; in his face.  This gave me many flash backs to situations in Bands I was in back in the states, same old drama, same old rocknroll.  I made sure that everyone talked before they left, I explained (with the help of Pamala) that the band was too important and we had to get past it.  They went and talked, than we all drank beer.  The next practice the guitar player wasn&#8217;t there, but the one after he showed up smiling, everything forgiven.  Same old rocknroll.</p>
<p align="center"><strong>The forth part</strong></p>
<p>That Sunday I moved out, Shannon and Brett helped me move 2 big boxes a big suit case and a back pack into a taxi, along with my new boss Lily and Marlon.  Marlon is a cat that Gina had a lot of contact with.  They worked together and Gina he used to drive her straight up a tree, calling her all the time and asking why she was out so late, asking her who she was with, telling her to go home.  They weren&#8217;t even dating, not even close.  They lived in the same complex and Marlon used to watch her James Stewart style from the window to see when she was in and out.  So now he would be my new neighbor.  Gina tells me that he has almost been fired on numerous occasions but it never takes because he kisses the right asses.  This makes sense to me after the third time I have to repeat myself to him along the ten minute cab ride to my new place, his English, it turns out, is not quite as good as many of my 15 year old students not good for an English teacher.  He says some mess about a man living in my apartment and I demand to know what the hell he is talking about right away, Brett and I decide he is talking about a man who lives in the next door apartment or something, and we just can&#8217;t understand the guy and so the matter is considered solved.</p>
<p>The place is bigger than Jed Clampets pad, we are talking about a lush 4 bedroom apartment, big screen HD TV, gas burning stove in large kitchen, whole gigantic balcony, two of the rooms have beds already set up in case I have guests from out of town.  Shannon and Brett and I do a little dance.  I immediatly proclaim that the smallest room will be strictly for my dressing and undressing, and the other rooms will fill their own purpasses in time.  A little drafty, but damn, what a sweet pad!  That was Sunday.</p>
<p>Monday</p>
<p>Monday was the first day of class.  The way the classes were set up I would be teaching grades one through four on two week rotation, the third week would be spent at the country school.  This meant seeing the kids once every three weeks and in one sememster I would have each child a totall of 8 times out six months.  Plus the country school is way out in the country (duh) and that means the bus would drop me off in the morning and I would stay until the bus took me home around 5 in the pm.  With nothing but fields in any direction, this is not an ideal place to be stuck each day.  So none of the facts about this job which have been mentioned above were thrilling to me.  And I love teaching high school, I can watch them grow as they get braver and their English gets better.  We can conversate on matters of the world or love or music or whatever.  You can&#8217;t really say that you are friends with a little kid, no matter how cute they are.  Many may disagree but my preference is with the older ones.  I was teaching first years, and everywhere I went the kids mobed me, slamming into my body full speed.  I actually had to pull apart a manpile of tikes and take the poor kid on the bottom to the nurse, he had been crushed and trampled in the malay of kids trying to grab my leg, lucky for us he had been trampled by a heard of six year olds and was therefor (aside from a cut on his cheek) reletivly unscathed but he was sad and crying, poor old thing.  My lesson taught the little guys that elephants are big, which they wrote on their papers and then drew elephants, than we did cats, which are pretty, and if we had time we went to monkeys.  Each class had a teacher in the corner, each teacher seemed so utterly engrossed with whatever they were doing (crosswords, writting their memoirs) that they took little notice of me or of their class that was rapidly losing all self control or non screaming abilty.  We are talking about a room of 60 first graders, I have covered this ground in previous posts, but it is tough.  I started feeling that pain in my throat again.  It was screaming at me that if it kept up I would mess my voice up good and have to go to the doctor for real this time. </p>
<p>After all the classes that day I was told by Lily that the school had given another key to my flat to a worker who would be crashing with me for the next ten days.  I said like hell.  This was not covered in our little meeting, (she swears it was but I swear it wasn&#8217;t)  I did not know I would have roommates, now the huge place was making a little bit more sense.  This meant that whenever a worker came to the school to do whatever the school would stick them in my house for however long.  This is not what I signed on for and I wanted no part of it.  They said they couldn&#8217;t understand why I was so greedy as to want such a big place to myself, I said I would gladly take a smaller place.  I do not need a four bedroom apartment.  I reminded them that at this point I had not signed a contract yet, and my former school still owed me the money for one airplane ticket, I could always split.  I am at a point in my life where I am over room mates, especially the total stranger kind that are sprung on me from out of nowhere.  After going back and forth, Lilly walked into the office where all the other English teachers are and loudly so everyone could hear what an asshole I am called out &#8220;you can have that big apartment all to yourself, now.  Even though it is big enough for many.&#8221;  Which brought many many dirty looks from everyone, united in their contempt for the new foriegn teacher.</p>
<p>Tuesday</p>
<p>Tuesday they wanted me their at 8:30 like the day before.  Around quarter to 10 I asked when my class was, always at 10:30 they told me.  Well, why do I need to be here 2 hours early?  I asked.  It is the Chinese way.  Was the answer.  Well, like, the other teachers all have paper work to do, tests, home work, whereas I don&#8217;t.  I just sit here at my desk.  I could write lesson plans, was the answer.  Ten minutes later, Lilly approved my lesson plans for the next three weeks.  I pointed out that it was supposed to be a 22 hour a week job and this would make it a 32 hour a week job.  She said I could start showing up at 9:30, one hour wasted a day instead of two.  Then me and Marlon left to go get breakfast, which is a big no, no I later found out.  Marlon didn&#8217;t seem to give a fuck and I didn&#8217;t either.</p>
<p>Wednesday</p>
<p>On Wednesday before the classes started I was told that the school had decided to pay for my ticket all the way to California, not to Atlanta.  The school leaders had looked online and agreed that Atlanta was too much money and just so long as I was some place in the continental United States I should be happy.  I calmly pointed out that in that case I would be homeless and broke in a strange city, and I asked how much they would care to be in similar circumstances in Hong Kong.  See, Gina is from Vancover which is right on the west side, fairly cheap ticket as they go, they didn&#8217;t expect for it to be so much more, and seemed a bit peeved that I had dared to grow up that far East of Los Angeles.  I was also quick to (ever so calmly) point out that the leaders of the school were looking up airplane tickes the week before Christmas, and wouldn&#8217;t they care to look at a date a few months down the line.  This argument was dismissed immediatly as poppy cock and they maintained that they could pay for half my ticket and I could use the money my former school was giving my for the ticket from that contract to pay for the rest.  That is my money, (I ever so calmly explained) I earned every bit of it by completing a year long contract.  That money had nothing to do with my present contract or with this school and it was none of their buisness.  They had all sat down before I had said yes and before I had moved my shit and before I had taught a class and told me that they would pay my way home.  So I walked.  I told them I had to think long and hard.  I stayed in, thinking all day and into the night.  Pamala called and asked if I was going to practice, I said no, but it was cool as the gig wasn&#8217;t until the day before Christmas.  She called right back to say that it was actually in 2 days and nobody had bothered to tell me.  Same old rocknroll.</p>
<p>So I went to practice and I called them up the next day and said that I would be out by the days end, which I was, this time Wei helped me.  Moved in Sunday, and out Thursday, just in time for English corner.  My old school has let me move back here for the time being, they are being really cool.  And now I am unemployed in China.  Life is cool that way. </p>
<p align="center"><strong>The fifth part</strong></p>
<p align="left">So then Friday was the gig.  I showed up at 2 in the afternoon and after a quick sound check waited around all day, watching all the other bands set up too.  It was cool to see how many cool bands are in this city.  One of the bands actually almost had a surf thing going, they reminded me of the ventures at times.  A few bands got up and played covers of the god aweful pop music, which prompted the guys in my camp to whine like woman crying and mock dance and prance and pretend to make out with each other while those bands played.  It was a complete disrespectful act of agression against bands that represented the very evil with which my dudes are idealologically oposed.  One of the pop bands had a song which ended with the singers acapella sacrine whinning, well the whole thing was drowned out by the guys in my band screaming and wrestling each other over the last cigerettes in the last pack they had.  The guitarist on stage shook his head and scowled.</p>
<p align="left">  Around 5 the power went out, and with the show at 7 we all waited anxiously.  Pamala brought her friends Lin and Kathleen, they are all way fun and cute, pretty good English too, so I spent most of my time goofing off with them.  Wei came too, and we sat in the dark waiting. </p>
<p align="left">The gig was to be held in the speaker hall of the college which was packed by 7 and over flowing by 7:30.  I would guess around 2 or 3000 people in all, sitting in the dark, a sea of shadowy heads with many glowing LCDs from cell phones giving the appearance of waving lighters in the slow part of any Bon Jovi video.</p>
<p align="left">And we waited, and the lights still we not coming on. </p>
<p align="left">At one point the organizer of the thing came and drug me onstage.  He put me behind the drumset and asked me to play.  This was not expected and a little embarassing, but I started improvising and the crowd started screaming.  I must have played for a few minutes, big response from the crowd who were frankly glad to have any form of entertainment.  But it was a little embarrasing so I went and sat back down. </p>
<p align="left">And we waited, still no lights.</p>
<p align="left">The second hour I was amazed that the crowd had actually grown.  They were lining up outside to wait in the dark room, the heat was off too, by the way and it was getting cold.  I started getting stir crazy, before the gig jitters.  It is a nervous pent up energy, a very letmeatem sort of a thing.  I started feeling like a crazed rodeo steer bucking and smashing against a metal fence that would never open, wanting nothing more than to hospitalize or kill some hill billies, the hill billies so close yet so far.  I started shodow boxing in the dark.</p>
<p align="left">After about 2 hours they called it.  It was a shame too, I felt like after waiting that long this crowd was crazy primed and would have torn out their hair for us had we just gone on.  It was announced that we would just show up the next night, even though the schools Christmas pagent was scheduled.  I got the impression that my dudes had just sort of said, fuck them, what are they going to do?  Lets just show up.  Everyone agreed.  Same old rocknroll.</p>
<p align="left">So the next day came and I showed up at 2 again and sat around all day, this time the power didn&#8217;t go out and we played as scheduled.  I didn&#8217;t hear a pep from the Christas pagent people, I guess we won.  We were set to go first, which in America is a drag because nobody has showed up yet.  Well that night by 7 we already had mobs of people squatting in the isle and by all the exits (no fire inspecters here) so we must have played for around 3000 people.  Screaming people.  Shit they were loud, it was so cool, like being a real rock star, and we were blasting, everyone was on with everyone else.  The sound sucked though, and the man at the soundboard must have been on his first day, and the cymbal I was using kept coming loose so I had to chase it as I played, but hell, thats rocknroll.  I watched the whole show, and at the end the other kids from the space we rehearse, the students of the guys in my band got up with their punk band.  They were teenage kids playing punk too slow and off beat from each other, the coolest thing ever.  How many basements in America, or I guess all over the world have hosted just such teenage punk bands.  The guitarist jumped around and thrashed his head.  The base player at one point started to dramatically power walk across the stage when the cord on his guitar got to the end and he stopped for a second, not knowing what to do, so he dramatically power walked back in the right direction to where he was standing in an awkward attempt to play it off.  All of us were laughing our asses off at that.  And the guys who were playing the pop music were all music students and technically great, but these kids were playing music that was real to them and alive to them and exciting.  It made me happy to watch them jump around adn to know it was burning in them.  Then a few of them left the stage and a few more came on and they formed a metal band that started with a medley of Metallica riffs.  Fucking cool.</p>
<p align="left">The other night Pamala gave me a big surprise and the whole band showed up at my door with two bottles of wine for me, red wine.  It was Chinese and nothing to be snobby about but it was way nice of them to do.  They also went out and came back with a huge cake for me.  We all watched a dvd I have of the MIDI music festival in Beijing, which I went to this year.  They knew all the bands that were playing, and I promised to go next year and want them to come too.  They also smoked inside my place, and spat on the floor, (which is what folks do in China) but I didn&#8217;t care.  It was cool they came by, bringing gifts no less.  They wanted to party with me on Christmas eve and they wanted to give me gifts because they wanted to thank me for playing with them, which is crap I should be buying them stuff and thanking them.  But that&#8217;s rocknroll.</p>
<p align="left">That was last week, actually had our second gig earlier today.  This time it was an event that had all the leaders of the college sitting along a special table in the front row.  They were starring us down with angry frown.  Fuck em.  Everyone else was into it. We used their gear and although they had me there at 3 it wasn&#8217;t until 6, an hour before go time that we realized the floor pedel on the base drum was falling apart.  A dude jumped out of the crowd and him and I fixed it with a pair of wire cutters and a coat hanger and it worked better than it did before.  So lie.</p>
<p align="left">So here is the plan.  Next semester, Febuary 25 I will start teaching at the college, not as much money but my whole airplane ticket home plus not a bad place to stay, two bedrooms, clean, warm.  In the meantime I will be spending the airplane money from my last job travelling to Singapore and Indonesia.  This plan has many ways it could fall through but so far so good, I think I will leave next week, wish me luck.</p>
<p align="center"><strong>The sixth part</strong></p>
<p align="left">Christmas was good too.  Merry Christmas.  Me and Brett and Shannon gathered all the western food we could find and had pasta, instant mashed potatos, and bacon.  It was nice.  I hope your Christmas was great if you are into that sort of thing and I hope you are happy and well. </p>
<p align="center"><strong>The end</strong></p>
<p> 
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?feed=rss2&amp;p=55</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boys are strong, Rabbits can jump</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53</link>
		<comments>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 15:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will</dc:creator>
		
		<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This blog is dedicated to Amy B, it was her birthday just the other day and I wanted to give her a blog, she&#8217;s taken to hounding me about them and it seems to be the only thing that gets me motivated.  So in a way I wrote this as a present for her, although [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="left">This blog is dedicated to Amy B, it was her birthday just the other day and I wanted to give her a blog, she&#8217;s taken to hounding me about them and it seems to be the only thing that gets me motivated.  So in a way I wrote this as a present for her, although aside from what I just said none of it has a single thing to do with Amy.  I actually hung up the phone with her and Ryan yesterday at around 1 pm my time, midnight there, and I stopped writting at 11 last night.  So, I just finished another long one, I have yet to get a single complaint about them running too long, I figure the ones who mind don&#8217;t bother and the ones that don&#8217;t mind seem to get into it.  And it helps me to write about everything so I will be able to go back and look years from now.  And in a way it feels like taking a huge shit, getting it all out.  So here it goes, its not really about anything more than the things going on in my life these past two months.  It ends on a sad note, but you&#8217;ll get there.  Funny stuff too, Halloween, a special apearance by Ultraman, and an alchahol feuled action adventure, whoa billy. </p>
<p align="center"><strong>I</strong> </p>
<p>So I guess I will just start with Halloween.  Might as well.  That was a couple of weeks ago.  I spent the whole week teaching my kids about Halloween, I first taught them the word costume, which proved trickey, I had to use the Chinese word which I made them race with their dictionarys to it look up to see who was fastest.  I told them about trick or treating, and I told them that if any students dressed up in a costume on Halloween day than I would give them candy, garunteed.  I wanted to impart the spirit of Halloween the way I knew it. I told them about how if someone stingey so and so doesn&#8217;t give candy than sometimes the children will be forced to preform a small bit of mischeif known as the trick, which may involve dispensing toilet paper all over the offending house, and I drew a house covered with toilet paper complete with dancing stick figure children in the yard throwing the paper.  The stick figure children were smiling and dancing.  I told them that when I was young I once did this, not all the way true but I did try once.  I recall the attempt we made as kids was against a menace of a shit bag 16 year old named Nathan Guant, but we didn&#8217;t have much drive or attention span or toilet paper so it was sorry and piss poor and all of what little we bothered to throw was on the ground by morning, I remember my friend Adam&#8217;s older sister telling us we were so lame.  Of coarse the way I told the kids every inch of the house was covered, their little eyes bugged out, and of coarse my story ended with my getting in trouble over the incident just to wrap up everything with a cautionary note to be on the safe side, although I can not imagine any of my students ever even thinking about doing such a thing.  They really lost it when I explained that this stunt was most funny on nights when it rained and the paper stuck to the house. </p>
<p>I told them about baked pumpkin seeds and my grandmothers pumpkin pie which was the best in the whole world, and I told them about jackolanturns.  I told them about monsters and used the bad guys in Ultraman as examples, and drew Ultraman fighting a giant google eyed slime monster.  I made them raise their hands if they liked monster movies, some didn&#8217;t and I asked them why, some did and I asked them why. I taught them about Dracula, and about how he sleeps during the day and used a sleeping student as an example.  I told them about Frankenstein and pretended to be the monster coming to life through electricity, then I charged at their desks with my arms stiff in front of me growling ferociously, the students screamed and lept out of their chairs.  I told them all about warewolves and I told them with dire certainty that they would all need to know about how to kill one as there are in fact many such monsters right here in Shangqiu.  The students all said &#8216;no, no teacher we will not believe you.&#8217; and I walked around behind one of the boys backs pointing to his head and raising my eyebrows to indicate he was a warewolf.  Unfortunatly, none of my students had silver bullets handy.  And then we all decided which students were warewolves and which were vampires like Dracula, and I asked them why monsters in Chinese movies hop up and down and I spread my arms out and hopped like a Chinese monster which caused many of the students to do the same just as the bell wrang to end class.  I left the classes that week hollering over the hopping vampires and the screaming kids and the chair legs scraping the floor and the holabalu of the children exploding into motion at the sound of the bells just the Pavlov proved they would.  I was hollering that English corner would be held that Thursday and that on Wednesday if anyone wore a costume on Halloween I would give them candy.  Some heard, some didn&#8217;t, some smiled and waved, some were already on their cell phones, a couple still hopped like vampires. </p>
<p>Usually my lectures invovle a little more serious subject matter and I also try to do games or activities which make (force under threat of humiliation) the students speak as much as possible, but sometimes I have to make sure they are having fun.  I seem to be the only teacher they have ever to do so.  May told her classes that on Wednesday I would be giving candy to every single student.  I had to go tell her kids that only kids with costumes would get candy and May thought that is wasn&#8217;t fair to the children who didn&#8217;t want to put forth any effort.  I suppose in some bizzare way in May&#8217;s head this is true, but in my head I am always right and she is always wrong.  She disagrees with this and it seems to be a running theme in our friendship, we are still best friends, May and I.  And we delight in arguing all the time.  I am so lucky to know May.</p>
<p>Speaking of friends, I am so happy to say that I have found cool westerners to shoot the shit with, Brett and Shannon are a married couple from Saskatchewan.  They are teaching at the college and I feel like we get along well.  Brett is a good guy and willing to drink whiskey all night and in the morning Shannon makes breakfast and shakes her head at how bad we were being.  And we talk and have great conversations and we travel to other cities on the weekends  So now life here aint so bad now, which is cool.  </p>
<p>That was the week before Halloween and Brett and I went to the candy market to shop for our students.  Brett and Shannon have way less students than I have (maybe around 1700 this semester) so they can actually buy cool prizes and shit for their students.  I am jealous that they can learn their kids names as well, by the way.  Anyhow, the candy market is a row of many stores along a street run by little chinese ladies who generally buy bulk candy which they turn around and sell wholesale to little stores.  The cool thing about this is the old ladies kick up a huge fuss and they wanted me to sample all the various delights.  Gum drops and things that were sort of like toostie rolls and strawbery mints and babana toffe and huge boxes of chocolete.  I left with a pillow cased sized bag of fake apple jolly rancers and some cinimen stuff that wound up being all sucky and a huge jar of chewing gum.  If these kids wore costumes I would be ready, if they punked out than I would have a ton of candy for almost nothing which is never all bad.</p>
<p>The college Halloween dance party was a costume event, so I did the best I could.  I figured I would be a rat if I didn&#8217;t come up with something, especially after teaching the kids about it all the past week.  So I wound up buying some chicken wire and wrapping it into a cone.  I then covered that in wrapped masking tape, painted eyes and cut out teeth for me to look out of.  It had horns and stands maybe almost five feet, maybe four and a half.  And I went to the college party and rocked it, and on Halloween day I wore y giant head to all my classes.  I was quite a sight, strutting around that way all day.  The kids all flipped out, and I was walking around the campus and saw the head master and all the school leaders, marched up and said hello, the head master looked like he didn&#8217;t know what to do and maybe would cry if I didn&#8217;t leave, so I did.  That was also the week I had a real bad cold and sore throat.  I made myself cowboy through it, it just wouldn&#8217;t do to be sick on Halloween.</p>
<p>All along I had guessed that one brave kid would wear something like a costume, but I was so jazzed that night when I got a steady stream of kids who had made masks out of paper.  Ask Ryan Burk about it, he had called me that night and we were talking as the kids were knocking on the door so he got to listen to the whole thing.  They had colored the masks and cut out eye holes, some of them were very creative, one kid tried turning his mask around and come back, which was crap and I told him that was an old trick and it wouldn&#8217;t work.  I only gave him a little candy the second time.  With most of the kids I was so thrilled I was dropping fist fulls of candy on them.  It was actually better than the always disapointing turnout in America.  One year, when I lived in Kirkwood I only got one trick or treater all night.  He was a kid from the neighborhood who had somehow managed to make a costume that made him look and smell just like a 60 year old crack head holding a dirty trash bag and no costume, the trick or treater said &#8220;trick or treat&#8221; through missing teeth.  I looked at him for a long time.  Finally I told him I wouldn&#8217;t give him any candy.  He pointed out that the least I could do was give him some cigerettes, I told him to get the hell off my porch or I was calling the police.  The trick or treaters in China this year were much better.</p>
<p>Plus in my classes that day we were playing a game where I read a block of text and the class bust into teams and competed in answering my questions.  On Halloween I was throwing candy to any student who got a right answer.  I was also asking difficult questions about the subject of the text which required them to think, which they seem to not do as well at.  They do much better when it comes to remembering facts or retrieving information found in the text.  Then at the end of class I was throwing fistfulls of candy out like Mardi Gras! Hip, Hip, Hurray for Halloween! </p>
<p>In the mornings those weeks I was working at another school, these kids were little, maybe 5 or 6 and they had been learning English since september, this being October, don&#8217;t you know.  When I explained to them &#8216;an apple is red&#8217; that was new information.  I felt it was difficult to teach them much of anything outside of memorization, every single thing that came out of my mouth they hollered it back in unison weather I liked it or not, a class of parrots.  This is the Chinese teaching style, conditioning from the age of very small to repeat in barking repition, never think, there is simply no need, just as long as they can memorize and regergitate the information on command.  So, on the first day I made the mistake of trying to teach them to respond to my saying &#8216;hello, how are you?&#8217; with &#8216;I am fine, thankyou.&#8217;  Well I wrote the whole thing on the board, and I had them repeat it a few times, which they were marvoulous at doing, then I asked them one on one &#8216;Hello, how are you?&#8217; and without fail each and every kid hollered at the top of their lungs  &#8220;hello how are you?&#8217; back in my face.  I was totally unable to break through the wall and have any one of kids respond &#8216;I am fine, thank you.&#8217; like I had asked a qustion.  And with highschool kids somewhere between my shitty shitty Chinese and thier highschool English level we can comunicate at least enough so I can get my point across, here I am at a loss.  On top of everything else I would have each class for fourty minutes one day every other week, so it is more or less futile to try to counter the conditioning their teachers have implanted in them all day long 6 days a week.</p>
<p>I recently sat in on a few Chinese classes during a day-long seminar I attended.  The teacher had a smile that was too big and phony which she used to patrol the room, her 12 year old students were expert repeaters, her arm was held out stiff and bent at the elbow in a C3PO pose, she was a prize winning dog trainer showing off her little Chinese human poodles.   The teacher was screaming a little, speaking English as fast as possible, ever smiling with cold teeth.  The over head projector clicked to the next slide, it was two children, one had a balloon over his head that read &#8216;What color is my cap?&#8217;  The teacher had her one girl and one boy out of the whole class who were good enough to answer all the questions, the majority anyway.  When she didn&#8217;t ask those two she encouraged the whole entire class to scream in unison like a company of marines.  A few times she ventured into the rest of the class, carefully avoiding the stupid ones, but she usually called on her two fav&#8217;s in the front.  She asked the boy in the front &#8217;what color is my cap?&#8217; and the boy stood suddenly and hollered &#8216;its <em>a</em> blue.&#8217;  &#8216;that is good.  Its <em>a</em> blue.&#8217;  Then she asked the whole class, the whole class seemed to agree in sreaming unison &#8216;Its <em>a</em> blue.  Blue, blue, blue&#8217;.  &#8216;Spell <em>it</em>&#8216;, she stress the word <em>it</em> like her life depended on <em>it.  &#8216;</em>B-L-U-E&#8217;  &#8216;Spell <em>it.&#8217;  &#8216;</em>B-L-U-E&#8217;.  &#8216;Spell <em>it&#8217;.</em>  &#8216;B-L-U-E&#8217;.  Each time, the B-L-U-E was barked out with speed and anger and hate, like they were all training for a war against the insideously wicked color blue and his godless army of &#8216;what color is my cap&#8217; and the ever impending threat of &#8216;Do you like a big panda or do you like a small panda?&#8217; who were suspected of being long time loyalist sympathizers with and geneally known to be (at the very least) in cohoots with the &#8217;Do you like to sing a song at Kangkang&#8217;s birthday party?&#8217; Gorilla terrorists.</p>
<p>I would also ask you, dear blog believer, when the hell have you ever in your life had to respond to someone asking you the question, &#8216;what color is my cap?&#8217;.  But just in case it does come up, just remember &#8216;its <em>a</em> blue.&#8217;  Thats B-L-U-E!</p>
<p>The next slide was a picture Yao Ming who plays in the NBA for the Huston Rockets, easily the most famous man to Chinese Children aside from Mao Ze Dong or Jackie Chan or Confucious.  &#8216;Who is <em>it</em>&#8216;?  The whole class now, &#8216;<em>It</em> is Yao Ming&#8217;.  Then to the one boy she always calls on, &#8216;Is Yao Ming very strong?&#8217;  The boy shot out of his seat like it was on fire and hollored &#8216;Yes he is&#8217;.  Then the teacher asked the boy, &#8216;Are you very strong?&#8217;  To which the boy hollered &#8216;Yes, I am.&#8217;  &#8216;Yes, you are very strong.  That is right.&#8217;  The teacher than turned to the girl to the left of the boy and asked the same question.  &#8216;Are you very strong?&#8217;  To which the girl replied &#8216;No, I am not very strong.&#8217;  The teacher barked back, &#8216;yes, you are right, you are not very strong.&#8217;  She then went around the room to all her little trained poodles.  Like well oiled robots each boy said that he was strong and each girl said that she wasn&#8217;t strong.  And with the exception of the boy who froze and couldn&#8217;t remember what to say (the only time I saw this ladies smile disapear) they all agreed that boys are very strong and girls are not. </p>
<p><em>*<u>Footnote-More of interest on this subject at the end of the post.</u></em></p>
<p>I was sitting next to the days key note speaker, a nice lady who as strange coincedence would have it had taught at the same school my friends Shannon and Brett worked at last year.  Her English was pitch perfect and we had been chatting all day.  She was taking careful notes during the class in question, she didn&#8217;t look impressed.  She asked me if I ever used the overhead projector in my class, and I told her that none of the class rooms had overhead projectors and if they had told her different they were lying.  She nodded slowly.  Later that day one of the many things covered in her three hour lecture cautioned teachers against pretty much everything I just told you about, so my faith in all Chinese education was now more or less restored.  I sat next to the poodle trainer who twisted in her seat nervously, her smile had scramed.</p>
<p>So I mentioned that that week I was teaching the little kids, they were little 5 year old repeating machines.  The first day I was there they had a guy come to take my picture as I taught.  The last day I was there they had actually called a news crew to come and cover the event.  I have taught kids that age before at my friends small weekend school, there I enjoyed small classes of 10 or 15 kids.  I had always found that the kids love it when I get em krunk.  They never get the outlet, see?  They never get to just be silly and blow off the steam.  So, I was doing with the class of 70 5 year olds what I always do with 15 5 year olds, even with their teachers there urging calm from the back of the room it didn&#8217;t take long for the whole thing to go hockey match.</p>
<p>Here is why, my lesson that week was that a rabbit can jump, a bird can fly, a fish can swim, a dog can bark, and a monkey can climb.  After I wrote the shit on the board, drew pictures of the animals to make sure they knew, made them repeat it a few times, made up a song about the sentence they had to sing, then everyone was out of their seats and I had these kids jumping like Rabbits.  I was jumping as high as I could and we all screamed &#8216;a rabbit can jump, a rabbit can jump&#8217; but not in any kind of unison.  No, we were fucking sloppy disorganized.  I had them fly like birds, they flapped their wings and I picked some of them up off the ground and flew them around like little airplanes, this made them so crazy and happy I thought a few of them might explode.   Then they learned how dogs can bark, so there is an even chance that TV crew put me on the local news barking at the top of my voice at a child, I didn&#8217;t see it so I don&#8217;t know.  The children made very good dogs, I thought, and they took to running around barking at each other like pros.  I looked to the teachers standing in the back of the room, they looked very nervous.  Then we learned that a fish could swim, which called for everyone swimming like fish, then a monkey can climb, and everyone climbed an invisable tree, or there desks in one or two cases.  One child climbed to the top of his desk and demonstrated how lemmings can drop.  He was ok though.  He was smiling. </p>
<p>Mind you, the whole time after acting out each animal I had them sit down and learn the next sentance about what another animal can do.  And yeah, it was totall chaos and I was screaming my self horse trying to quite them down enough to say the next thing, thats what you get when you put 70 5 year olds together and make them jump and scream like wild animals, I know that.  But I bet that when that kid is 10, they will know the word for what a rabbit does in English, or at least they will remember how much fun we had trying to learn.  I bet some of them will remember how much fun we had that day a long time past age 10. </p>
<p>The class concluding with a pop test, &#8216;this side of the room,&#8230;.. ALL MONKEYS!  MONKEYS.  What can a monkey do?  Yes, yes CLIMB, CLIMB!  This side of the room,&#8230;.wait for it, wait for it&#8230;..DOGS!  And what can a dog do?  YES YES, a dog can bark, ok, everybody,&#8230;..SWIM!&#8217;</p>
<p>I appologized profusely after class to their next teacher.  I wouldn&#8217;t have wanted to handle that class.  As I left I went around giving the kids high fives and shaking their hands.  Many wanted to hug me.  A boy in the back hugged me and he said &#8216;I like you very much&#8217;.  I learned later that all through the class this boy had begged his teachers to tell him how to say this to me.  Outside the class all 70 surrounded me, all trying to hug me or shake my hand at the same time.  I think I was a big hit.  It was nice to feel that much love too, I don&#8217;t think I deserve it, but I would be lying if I said that it didn&#8217;t feel really nice and magical.</p>
<p>So, like I said, I was nursing a sore throat that week.  Screaming at the absolute top of my lungs that day didn&#8217;t help matters, nor did all my other six classes that day, on top of everything else that was the day of my schools big English Corner.  I may or may not have mentioned English corner before.  At the Shangqiu college where Brett and Shannon teach has an English corner which involves being surrounded by super duper college girls who want nothing more than to ask me questions to improve their English, sort of like the beer commercial where the loser opens a coors light and his office turns into a beach filled with girls in bikinis.  Sort of like that without the beer, beach or bikini.  That was the cause of my initial interest, but now I have found that I am making friends with many of the college students and I look forward to our conversations, sadly from lack of anything better to do, English corner has become a mainstay of my social life.  So, this past month I started one at my school, a place where any student who felt like it could voluntarily go and try to have conversations in English one night a week for an hour.  The first few nights had me as a nucleus surrounded by an inner ring of believers who wanted to work on their English, than a significantly larger outer ring of kids who were there to make fun of us by calling &#8216;Hull-ooo&#8217; in a high pitch girly falsetto.  Well, I am proud as hell to say that at this point I have my English corner growing steadily in force, the last one was huge and a lot of fun.  Brett came out to the last two and brought a few of his students with him.  I have a pack of cool boys who hang around with their elbows resting on my shouldier the whole time to show that we are bro.  And I seem to have my ever loyal giggle section of young girls, who want to flirt and blush which is creepy but flattering and funny at the same time.  Often creepy though.  And I am starting to get the younger kids out too, and I ask them things about their favorite color, or which one can run the fastest, that sort of thing.  I have yet to mention anything about English corner to the school leaders, this is somethihg I am doing on my own steam for my dedicated students and because we all have fun.  I have even asked some teachers to come, they show up for a minute and make sure I see them and then leave.  So it is all me and the kids who are into it and I dig that.  Last week we tried to convince the kids that Brett (who clears six feet) was not nearly as tall as I am.  Brett tried to tell my kids that he was standing on two students.  That had them laughing.  Last week a boy and a girl who I taught last semester told me they wanted to start their own English club, I said that was the coolest thing ever.  I also asked if I could joing their team,&#8230;&#8230;..official member.  That&#8217;s right. </p>
<p>Meanwhile English corner involves me hollering over the din of questions and laughter from the kids.  And there are so many, now I am having to holler louder and louder and if there is still circle of kids making fun of us outside our circle we can&#8217;t see or hear them, and I promise we out number the haters and even if they are there nobody notices or cares anyway. </p>
<p align="center"> <strong>II</strong></p>
<p>The week before I went to South East Asia (back in the summer) I met a man from Ghana at the gate of my school.  He saw me and told me to hurry, we had to talk and it had to be fast, did I have someplace we could go?  I said sure and we went into my school, he was looking over his shouldier.  Micheal had been studing in Moscow, a friend had told him about a great school in Shangqiu.  The great school turned out to be best foriegn language school and also turned out to be run by a souless mother fucker who explained that the terms for the job would be discussed on arrival.  So, of coarse on arrival it turns out that the terms are you get to sleep on the floor of the classroom and eat three bowls of rice a day for free and teach as many classes as the souless motherfucker says.  Here I will point out that only an idiot would travel all the way from Moscow to China with no way to go someplace else and not know the terms of the job in advance, but also that only a souless motherfucker would prey on and victimize them in this way. </p>
<p>So Micheal told me his trouble and I sympathized with him, I think I understood most of what he said, his accent was heavy.  He begged me to help him find a job and I agreed to try.  After he left my appartment the souless motherfucker was waiting in the hall, he looked frantic, like a bounty hunter tracking his querry.  &#8220;I looked everywhere for you.&#8221;  he forced a smile when he saw me.  The guy is short and fat and bald and has human shit in his heart and veins instead of blood.</p>
<p>After asking around it turned out that most of the people in Shangqiu are totally racist, an obvious by product of growing up in a small city and never ever ever seeing a single black person.  Not an excuse, just an explanation.  I told people his qualifications and people seemed all excited until they found out he was from Africa.  &#8220;Micheal couldn&#8217;t be a good teacher because the children would be too afraid of his skin&#8221;.  Direct word for word quote.  Maybe they would have been too, and of coarse I argued that Micheal could win them over and forever break this chain of ignorance.  Deaf ears.  This pissed me off but they don&#8217;t really have any kind of anything like they have in the United States for that sort of thing, can&#8217;t sue, can&#8217;t call the news, news wouldn&#8217;t care even if the government gave them permission to cover such a subject, which will never hapen in a million years.  So not really much I could do about it.  A week went by and I left for South East Asia.  When I got back my friend Micheal was gone.  I never learned where.  I guess it stuck in my craw a little, I wanted to help the guy and I couldn&#8217;t.  Hell I tried right?</p>
<p>The week after Halloween brought another knock at my door revieling another man from Ghana, same deal, all stuck, spent all his money coming to China from Moscow.  His name is Emmanuel and he said he had a masters, I went to the school that night to see him and I found him locked inside the empty school.  I talked to him through a crack in the door.   He told me he didn&#8217;t have the key and couldn&#8217;t get out.  He told me he held a masters degree, and as proof he passed me the sylabus for a class in administering care for someone suffering from diabetis, which I felt didn&#8217;t really prove that he had a masters degree.  I pointed out that now that he had given it to me I could just as well have a masters degree by his logic for all anyone else knew.  I didn&#8217;t press the matter.  He asked me to write him a letter of recomendation, which I said I couldn&#8217;t do as I didn&#8217;t really know him.  On the wall was a bulletin board of pictures of the students at the best foriegn language school, many of which had the faces of African teachers.  I saw Micheal in a few of them, and a couple of guys I didn&#8217;t recognize.  Clearly this was the souless motherfuckers game.  Get them to come to China on their own dime, and treat them like shit until they figure a way to escape, then find another poor sucker who will be trapped into being a free teaching slave for a few months.</p>
<p>I told Shannon this story on the phone and she said I had to contact their friend Avros, the Indian foriegn teacher at their college.  Avros is sort of a legend around here, everyone seems to know him, his name often mentioned always with respect.  He has his own foriegn language school, and he seems to know people in the Shangqiu government.  I told him what was what and he agreed to take Emmanuel to see some of the people in the government to take this dude down.  I was all happy to find a good fat cat to pick a fight with, and Shannon and I agreed to help buy the guy a ticket to Beijing where he would have a lot better chance of finding a job than here.  I offered to let the guy sleep on the floor of my tiny appartment and Shannon lent me some bedding for him.  It would only be for a few days, I reasoned, and then he would be on a train and gone.  Best of all the souless motherfucker would be out a teacher.  I noticed that he only had leather dress shoes and no socks so I took him to the outside shoe market and got the guy some sneakers and socks.  I gave him the food card for my school cafeteria so he wouldn&#8217;t go hungry.  That night Emmanual and I stayed up talking about the souless motherfucker, all though Emmanuel would never use such words.  To him he was a very bad man, very bad man, Which he said over and over.  He stood in my office, paceing as he talked with indignation.  The point which he often returned to was that it was human exploitation, he said that again and again, and I said yeah!</p>
<p>So the next day, I took him to meet Avros, we went right before their English corner started.  Emmanuel told him his story about what had happened and his conditions and everything else.  Avros explained that the three of us would go to the city and talk to some people and get this guy busted with the authorities.  Suddenly, out of nowhere, uncharactoristic of anything he had said before, Emmanuel refused to go.  He would not help us, he didn&#8217;t want any trouble.  Avros asked why he expected us to help him if he wouldn&#8217;t help himself, which I found to be a paramount question.  His feet were dug into the sand, even when we reasoned that we could put him on a train to go away for ever that same day, he still wouldn&#8217;t budge.  Mind you that as far as anyone could see, the souless motherfucker wouldn&#8217;t be able to touch Emmanuel, please do not think this guy is somehow dangerous with connections like in a movie, he is just a shit bag low rent con man.  I would guess the ones at risk were Avros, who was sticking his neck out by asking a favor of his friends in the government, and me because the souless motherfucker knew where I live and could concievably show up with some boys if we managed to fuck him up enough.  But Emmanuel wouldn&#8217;t help so nothing was done, so I expect another man from Ghana who came by way of Moscow knocking on my door any month now.</p>
<p>I had gone from having a mission to having a man on my floor and I was ready for him to go.  He spent the next three days on my computer, hunting and pecking, asking for help over and over.  The final straw came when by buddy Ryan Burke called from America and he acted like I was being rude for talking so long, as though it was somehow his computer.  That was that.  He had a few Chinese friends that picked him up that day, and I gave him some money for a ticket, not a lot but not a little either, almost enough to take him all the way down south to Guangzhou where I am told many people from Africa live, his Chinese friends helped him out with a little money too.  And so he showed up the next day looking to crash and had no explanation for why he hadn&#8217;t gone to Guangzhou yet, I told him he could get on the train or stay some place else, I had already done enough and I wanted my appartment back.  His Chinese friend offered me a ciggerete and I told him I don&#8217;t smoke.  So the guy lit up in my appartment and suddenly it wasn&#8217;t cool at all anymore and I told him to go.  I started dragging his shit to the door and he argued with me and I turned to homeboy and in a not very nice way said &#8216;could you please not smoke in my house?&#8217;.  That day I finally broke down and let him leave his shit in my place but not but he had to stay elsewhere.  Mind you I have taken the train to Guangzhou, it leaves everyday at midnight, a fact.  I was willing to take him by taxi to the train station, but I am not running a youth hostel, you will not find my name listed in lonely planet.  He came back the next day and I think the whole reason for not leaving was he thought I would let him use my computer which I would not.  I told him to go to an internet bar.  Internet bar in China is really cheap.  He could sense the tension so he showed me pictures of the wife and kids he has back home.  He showed me pictures of him taking care of AIDS patients.  This made me think more of him, but I still wanted him the hell out of my house.  Move along, rollemout.  So I helped him catch a cab, we took the cab into my school and I ran in front clearing kids out of the way, sort of mother hen of me but I am so scared about how Chinese Taxi drivers work.  I hear he is in Guangzhou, and I hope he is ok.  I realize that he can&#8217;t speak Chinese and has no money, I tried to convince him to go to Beijing to get to his consulate, but he wouldn&#8217;t listen.  And I sympathize and hope he has found friends and I hope he is eating but at the same time I have been to Guangzhou and it is bigger that Shangqiu so there are more chances than Shangqiu, and it has many Africans so there is hopefully less racism than here and more people who will help him.  And may I remind you that you do not come to a foriegn country if you don&#8217;t have any garuntee of a job.  I feel like I helped him the best I could.  Yeah, he is in a shitty place, but I think it is at least as shitty as being here.  I am waiting to hear from him, I hear he is in Guangzhou now. </p>
<p> </p>
<p align="center"><strong>III</strong></p>
<p align="left">That week I think I got over the cold symptoms but the sore throat was getting worse.  It was aching at the end of each class, I felt like I was tearing my throat to pieces.  That week was much more subdued.  I Hung up a map of the United States and took them on a state by state tour of my country.  I also taught them a little spanish when I got to Mexico (Mushaguo in Chinese).  That weeks English corner at my school was even bigger than the week before, which was amazing.  Now I am giving kids English names, which they want me to do all the time. </p>
<p align="left">And last week I went to a resturant that I hadn&#8217;t been to before.  I try to do this from time to time as it forces me to speak more Chinese.  The guy was pleased to see me, he brought me an entire medium sized bottle of Chinese rice wine, bi zhou (pronounced byjoe).   Then one of those one in a million chance things happened.  The weekend before had been the night of the big Halloween shindig at the college, and that night me and Brett opened the bottle of Jamison we had found the week before that in Zhengzhou.  See, the week before Haloween me and Shannon and Brett had gone on a 3 hour train ride essentially to eat at Mcdonalds and shop for stuff we can&#8217;t get here like Cheese and bacon.  We also found an all you can eat pizza shop which also had buffolo wings.  We asked how much was the beer and it wound up also being all you can eat, so we had several.  But amoung other things we found a bottle of Jamison whiskey.  So the night of the Halloween party Brett and I stayed up all night finishing it.  I hope I didn&#8217;t make a rambling ass of myself but I am pretty sure enough that I did.  Brett and Shannon are so cool they didn&#8217;t seem to mind.  The point of the story is that the Jamison came with a tiny airplane bottle which I had put into my jacket pocket.  So here was a guy giving me a whole bottle of bizhou, and it occured to me.  I pulled it out of my jacket pocket and in exchange presented him with a miniature bottle of Jamison, fine fine whiskey.  So he sat down and we drank a few shots together, him the whiskey and me the bizhou.  Clearly he got the better bargin but it was ok, he seemed so happy with this.  All the cooks came in from the back, and the waiters stoped what they were doing and a few of the costomers came to check things out.  Then they poured out more bizhou and I tried to refuse but they weren&#8217;t hearing it, then they brought me beer, and I toasted them all in Chinese and they smiled and bowed their heads and I downed another shot, and I went home and slept until diner time.  I am happy to say that now when I go in there I am treated like a foriegn dignatary, a foriegn dignatary that likes to drink a little with lunch.  Byzhou is not good for a sore throat.  Neither is beer.  I was drinking plenty of both last week.   </p>
<p align="left">Jane sent me a message that she was sad, and she said that she wanted to be alone for a few days.  This was not good news.  I emailed her each day trying to see what was wrong, but respected that for some reason she wanted to be left alone so I didn&#8217;t call her.  I didn&#8217;t know why she was doing this but I was worried about her, and I had a bad feeling about things. </p>
<p align="left">But I was distracted, I was all set to go to Keifeng.  Shannon and Brett and I went last Friday night.  Kaifeng is about an hour and a half train ride away and was once the capital of China, way back in the day, about 1000 years ago.  At some point invading forces caused the Emporer of China to flee the city and he took up residence in Shangqiu, so the capital seat of China was actually briefly in my home town, you can still see some of the remnates of which in the south of our town.  At any rate, Kaifeng is the city I wrote about in the the third Blog I ever wrote on this websight, back in January when my sorry ass just got here.  The blog is titled “one item one should never find one’s self for want of when paying a visit to the docter in Zhengzhou”, go give her a look, blog believers.  I just reread it, and it&#8217;s a trip to think how strange my whole world was back in January.  Now it is all normal, I am hardened to it.  The novelty and the shock have long since vanished and I am existing on my own terms in another planet.  Life in America seems like a distant dream or memory which I recall everytime I get an email or call from a good friend. </p>
<p align="left">So anyway, where the hell was I, anyhow?  Oh, ok, yeah.  Right.  Back in Kaifeng.  The first thing we did Friday night was to go visit the night market.  A night market is a place in a city where the streets are lined with little carts that have foods of every possible description.  Lots of meat roasted on sticks over fire, lots of interesting things we couldn&#8217;t identify.  Lots of cool stuff.  We found one guy who had sheep eyes on a stick so of coarse I said we should try em.  Brett agreed and Shannon was grossed out, so her and their Chinese friend who (I spent last weekend with but whose name already escapes me) went to KFC.  It was gooey, and chewey, kind of like fat on a steak but round in a ball.  The idea made me gag at first but aside from that it was really tasty.  I must say, a fine juicy meat, sheep eye on a stick.  And yes I know it was the eye and not the testicle, you smart ass, you.  It looked like an eye, thats why I know.  Shut up.   And even if it was the ball, so what?  People in other countries do it, so what.  It wasn&#8217;t though, I am sure I ate a lambs eye shish kabob.  Nothing gross like testicles.</p>
<p align="left">So we wandered around the night market, had a lot of food, a lot of which can be found at most night markets in China, the one in Kaifeng is mainly famous for its size I think.  Brett and I sank a few beers talking to a guy from the autonomous region of Xinjiang, which is an area that is in many ways outside of China.  The language, for example is an entirely different linguistic family from Mandarin or cantonese and they all wear long beards.  When I had a long beard many Chinese people guess I was from Xinjiang, it made more sense to them than America.</p>
<p align="left">So we talked with him the best we could and ate meat on a stick and sank a few beers.  The girls were going to bed and the temperature was droping fast so I recomended to Brett that I pick up a bottle of the homemade bizhou I saw on the street and we just head back to the hotel.  Having an extra girl (what the hell was that girls name?  Christ! Its driving me nuts, you know?  Just give me some time, maybe I&#8217;ll get it.)  Meant that we were sleeping boy boy and girl girl, so we had two rooms with two beds.  The homemade bizhou stand had pulled up stakes when we came to it so I grabed a cheap brand bottle from a cart with wine and cigerettes and we started heading home, maybe 20 minutes after the girls.  We went around the corner of the building to an alleyway to get into our hotel, and Brett spied what was sure enough a dance club, neon lights pouring, base bumping.  So I tucked the bizhou safe in my jacket pocket and we went in.  The music was too loud to talk and the dance floor was packed.  At the bar stood an American who bought us all a round of whiskey, we&#8217;ll call him Gill.  He was in town visiting his girlfriend, but alas her grandfather had died that very day and it turns out that her father hates him so here he was at the bar.  He was a young dude, certainly not a bad looking guy and soon one drunk girl started sashaying her way up to the bar and she grabed his hand and drug him to the dance floor.  While his was gone I picked up another round of whiskey and a two coronas for Brett and me, the first corona I tasted in 10 months as of November 7 kids.  It was good, I fucking love that beer.  I miss it, you know what other beer I miss?  Red stripe, I fucking love me some red stripe.  Gill managed to shake himself lose from the girl, he didn&#8217;t seem into her.  She was a little on the fat side, and I reminded him that it is shitty to cheat on your girlfriend the same day her grandmother died, he should at least wait until tomarrow.  Gill pointed out that it was almost midnight and Brett ordered another round of whiskey.  The drunk girl grabed once again grabbed Gill&#8217;s arm and drug him out to the dance floor again and this time a tall girl stood up and started pushing the chubby girl.  It seemed to us that the tall girl was pissed at the chubby girl and wanted all the gill for herself, they pushed each other a couple of times and then the chubby girl won and off they danced.  Gill didn&#8217;t want any part of either one of them so he escaped and talked to us.  So then the girl drug me out to the dance floor and I told her quick that I have a girlfriend and wasn&#8217;t into it and sat back down.  I recomended we go to the parking lot and drink bizhou, and Brett and Gill&#8217;s eyes lit up like Vegas.</p>
<p align="left">In the parking lot we stood in a circle and passed the bottle around.  Gill said it was so cool to drink with foriegners and we agreed.  The drunk fat girl was annoyed and started pushing Gill, she demanded to know where we lived and which one of us was going to take her home for sex, right like that.  Gill told her to get lost and she stormed off.  His Chinese was perfect too, he studies Chinese in a University, he told us.  &#8221;thass what I neeed ta do two.&#8221;  I said shaking my head with utter conviction.  Taxis started collecting to pick up people letting out of the club, we started trying to get the drivers to drink with us and I remember my relief when none of them would.  We passed the bottle around for a time, I can&#8217;t remember what we talked about but we talked about something.  The last drop burned my throat and that was that, I threw the bottle across the parking lot and heard it shatter some place a million miles away from my consciousness, a good thirty meters away.  Then the fog crept in.  The next thing in my memory was Gill laying face up in the street his face placid like a charub, I don&#8217;t know how far later this was.  He didn&#8217;t want to get up, and we were trying to find his hotel, we were going on a conversation from a few hours ago when Gill off handedly told Brett that he was staying a few blocks that way.  I remember pulling on his arm and I remember him not gettin up.  He wanted to sleep there, and I told him he would be run over by a car.  Next I remember walking with his arm over my shoulder, Brett supporting his left side.  In Canada Brett was a paramedic, so it is good to have him along on such a journey.  Now that I think about it, I would say that Brett did most of the heavy lifting and I did most of the heavy dropping.  I was living proof for all Chinese teachers that boys are not always strong.  I remember singing the song &#8216;I remember Halloween&#8217; by the Misfits, I don&#8217;t know how long that went on, it couldn&#8217;t have been very pleasent for anyone else.  Gills legs started going all limp and he fell face first.  We tried to drag him up and he wouldn&#8217;t go.  We tried to reason with him, but then he started cursing me out and told me to fuck off and to leave him there.  I remember that made me mad so I yelled at him.  I remember trying my best to sound like a drill sergent and screaming at him that he may curse me but we had been trying to find his hotel for, I had to ask Brett, (who like a rock could still tell time) said it had been almost an hour and a half that we were trying to get him home.  I gave him a swift kick in the side, after all the man was clearly down, what better time?  And Brett ran off around the corner and I sat on the sidewalk next to where he Gill was laying and we talked about our Chinese girlfriends and how sweet they were and how much we missed them and how happy they made us and we smiled.  Then Brett came back, having found a hotel that claimed to have a foriegner guest registered.  Brett grabed Gill&#8217;s shoulders and I grabbed his legs and we started carring him that way, which he hated.  He protested and I remember screaming something in his face to the effect of &#8220;than stand on your own two feet and walk like a man!&#8221; Just like Full Metal Jacket.  I was as drunk as he was mind you, but at least I could walk.  And we still carried his arms over our shouldiers but it worked and he got up and the people in the hotel walked us to his room and we put him down and took off his shoes and Brett the man had the presance of mind to ask them to check up on him every hour.  He also thought to get us bottles of water and we stayed up drinking two bottles each.  Gill emailed me today, he seemed very sheepish and embarrased about the whole thing.  I told him we&#8217;ve all been there and he should just relax.  He also asked if we could all get together around Christmas, and I told him that sounded fine. </p>
<p align="center"><strong>IV</strong></p>
<p align="left">The next day, Brett was mad hung over and I was more or less ok.  This was strange as I have witness Brett drinking a lot more than we had the night before and I have always seen him come back grinning, on top of that I don&#8217;t think he had nearly as much Bizhou as Gill and me.  He looked like hell itself, and he said he felt much worse, subsequently we were off to a slow start that morning which was cool.  Another problem was my throat had gone from bad to worse, it felt like I had ripped a huge hole in the inside of my neck and when I tried to talk I had a growling whisper like Miles Davis.  I turned on the TV while I waited and found some totally rad looking Chinese sci-fi show with dudes in space suits flying around and landing on a moon like planet with a cool rocket ship.  They were exploring the planet cautiously with scientific devices and laser guns drawn when Shannon showed up with really sweet hamburgers from the local fastfood place called best food, the logo for which was a smiling monkey with some kind of wierd tribal war paint on his face.  But that was such a good fast food burger, rememinded me almost of burger king but better, and the fries were good and she brought sprite and asprin.  As I munched my awesome burger, the astronuaghts found a deep hole in the planet, something in the hole made their scientific devices go all crazy.  Then a giant monster jumped out of the hole, they started zapping it with their lasers.  Brett came emerged from the Bathroom groaning.  Karen was up at this point too, and we talked about what we were going to do first that day.  Then Ultraman jumped out of nowhere and started battling the giant monster to save the Chinese cosmonaughts, I was all &#8220;Ultraman, awesome!&#8221; Then Shannon told me Ultraman was gay.  That was just crazy I told her, she kept saying he was gay though, just to get my goat.  Anyway by the time the monster had died so had my hangover, Brett wasn&#8217;t looking so hot though, and as the day went on Brett looked worse and the pain in my throat started getting better but not by much.</p>
<p align="left">Both places we went that day were the same places I have already written about in the third blog I wrote here in the adventure, “one item one should never find one’s self for want of when paying a visit to the docter in Zhengzhou”, so I won&#8217;t get to into it.  Also, I think if you look in the comments after that blog Carson left a couple of links of sites where you can check out the pictures for yourself, which I recomend you do.  I will say that this was the big flower festival and it was totally wonderful.  Everything was covered in chrasathimums of every shape and color, bees going ape shit, this is their Christmas.  In the middle of the walkway (surrounded by two large lakes) which takes you to the palace was a dragon with gold flowers for skin, mind bending gardens on either side.  It was so great.  When we went to the Temple it was even better, and at first I was worried that it was so crowded it couldn&#8217;t be as great as the first time I was there, but I was happily surprised.  I felt the same calm and peace as before, and now there were wonderous flowers everywhere.  I prayed to the Buddas for Jane&#8217;s happiness, I was still a bit worried about her cryptic email from a few days ago.  And I bought a Mao Ze Dong Show globe with gold glitter.  Along the bottom were fake American pennies, and on top of everything else, I bought this thing at a Buddist temple, from a Monk! </p>
<p align="left">We took the train home at 6 that night and we were all tired.  Brett had actually gotten worse which told us that it was more than a hang over.  Hang overs tend to go away, not increase with time.  I talked to him today and he still has a cold, he figures that his body could have beaten it if he wasn&#8217;t tearing around drinking beer/whiskey/bizhou all night.  On the train ride home we both slept in our seats. </p>
<p align="center"><strong>V</strong></p>
<p align="left">That night when I got home I tried to email Jane, she text messaged me.</p>
<p align="center">I got dumped.</p>
<p align="left">It&#8217;s ok though.  I have been increasingly worried that it would hurt to go back to America and I was afraid of doing that to her, now I don&#8217;t have to worry as much.  Her rational was that were are too different, I think she never really figured out what to make of me.  She said it brought her too much pressure, and I understand.  I am fine, really, honest. a little sad, actually a little relieved.  I am sure that she still has feelings for me and I still do for her, we have talked a lot since, and I am doing my best to make sure she is ok with everything, She has been crying a lot and I have been comforting her about it which I am still glad to do.  But I had a good time dating her, she was a sweet girl, maybe the sweetest and most honestly sincerly kind and sweet human being I have ever known.  Pure sunshine, and now its gone,&#8230; sigh.  Thats all I have to say about that. </p>
<p align="left">And yeah, I am still staying in China for another six months.  I am sorry blog believers, good friends.  I love all of you so much and I am coming home sooner or later, now I must beg for your patience.  Nothing is in America that will not be there for me come September or next November.  I know that all my good friends will be there, I know your love will be there then as I feel it from you now.  But don&#8217;t give up on me, good friends.  I will see you before you know it, so keep calling and keep emailing.   </p>
<p align="center"><strong>VI</strong></p>
<p align="left">Funny thing about the next morning, last Sunday, I woke up in screaming pain.  Well, I guess its not really funny ha ha.  I couldn&#8217;t talk, instead I was making a wierd squelling noise.  So I went and waited outside May&#8217;s class for her and asked her (via notepad) to take me to the hospital, damn I was in so much pain.  We went to the main hospital and waited endlessly.  I taught May how to play hangman, which was fun.  The doctor looked in my throat finally and a few seconds later I was pushed back out the door.  I was to take a pile of pills which were so expensive, although the doctor visit itself costed $0.38 American.  It was 1 in the afternoon before I could whisper without it hurting.</p>
<p align="left">Next we had to go to another clinic where I would get the penicilin IV drip.  The clinic was a small shopfront near my school which I pass by all the time and have never really looked at.  The front out side is lined with people sitting on the ground with tubes hanging out of their arms leading to IV jars hanging from hooks in the wall or tree branches.  We stepped inside the clinic just in time to witness a baby shitting bright orange chunky liquid all over the floor.  He mother held her and people stood around watching, many of whom had IVs haning out of one arm, the other arm holding their own IV pouch above their shoulder level.  The room was small and dark and packed.  Dingy.  Everyone was waiting around in pergatory.  In one corner a frail old woman layed in a stretcher with an IV, and her Frail old husband sat next to her holding her hand, they both looked so sad and so worried, so unable to fight what ever was happening to her.  In the center of the room behind a cluttered destk sat the doctor, a stout fellow who smoked with one hand and picked his nose with the other punctuated with what quickly seemed to be compolsive spitting in the same spot on the floor. I stood there taking in the scene for a while, then the doc glances in my mouth for a 10th of a second at best and decides that penicilin isn&#8217;t the right thing, how about this other medicine that none of us can tell you about, wouldn&#8217;t you rather let us pump that through your body an hour a day for the next three days?  Doesn&#8217;t that sound like a good thing?  What if I tell you that the other medicine is much cheaper?  How about it?  I walked.</p>
<p align="left">So me and May went to a third hospital, an out of the way clean hospital.  And I argued for the longest time that they wear gloves when they stick me, and I wanted to see the needle come out of the package.  This made them crazy mad, and so they all laughed and discused how stupid I am.  Nobody ever got AIDS from a hospital, they reasoned.  They also argued that their medical skills were not enough if they used rubber gloves.  May said that they don&#8217;t use gloves on every patient in American.  Yes, they do May.  Well, if they use the same glove all day than it will become dirty and contaminated.  Well, they put on new gloves with each new patient.  This news was a stunning blow for everyone in the room.  Finally they did put on gloves, the gloves were a little on the big side, but still rubber gloves.  And for the last three days I have sat in a chair for an hour each morning waiting for the juice to flow through my body.  I have been reading the books that Carson sent me, he sent me a ton of books, ya&#8217;ll.  Maybe 20 books!  Amazing!</p>
<p align="left">And today was the last time I had to go, they had run out of the other gloves so they used giant cafeteria lady gloves, the kind that would be too big for Andre the Giant.  It was like the key stone cops trying to stick something sharp into my body.  They did it though.  And even though I didn&#8217;t make them happy they did it smiling, I know they still think I am crazy, but lots of folks think that. </p>
<p align="left">And I have had no classes this week to save my voice, which is steadily healing, thankyou.  And I promise to try to take better care of my voice, I have ways of making the kids quiet down without yelling, sometimes I get so into it with the class that I forget myself.  And yesterday I spent 11 hours and the past 4 today writting what you just read, thank you very very much for reading it, and thankyou very very much for being my friend. </p>
<p align="left"> </p>
<p align="left">Love,  </p>
<p align="left">W.</p>
<p align="center"><strong /></p>
<p align="center"><strong /></p>
<p align="center"><strong>HAPPY BIRTHDAY AMY BUGG!!!</strong></p>
<p align="center"><strong /></p>
<p align="center"><em>Footnote:</em></p>
<p><em>*Just now as I was writting this I whipped out the text book for age five students that the school gave me.  I haven&#8217;t looked at it as I tend to come up with my own stuff, mostly games and songs in English for kids that age.  And I am now looking at Lesson 25.  Lesson 25 shows a picture of a boy punting a soccar ball into a net.  Next to the picture is a drawing of a girl asking the age old question &#8216;what can a boy do?&#8217;  in bold we have our answer &#8216;<strong>A BOY CAN PLAY SOCCAR</strong>&#8216;  next to the other picture in Lesson 25 a drawing of a boy asks What can a girl do?  <strong>THE GIRL CAN DANCE</strong> to go along with the picture of the girl dancing with two fans in a pretty flower garden.   <strong>  </strong></em></p>
<p><em />
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?feed=rss2&amp;p=53</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dalian my wayward son, there&#8217;ll be piece when you go home.</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=50</link>
		<comments>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=50#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2007 15:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will</dc:creator>
		
		<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=50</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi, I&#8217;m the will sanders blog, remember me? I am long winded and often mispelled and have been MIA for a long time now. Sorry about that. Here is a comment I just got on myspace from Amy Bugg who is frankly sick and tired and will have no more of it.
&#8220;Will, I&#8217;m becoming a [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, I&#8217;m the will sanders blog, remember me? I am long winded and often mispelled and have been MIA for a long time now. Sorry about that. Here is a comment I just got on myspace from Amy Bugg who is frankly sick and tired and will have no more of it.</p>
<p>&#8220;Will, I&#8217;m becoming a blog-un-believer. Sure, we talk on the phone, but it&#8217;s just not the same! When will I get the witty, yet insightful story of your trip to visit Jane in the city where you&#8217;re not a big, white, western freak? &#8221;</p>
<p>&#8212;-Amy Bugg&#8212;-</p>
<p>Here is your answer Amy Bugg, right now. But I don&#8217;t know if its gonna be insightful, I will instead aim at 75% spelling good. I guess I will also have to work on the grammer.</p>
<p>First of all I want to start by posting up an email I wrote to Marcus. I almost hesitate to do so as it sort of recovers already discussed ground here at the willsanderschinaadventure, but I found myself in a train situation which was actually a bit worse than the bad time I told all a yall about earlier. And it is a lazy way for me to tell everyone about my ride to Yantai without actually having to do anything more complicated that copy and paste. Lazy me. Here it is, I gotta go to the bathroom.</p>
<p>Hey Marcus hositgoin?<br />
I did again, I got on a train with no bed, just standing room. It is amazing how people pack in those trains. The majority of them are unable to sit because their isn&#8217;t enough room for their legs on the floor. I won&#8217;t even get into the toilet. It was a major deal to make it maybe 10 feet through the wall to wall humans cruched in upright cannon balls on the floor and wedged in with less regard or consideration then their luggage. What really got on my nerves was when the 22 year old kids in the National railroad uniforms came through they hollered for everyone to get up, no polite excuse me, but the people saw the uniform and jumped from where they were and climbed on top of each other to give for these important vangaurds of dangerously overbooked dirty public transport.<br />
It was sposed to be 10 hours and wound up being 13. I thought ahead this time and broght a tiny fold stool, but got stuck sitting in the doorway. I had to get up every 2 minutes or so to let strangers climb over my entire body and shove me in the process, which lasted for the first 5 hours of my journey (give or take, maybe 4 maybe 6). Finally a dude wanted to give me his seat as he wasn&#8217;t going that far and I think he felt sorry for me. Near my seat a mom and a dad held vigile over their small daughter sleeping on the floor. I watched that man stand with one foot on either side of her small body for at least 7 hours, again give or take. He was making damn sure everyone who tried to climb through there could see where she was laying on the floor, and his wife sat indian style on the floor craddling her head. And I was supposed to get into town at 9 and it was more like 12, and I still havent slept a great deal, and I am hungry, but my plan is to wait till diner, find a cool place to eat, eat, then go to my super 8 hotel and pass the hell out. Tommarow I will go to Dalian and find my sweet jane, and I will stay there for a few days with her. Then we are off to Qingdao for october feast which means BEER!!!!!<br />
I have also heard they have a good sushi place in dalian, I can&#8217;t believe I miss sushi.<br />
I&#8217;ve been thinking about T Rex alot lately. Sometimes I look them up on youtube and watch them sing. You have that record, the slider. It is so good. It has a groove that makes your soul quake in its wake like a disco in your asshole. I really miss that music.<br />
As I am sure you can tell I am slightly sleep deprived and killing time at the internet bar.<br />
My sister is all scheduled to spew forth progeny tomarow! Ming Tian! I am so happy. This internet bar has roaches. Not the big outside kind but the little ghetto nasty in the sink kind. The worst! I hate them!<br />
How is your wife?<br />
w<br />
ps last night I started in Shangqiu in the Henan province then the train went north to Tai Shan and then turned east to Yantai all the way on the ocean. I must take a boat to Dalian, that damn boat will take 6 hours. I love to travel but damn if you don&#8217;t have to wait around whole days and nights twiddling your thumbs on occasion. anyway. I am pretty tired. it is now 4 and I really haven&#8217;t slept a lot.<br />
tell everyone I said hello, ni hou<br />
I love you<br />
w<br />
ps how are the (Dick-George Tenn Tom, playing in a theater near you) screenings going?<br />
please send my regards<br />
w<br />
The only thing I want to add is that the whole night I kept looking up at the sign on the wall which said the Maximum occupancy was 150, laughable!<br />
So that was what I was feeling in Yantai, I have since learned that they don&#8217;t give Shangqiu many beds to sell as it is such a piss ant little one horse place, and this was national holiday, I souldve mentioned that too. October 1st 1949 was when the Ancient Chinese empirial system officially made way for the Peoples Republic of China, and in stepped Mao. This is a rather big holiday week in China, hence my difficulty in procuring a train ticket.<br />
So thats where I was, Yantai, tired, hungry, my brain still adapting to no longer being one of many human BBs packed together in a speeding rattling shotgun shell, unshowerered with still the same pair of drawers on me, forelorn and trying to remember how much of an adventure it all was. Sometimes the glass is half empty though. And that was Yantai.<br />
After I got off the train I marched past the wall of taxis and headed to where I suspected the waterfront might be. I followed the signs and became quite lost, but found a few kind souls to laugh and point me in the right direction. The first ticket I bought at the ferry terminal was for that night at 8, which would put me getting into Dalian at around 2 or 3 AM. I didn&#8217;t realize that was the time when I was buying the ticket, they were speaking Chinese and I got my numbers in my head all screwie. So I went back and pleaded and begged and they switched it to sometime tomarrow, putting me in Yantai overnight. I was so happy until I realized that the ticket was for tomarrow at 8 PM which was the same problem a day later. So a third time I returned to the window, my self respect shot all to shit. This time I made sure to specify tomarrow morning (mingtian zaoshang) and this one was for 8 AM, problem solved. I then went to the first hotel I could find, the super 8 across the street and I checked in. It was a bit more expensive than I wanted, hell I wanted a hostel with a bunk bed, maybe a few folks to sink a beer with, but I find that there is something about spending a night in a dangerously packed hot box with hundreds of people you can&#8217;t really talk to (not in a meaningful way, not yet) that makes one less pickey. That shower felt good though lemmie tell you.<br />
Yantai is a dull place, I wasn&#8217;t there long but I got the feeling that everyone going there was trying to get on a boat going someplace else.<br />
The next morning I checked out and headed for the ferry which would take me to Dalian. A little geography for my fellow Americans, Dalian is on the south tip of a pennensula that hangs into the ocean into a large bay formed by North Korea on the east and China to the West. The China side is very near Beijing, near for China anyway. It is a city with mountains and beaches, I understand it is like Hawaii for Russians as it is one of the closest beach destinations for them.<br />
Last week I was talking to Jane on the phone. She told me that the foriegn teacher at her school in Dalian was from America, in the South, maybe very close to my city, Atlanta. I pressed to find out where, and a couple of days later she called back and told me Denver Colorado, which I suppose is closer to Atlanta than, say, China. So if you don&#8217;t know where Dalian is on a map you shouldn&#8217;t feel too bad. Its cool.<br />
The first thing I noticed when we entered Dalian harbor were the United States military ships, it looked a bit like North Korean operation overlord hanging around waiting on the go code. The next thing I noticed were the majestic mountainous islands springing from the sea. It looks like a dream city on the beach, surrounded by mountains. It reminded me of Hong Kong Harbor but somehow less impossing and scary and more friendly and quiet, and much smaller.<br />
I had the name of Jane&#8217;s college written in Chinese printed off an email, and I began showing it to the taxi men who were barking for customers at the ferry landing. Each one took a look at my paper and turned and walked away as if I wasn&#8217;t even there. This happened 3 or 4 times. I have a short temper and it was starting to piss me off, so I split.<br />
So here I am once again wondering aimlessly in a strange city in China with no clue which way to go.<br />
I first tried to ask a bus driver how to get there but he couldn&#8217;t even tell me. Then a lady who could see I was having trouble speaking Chinese tried to write something for me, in Chinese. I guess she thought maybe I couldn&#8217;t talk but could read chinese charactors. I thanked her for trying and left. wondering, wondering, wondering. I found a taxi stand several blocks away and waited. Waited, waited. Finally a taxi came and I showed the driver my little piece of paper, he took one look at it and drove away without saying anything. I was starting to see a pattern.<br />
Now after wandering aimlessly and trying taxis and the random bus I started trying to use a phone. I have no cell phone, a fact I find liberating and joyful, not having some blasted noisey ringing contraption rattling in my pocket all the damn time, so I had to rely on the public phone. In China you have to find a special place that will sell you a special card to use the street phones, so I started poking around at shops to see if they had the damn things. I had my bag on and I had been walking for a while. I started feeling lost and the light at the end of the tunnel was sweet Jane, my way cool chick. I started having the proclaimers song &#8220;I would walk 500 miles&#8221; running through my head.<br />
So I bought a phone card, only to find out that it was a cell phone card which to me was useless and worse, expensive and useless. It took a long time but I was able to find another shop with the right card. I was now 2 hours late and it was getting to be supper time, Jane would be worried, that started nagging at me.<br />
So I was armed with the right card, only to find out that most of the public phones (as is so often the case in the US as well) were busted.<br />
I would walk 500 miles<br />
Finally I found one that worked, heres the rub. In China you always have to change a bunch of stuff about the number depending on where you happen to be. I have first hand witnessed many Chinese people trying to dail the same number just to have it not work. What if you put in a zero? One may offer, or a zero plus the area code. The area code is sometimes 3 digits, sometimes 2. I don&#8217;t know. I would like to think there is a system that escapes me but damned if I know what it is. I just know that I tried the number every way I could think of and it wouldn&#8217;t work. And it was a local call, it should have been easy, but I was at it for ever. Going on three hours.<br />
And I would walk 500 more<br />
So some kids came up and wanted to practice their english and I told them where I wanted to go and they confirmed my theory that Janes college is a really long way from the University which is they taxis didn&#8217;t even want to fool with my laowei (foriegner, often but not always a slur) ass. These kids walked me to the right bus stop and after confiring with each other for a long time and then asked a few other people hanging out everyone agreed on the 3 buses I should take to get there. 3! The first bus took me for about 10 minutes and the driver informed me that my next bus, the number 19 stop was over there somewhere, he pointed vaguely over his shouldier and in some direction and I was off. I was at the side of a very large square and I didn&#8217;t see any stop for the 19. But in the traffic I did see a 19 bus go by without stopping. So I ran in that direction. Then a few minutes later another. Finally, (after quite a long walk chasing buses) I found the stop and waited, only to be told by the driver that I wanted the 109A. I found the 109A and took it, for almost an hour to the college. Actually the last stupid thing I did in a day of stupid things was to miss my stop and wind up at the depot and have to go on another bus going that way, but luckily her college was near there anyway. It was going on four hours when I started wandering around on her campus, 20 more minutes before I said the hell with that, and another 20 minutes for me to walk to a phone that finally worked, it rang and a very sad little voice answered. She was so worried. ten minutes later I met her at the front gate of her school.<br />
To be the man who walked 1000 miles to fall down at your door.<br />
odalota<br />
odalota<br />
odalota<br />
odalota<br />
yodelodel yodelodel yeay<br />
Here comes the punchline. I just now, this minute, two weeks later, called Jane to ask her what she remembers from that day. We were talking and we realized that she had actually expected me to come in at 3 AM the night before. I had called her from the hotel in Yantai and told her the story about buying the wrong ticket for the boat and she misunderstood. The poor old thing had been waiting on me all day and here it was 7 at night, she was worried sick. I feel like a real shit heal, and I honestly didn&#8217;t know that until the phone conversation I just had. Thats the trouble with dating someone who&#8217;s second language is english, especially when your chinese sucks as bad as mine does, and I suck at Chinese. Wo chong wen bu hao.<br />
At any rate.<br />
It was a happy reunion. We had been dating briefly in Shangqiu and then she went off to school, and I went off to South east Asia for 2 months. I guess I&#8217;m going to have to write about that sooner or later too.<br />
We spent the next hour trying to find our hotel, which she had gotten for us. The hotel wound up being next to a whole strip of barber shop/whore houses. Here is an interesting tidbit, apparently a barber shop in China with a purple light in the window means whore house.<br />
Anyway, our hotel wound up not being too bad, despite its being surrounded by houses of ill repute. The room was set up to look like a fancy office of a buisness man with a huge thick dark mahogany table and an oak bookshelf which displayed tiny golden statues meant to look like phoney awards and prizes, although really they were little more than heavy nick nacks. The bathroom down the hall only had hot water from 8 to 9 pm which was sort of a drag the next morning, but all in all a great place, big TV, hard wood floors.<br />
So that first morning we set out for the beach which was right near our hotel in the whore district. We walked along the beach hand in hand to a fair, which came complete with rides, giant fake dinosuars, and stalls which were cooking up squid and fish shish kabob, just in time for breakfast. I tried my luck at an air rifle stall, shooting baloons. They told me it was only 2 RMB and I poped 19 out of 20 baloons, pow pow pow. I supposed at the time that surly I was the greatest marksman of all time and had missed my calling as an international sniper assasin for hire, deadly with a BB gun. I then learned that it was 2 RMB per BB and that I had just thrown more money into this endevour than I would for lunch that day. total scam and rip off and the first really stupid thing I did that day, but the day was young. The good news was I had won a stuffed penguin and dolphin for Jane.<br />
Then I discovered that she had never even seen a farris wheel, so we went up. From the top we had a great view of Dalian, the from the tall mountains to the buildings to the shimmering sea.<br />
Then we headed for breakfast at a little place that had dumplings, no squid for breakfast I said. I put my foot down.<br />
The aquarium was way too expensive so we hitched a cab for the museum. I think that Dalian has many such places, the one the cabbie took us to wound up being the natural history and ocean museum. It was so cool! It had big fake whales and a whole whale skeleton, and it had all sorts of cool stuff about sharks. And it had tons and tons of really cool looking fish floating upsidedown in jars which was creepy. The basement was full of cool fake dinosuars. They also had the dead body of a woman who had died 250 years ago and been frozen, it really creeped out Jane, I thought it was cool.<br />
Then we walked for a while and found our hotel.<br />
For diner Jane said we should have snake, the dish Dalian was famous for. I said first I wanted a sandwich and then snake, as I was hungry and Dalian has stuff like sandwiches. So we went to a subway, which was so awesome and I had tuna fish the first tuna fish in 10 months, thrilling! We then went looking for snake.<br />
Across a busy street lead to a narrow alleyway jam packed with stalls on either side. Smoke bellowed the scent of barbeque meat of every concievable animal amid screams from barkers hungry for buisness. Fruit, produce, and noodles too, soups and cookies, but mainly meat on a stick, I wondered how long it would take to hit upon the saught after snake. Jane started buying babequed squid on a stick, followed by babaqued chicken head on a stick, but still no snake. After she picked up what I guess was pork I asked Jane about it and she laughed, she had been trying to say &#8217;snack&#8217; but it came out &#8217;snake&#8217;. Snack was a literal translation of the word for such barbequed delights. So no snake, just barbequed squid and chicken heads, which made me a triffle upset with myself that I had eaten first and not saved room.<br />
The next day was pissing rain. We went to a large square, wandered around for a bit and got rained on. We then went to the ferry to buy tickets back, then to the train station in hopes of buying a ticket leaving Qingdao so I wouldn&#8217;t get stuck in cattle class again on my way home. Of coarse you can&#8217;t do that, not in Dalian. For some reason you can&#8217;t buy a ticket for any city but the one you are in and even then only five days in advance. This makes next to no damn sense for a country as dependant on trains as China, but I do not aim to get started on that rant presently. I&#8217;ll just say that I couldn&#8217;t buy a ticket and that made me say &#8220;grrrrrrr&#8221; and &#8220;grumble grumble&#8221;. Then we went shoping in an underground Korean mall, which to me feel a bit confined and claustrophobic, but it was interesting. Jane found a small comb she liked with a traditional dress Chinese lady as the handle so I bought it for her which made her happy. We took photos in a photo booth, and wandered around. I looked around for a baby present for my sister, see, that was the week my niece was due, Emma. And I was so excited, I was checking my email the way Rainman checks on the peoples court in hopes that there would be news, but on that day no news so far, also no good stuff for babies in the underground Korean mall. Then we went to a foriegn language bookstore and I picked up a collection of Hemingway stories. Most foriegn language book stores are aimed at kids trying to learn english so their selection is pretty much the list of things I blew off reading in highschool, but I&#8217;ve always liked Hemingway.<br />
Outside the bookstore I suggested pizza for diner, trying to get my fix. Jane had never had pizza, can you believe that? so we went to a pizzahut nearby, which in china actually passes for a fancy sitdown piano in the corner kind of joint. They had a waiting list, I scoffed. Right next door almost we found an American cafe that had pizza, not crappy oily pizzahut pizza either, this was like pizza from a dream. I was dazzled by the way the cheese stretched from the slice to my mouth, I had almost forgotten that good pizza is supposed to do that. We got a medium peporoni and one hawaian. So as it turns Jane does not really like pizza, its too strange for her, I have been in China long enough to sympathize.<br />
The plan for the next day was six hours to Yantai by boat, then maybe four or five more by bus to Qingdao, an all day affair.<br />
A little while ago when I talked to Jane I told her I was writting this post. In addition to the realization that she was waiting for me all day in Dalian, she also told me that I had to include the lady on the boat to Yantai, I promised that I would. Hell, no way I would have left her out anyway.<br />
Now I was the only westerner on that boat, it was clear and obvious, and many folks were starring, I am used to that. To make matters worse, there I was with this amazing beautiful thing from China. Prettiest girl in China as far as I can tell, so we were getting it good, but like I said I am used to it, it isn&#8217;t even a thing anymore, honest. That&#8217;s just my life. When I go home I will have to seriously adjust to not being starred at. So Jane and I sat along the wall and she practiced her english with me, I had her read me the short story &#8216;the killers&#8217; by Hemingway which they based the Burt Lancastor movie on. Hemingway is good for teaching, his language is understandable, but usually with a deeper meaning. Eventually people lost interest in Jane and I, but we both noticed that a woman accross the room was still starring at us, and had been for some time. She was obese and wore her hair pulled back in a tight bun. She had an evil frown, and she was giving us a chilly evil eye. What I do when in this situation (as I am in this situation often) is I smile and wave at the person. This usually tends to embarrass the person into realizing that they are starring in a nonagressive way, and usually they wave and laugh at themselves just a little and leave me alone, I laugh too, with a kind smile, and everything is cool. I waved at this lady and for a second she didn&#8217;t move, so I waved and said hello (ni hou) and she smilled and waved back, but then she frowned again and kept starring with the evil eye, and the evil frown. So we went back to Hemingway for a while, picking each sentence apart. When she finished the story I kept reading to myself and she did the same from her book. Every once in a while I looked up and she hadn&#8217;t moved, she still sat in the same chair with the same demonic stare. I sketched a picure of her and showed it to Jane and we both laughed. I suggested we move to sit on the deck outside, which we did. We sat and watched the ocean go by for maybe an hour, maybe less. We saw giant caps of jellyfish all over the place just under the surface, it was so amazing. When we went back inside and sat down the evil eyed lady stood up and walked over. She was now standing right behind our chairs starring, this was getting wierd. I gave the lady a look and she went and sat down again, but she kept looking. For a while I pretended to take pictures of Jane but was actually aiming the camera past Jane&#8217;s shouldier to get a shot of the lady but I couldn&#8217;t get her in focus. Finally Jane decided the lady was suffering from some kind of mental problems, which made sense to me, we just ignored her for the rest of the trip. But as when we arrived she walked over and said to me &#8220;I&#8217;m leaving&#8221; (zou le) to me. I nodded and smiled. Later Jane was laughing at me about it.<br />
In Yantai we stopped for lunch and had them box it up for the bus ride. On the bus, the mean lady made us throw out our lunch and told me I wasn&#8217;t allowed to take off my shoes for a five hour ride, even though I had wet socks and shoes from the rain. I got all mad about it, Jane thought I was being silly. So I calmed down. I did take my feet out of the shoe and and kept just the toes in the shoe iteslf and rode that way in full view of the driver, just to be an ass. Jane thought this was very silly too.<br />
Flash back time here at the willsanderschinaadventure, going into the time machine, that means its time for the time machine sound<br />
SSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSSHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHWWWWWWWWWWWAP!<br />
That is how my time machine sounds.<br />
A week before I left for this trip a dude at the Shangqiu college warned me that it would be jam packed in Qingdao and to get my hotel booked on the internet as soon as I could, national holiday don&#8217;t cha know. I agreed and after a few more days of lazy pointless procratanation I was on the job. It took a full day of surfing the internet but I finally found one hotel that wasn&#8217;t too expensive and booked it. This was one thing less to worry about, which made me happy.<br />
So we got to Qingdao and the sun was already down. Jane called the number the hotel had emailed me and was discussing price and that sort of thing. Then she asked for directions and thats when the fun began. The sneaky so and sos had said Qingdao on thier websight but had failed to mention that they meant the Qingdao region not city, and they were actually 2 hours away by bus from the city of Qingdao. This was alarming news for me indeed as I had already called them twice (once by myself and then again once with May speaking) to ensure and reesure that I had a spot there. The sneaky guys, they were so sneaky, oh so sneaky, it made me mad.<br />
And here we were, in Qingdao, which is in the top 10 places for tourists to go in China if it isn&#8217;t on the top 5, in National holiday, with no fucking hotel, tired from travelling all day, night time already. An adventure I tensly assured Jane through grit teeth.<br />
First we tried the old lets try this random bus and see what happens method, always a stupid idea, always seems good at the time. It wound up dumping us a scary alley way with no light or hope for survival. As we were getting on the bus Jane&#8217;s face bumped into my backpack and I hit her in the eye with the wood footstool I had straped on the back of my bag for the train, so now we were lost hopelessly, no hotel, and I had given my girlfriend a shinner.<br />
So we got on another bus at someones advice, and Jane struck up a conversation with a girl who told us where to go, first we went past the big bar street which was clogged with thousands and thousands of people, it was an endless sea of heads, now I was getting really tense about finding a place to lay our heads. We got off the bus in a huge square where the other passenger had told us and immediatly we could see that these were the five star posh hotels that we could never even think about affording. We even ducked into a place that had only one vacancy left, which costed 800 RMB a night. Trust me that is even a lot of money in America. Jane was so cool the whole time, she kept saying not to worry, we could always just sleep on the beach. I believe she would have too.<br />
Outside the hotel a dude came and started fast talking us, with much trepidation we climbed into his car, off to a hotel. The way it works is they usually get a slightly higher price than usuall and you are paying extra for his comishion, so our room was 120 RMb the first night instead of the 110 we paid the rest of the time, which was fine. The room was ok too, it had 3 beds and we pushed 2 together. The problem with that room was the mosquitos. It had sqwished mosquitos all over the wall and when I woke up I had like 10 bites.<br />
I hate them.<br />
Qingdao is a beautiful city. It was owned by the Germans for one hundred years, until recently I think and it has German architecture everywhere. It is also where they make Tsingtao beer, sort of like the budwieser of China but a little better. You can get it in the states.<br />
So the next day was spent wandering the streets of Qingdao. First we went to a huge catholic church which sits atop a hill overlooking the city. It was quite impressive and Jane had never been in a church before. We looked at the statues and the plate glass windows and I found myself explaining what little I could remember from whenever it was I learned all that stuff about Jesus and mary and Joseph and all that. The atmosphere in there was interesting too, it has sort of been converted into a museum of catholicism for gleeful noisy Chinese who were taking tons of flash pictures of the confessional and the pews and whatnot. I tried to explain what it was like for me going to a mass for a catholic friend whenever they die or get married. Jane seemed to think it was cool so we stayed there for a while. Watching her looking around wide eyed reminded me of the first Buddist temples I went to here in China. It seems that there is a power that resonates from a place like that, an ancient temple or Church. Just like a rocknroll club has a mystic vibe of something that you can close your eyes and recognize but not touch, when I was a kid I would find it at comic book stores. Like the lingering antiseptic funk of a hospital, or the misery that floats around anywhere near a jail or funeral parlor. I was recently at one of the killing fields in Cambodia, and the second I walked into a cave, with no knowledge that this was where the Khmer Rouge had done so many bad bad bad things I knew it, I swear the air was different. I stood there all alone and I knew that something must have happened there. Later when I left the mountain a Cambodian kid told me that sure enough that was the spot. It was something far feeling beyond sight/sound/touch/taste stuff. I am not sure where this came from but I honestly feel that some holy sacred places carry something and even least sentient beings are atuned to. Its a force which demands to be recognized. This Church had that power for Jane, I have been in Catholic churches before so it didn&#8217;t get to me so much, but I could see it on her face. Her face is all purdy.<br />
We kept wandering the streets her hanging onto my arm, cobblestone winding up and down hills, you would swear an oath that you were in Europe if you didn&#8217;t know any better.<br />
The next order of buisness as far as I was concerned was to find Jane a pretty bathing suite and to go swimming. Jane had not only never been to the beach, she can&#8217;t swim. So my plan was to find a pretty bathing suite for Jane and to teach her to swim. Well we looked and looked and didn&#8217;t see a bathing suite, pretty or otherwise. I was getting sort of bummed about the whole thing when Jane suggested we just go walk on the beach for a while. We went down to where the rocks were sticking up out of the tide and took off our shoes. We went out along the rocks and Jane decided that the only thing to do would be to jump in with our clothes on. She was wearing a skirt and shirt, I was in the official willsanderschinaadventure adventure clothes, (tee shirt, jeans, ski cap), so I lost the jeans, put my wallet and keys in the backpack with my pants and went in after her in my boxers. luckily I was wearing a fairly thick pair of boxers with the flap you have to reach into, not the hole where everything hangs where it may. I am a flap man. We soon found that the sharp rocks in that area along with the undertow made for stupid idea swimming, Jane being a novice, stupid idea swimming even while sober is a very stupid idea, so we climbed out soaking wet and walked to a nearby beach. Beaches in china seldom seem to have swimmers, this one had droves of people on the shore looking out to the waves but not a single swimmer until we got there. So now maybe a hundred Chinese folks were watching with dazzled eyes and gaping jaws as I tried to teach Jane to swim in my underwear with her fully clothed, the strangest thing any of them had ever seen apparantly. I have full confidence that some of them are still telling the story and have hopes that maybe others still plan on telling that story for the rest of their lives, maybe embelishing details and adding things as the years pass, maybe not. I can always hope.<br />
Alas, I tried everything I could think of but no dice. Jane was not learning to swim that day, besides it was a little on the chilly side. Jane started getting goose bumps and shivering so we got out, and toweled off. I have will not give though, she will swim and I will help her, it will just have to be another day, thats all.<br />
We went back to the hotel and got all showered and dry and warm. Then we made an attack plan. Jane was translating the map for me and found the beer street. On the beer street was the Tsingtao brewery /slash/ museum. Attack plan found.<br />
The Tsingtao brewery costed an absolute arm and leg to get in, but what the hell, its beer. Most of it turned out to be sort of a drag too, blah blah blah a bunch of comercials for Tsingtao, blah blah blah we have the finest beer because we make it real good blah blah blah. There were then some interesting bits about the history of Qingdao and the Germans coming in, but not as much as I had hoped for. They had cool stuff about making beer early back in the day, they had the big wooden vats and kegs. one of the coolest things was the history of beer itself room, did you know they were drinking beer in Sumeria? I didn&#8217;t know that! They were according to the Tsingtoa museum, they were drinking big toasts to the evil capricious gods of &#8216;my home is flooded again please spare my children&#8217; but it was a start.<br />
Then at the end of the tour we got a pitcher FREE! Well, not so much free because it cost so much to get in in the first place, but it felt free at the time. Then we went to a beer resturant, I was really hoping to find something in a german beer, but this beer street wound up some kind of Tsingtao brewery street. So we had a big chinese meal which was good. Jane was being a good sport about me trying to get my western fix, I felt like we should be trying the local food as well. Plus I sampled many different Tsingtao beers, they actually have a dark beer thats not half bad.<br />
That night we took a bus back to the beach near our hotel. We got more beer and went out to the rocks that stuck out of the water and looked at the ancient pavillion across the water, the pavillian on the Tsingtao bottle. And we watched the waves and we talked and we laughed and it was nice. The waves started getting higher and the tide was coming in so we had to leave, before we did so I told Jane about pouring out beer for friends that have passed and we both poured out beer for my home girl Jewel who we had lost the week before,<br />
I miss you and rest easy, Jewel I wish I had called you when I still could.<br />
We escaped the tide but only just. And we went up to the board walk that lead out to the pavillian and we sent a red lanturn with a candle in the middle up to the sky, and we both wrote our wishes in marker on the side and both our wishes wound up being the others happiness, written in two different languages the same wish for each other and we watched it sail up to the night sky and shrink until it was a tiny faint red star a million miles away. And I guess we went home to the hotel after that, I guess thats what we did. And that was easily the best day of the week and it is in the running for best day in China.<br />
What did we do the next day? Oh, ok yeah. I remember now. Jane wanted to go to climb a mountain but we had to go get the tickets, one for her to go back to Dalian and one for me to go to Shangqiu. That was an all morning affair, of coarse they have 10 different places to buy bus and train and boat tickets all within a city block radius, all tucked away hidden. We went into one to ask a guy at an information counter and some dude in a phalony uniform tryed to push us back through the gate but the information guy helped us just the same. Finally we found the right place and learned we could get all the tickets there, which was cool. Jane still couldn&#8217;t go by boat from Qingdao to Dalian, she had to take the bus to Yantai. I also found out about the sleeper bus, a bus with beds. I jumped at it, I am on a train hiatus. Fuck trains.<br />
After all that we realized that the mountain was too many hours away to be feasable, so we spent the rest of the day in the hotel. That night we went to a place that had beef and lamb and pork on a stick. Jane decided she could outdrink me, I begged her not to try, but I wound up nearly carring her into a taxi less than an hour later, the poor old thing.<br />
So then the next day we got up early and went back to the bus station and said goodbye. I looked in her eyes and realized that with my contract ending in December I may never see her again, I couldn&#8217;t leave it that way. And I watched her get on the bus, and the rest of the day I conspired to find a way to see her again.<br />
So for anyone who doesn&#8217;t know already I am trying to get a job in Dalian and stay for six months after my contract here ends. I feel like I have to see this thing through.<br />
PS<br />
The sleeper bus is too short for a Chinese person and for me I spent the whole ride with my legs bent in wierd positions. It was like trying to sleep in a love seat, still better than the ride over, you understand.<br />
PPS<br />
Emma was also born that week, she is a beautiful baby and I am so so so happy! I will be the coolest uncle just wait and see!
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?feed=rss2&amp;p=50</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Car 13</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=49</link>
		<comments>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=49#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2007 15:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will</dc:creator>
		
		<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=49</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So for whatever reason this blog seemed to cut off in the end and it has taken me this long to fix it. Sorry it took so long, if you enjoy the way it ends than you should thank Amy Bugg for fussing me about it everytime she talked to me.
By midnight the toilet at [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>So for whatever reason this blog seemed to cut off in the end and it has taken me this long to fix it. Sorry it took so long, if you enjoy the way it ends than you should thank Amy Bugg for fussing me about it everytime she talked to me.</em><br />
By midnight the toilet at the south Shangqiu train station flung an oder of piss that was deafening. I sat against a pillar near the door on top of my fancy backpackers backpack. I am a white boy, which means that me and my backpack stood out in a room of a hundred Han Chinese. The station had chairs across the room but I had picked my spot for strategic reasons, I wanted my position prime for the upcoming malay of bodies rushing the door when the train shows up any minute now. In my right had was my train ticket, in my left the letter May had written for me to give to the conductor. The letter felt just like a note from mother on the first day of school, but the note was important in that it carried my hope for peace and quiet sleep this long night and long day which would follow. In Chinese it explained that I spoke very little Chinese and was going all the way to Guangzhou (the far end of the line), and could you please help me get a bed or a seat if there is an extra. See, I had bought my ticket a couple of days ago and it had sold out everything except standing room only. Standing room only would be a little bit of a drag for a two hour ride, there is always a chance you get a seat but a great chance that you don&#8217;t. It is the glimmer of hope that I find makes the whole thing so hectic. This is ok for a few hours, tolerable anyway, BUT this train leaves Shangqiu at 12:12 at night and doesn&#8217;t get to Guangzhou until 4 the next afternoon. That&#8217;s a long damn time, folks, as I understand a great deal longer than anyone else in standing room only was in for.<br />
When the train pulled in 30 people wind sprinted to the platform. I showed my letter from mother to a conductor, he scowled. He asked me in Chinese how many people and I told him just me, also in Chinese. He showed the note to another conductor. This conductor frowned. A third conductor shook his head. They led me to a door on the side of the train into the compartment between train car 9 and 10, car 9 being the classy sleeper. A man on his way into car 9 spoke a little English, just enough to translate that the conductor wanted me to wait in the compartment, which of coarse I had gathered anyway. After about 5 minutes the head conductor came told me there were no more beds or seats and I would have to go into car 10. The compartment between car 10 and 9 had a door on either side with a window. On the other side of car 10&#8217;s window was a sea of humanity packed like sardines. Souls huddled on the floor, those with children sleeping in their laps granted wider allowance, those without squished in tight, everyone else standing with both hands against the wall vainly trying to ease the weight of their feet. I could not see an unoccupied square inch for me or my back pack. I looked around the compartment between car 9 and 10. Nobody. I laid my backpack on the ground and sat laid my shoulders on top of it like a big couch pillow and folded my legs. After a few minutes the conductor opened the doors to the 2 cars to let the people in car 10 get to the john in car 9. When this happened the door to car 10 opened and latched itself perpendicular across the compartment forming a wall which isolated me in a tiny pen. The luxury suite, I decided, and I pulled a black ski cap over my head to block the yellow green fluorescence and thought about all the shitty jobs and traffic and nasty places in America that were nowhere near as cool as sleeping on the floor of a train going across China. My head rattled against the wall with the engine like leaning on the window of a yellow cheese bus back in high school. A sleeping pill helped me finally get about an hour of sleep at 3, then we got to a stop and they needed me out of the doorway so I got up and was crammed into car 10, but just for a few minutes. Soon others from car 10 were digging on my idea and gathering in the compartment, though I still had my tiny pen behind the door and I think I got 20 or 30 minutes of sleep every other hour.<br />
In the morning, maybe around 7 I had the bright idea to stretch my legs and have a look-see if maybe some seats had opened up some place. On the other end of the narrow hallway in car10 was the dining car where everyone laughed at me and my backpack. One man could speak pretty good English and I told him about my whole situation which he found surprising, he agreed that 15 hours was a crazy amount of time to do standing room. He turned and told everyone else in the dinner car, they all discussed this issue with each other over their breakfasts. We were just pulling into Wuhan which was my new English speakers stop. He told me that the consensus reached by the men and woman in the dining car was that they should give me a bed and I should go to car 13. &#8220;Car 13 you say?&#8221; Car 13&#8243; the man assured me smiling. I thanked him for his help and he got off. Wuhan is a large and major Chinese city as they go, not Beijing or Hong Kong big, but big still. I was optimistic as this would have to mean a lot of people getting off. Unable to perform simple threads of logic I didn&#8217;t see that this would also imply many new people getting on.<br />
So at the beginning and end of each car was a insurmountable clot of of people. Cars 11, 12, and 13 each had seats on either side, each bench was made to hold 2 but holding any where from 3 to 5. the floor was covered with crouched bodies, the bodies were flanked by legs of those not lucky enough to sit. I have never, ever, ever felt so claustrophobic. And I really mean that from my heart, I had to stop and reflect on my life just now, and yeah, never. The worst was the bodies standing had nowhere to go but to squeeze into more bodies sometimes. Often there was no room for my backpack behind me and I could feel the whole crowd crushing as I had to wedge my way through, and over people, saying &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry&#8221; in Chinese the whole time. Yet nobody was angry, at least they didn&#8217;t show it. If they could they would get out of my way, many stood to let me pass. I wasn&#8217;t the only one trying to get through, the whole Wuhan crowd of newbies were pulling and pushing through the maw as well.<br />
And after 30 minutes of this I made it to car 13, through car 13, and to the compartment past. In the compartment I handed my note to to a conductor, he read it and frowned like the others had. He left and after a minute he came back and pointed for me to go back in the direction I had come from. I couldn&#8217;t imagine doing that to those people again, so I found an inch to stand in with my bad on the floor upright. After some time a lady came through pushing a snack cart which took up the whole isle, forcing the sea of people to part in crushed piles of flesh and luggage, teeth gritting. I didn&#8217;t see anyone wanting to buy snacks. After an hour standing there I finally gave up and tried to make my way home, back to my little corner that only I knew just past the dining car. I took me a long time, when I finally got back to car 10 all the people smiled and laughed and waved at me. I got the feeling I was still the chief topic of breakfast conversation so my return was met with grand interest. My luxury suite had been discovered by a soldier in the Chinese army who slept in the fetal position in the little hole behind the open perpendicular door. But I found a nice spot to curl up on the floor nearby with my book. The view out the window was getting good too, the terrain had gotten hilly and green and pretty. Much different from the flat farmland all around Henan. I guess a couple of hours later the conductor came and kicked everyone out of the compartment, so I started back through the dinner, where lady handed me a hand written English note that said now there were beds free and I should ask again at car 13. This time I picked up my bag and lifted it above my head like a conoe portage. This time everyone was settled so I was waking up people sleeping on the floor, which felt terrible. This time at the end of car 13 I found a desk which had been covered with people and hidden last time, behind this desk were the conductors who could help. I gave them my note from mother and yeah, there was a bed, it was gonna cost me too. Everyone in car 13 was watching with great interest. I felt weird asking for a bed with all the others on the floor but they were all in it for a few hours, I was talking 15. I paid the extra and was lead to car 7, on the way the people in the dining car cheered when they saw me with a conductor, I had been quite a point of conversation for them. And in car 7 they took me to my bed which was occupied by an entire family. They suggested I sit in a nearby chair. I motioned to the top bed which was empty and told them in Chinese I was tired and they agreed. I still don&#8217;t know if it was one of their beds or someone elses. I do know that at 11 that day I blinked my eyes and slept until 3 in the after noon. The train got to Guangzhou at 6, two hours late. I hadn&#8217;t eaten anything all day except for a couple of peaches. But it was ok, the whole time it was ok. Sometimes it gets to a point where a former you would have thrown up you hands and said &#8220;fuck it&#8221; and given up, but getting buried alive in another culture as I have I find that you just got to sigh and smile it off to a certain extent. Sometimes its the only way. Hell, China&#8217;s just like that sometimes.<br />
So I wrote that a while ago, Fridaynight I have another standing room only ticket for Yantai, 10 hours away. From there I will go by boat to Dalian to visit Jane. I am not so worried this time, I know it will suck and I am all set for it.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?feed=rss2&amp;p=49</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Mayor of Monkey town</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=47</link>
		<comments>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=47#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2007 15:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will</dc:creator>
		
		<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=47</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I rolled into Lopburi by bus, hoped off and looked around,
monkeys.
Doug Brown had told me all about Lopburi months ago when he heard I was heading to Thailand, god knows how he knows about it.  Lopburi is a relatively smallish city which operates under the facade of being so Buddhist that they would never [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I rolled into Lopburi by bus, hoped off and looked around,</p>
<p>monkeys.</p>
<p>Doug Brown had told me all about Lopburi months ago when he heard I was heading to Thailand, god knows how he knows about it.  Lopburi is a relatively smallish city which operates under the facade of being so Buddhist that they would never do anything to stop the enormous monkey infestation.  Truth being often stranger than fiction, at some point they must have nabbed a truck load of monkeys from the jungle ages ago in hopes of building tourism, they have since breed and now you got a town with maybe a few thousand monkeys.  What a sight that must have been, a speeding truck load of rustled monkeys making a midnight run like an old moonshiner.  Every person in Lopburi carries a sling shot at all times like a dead eye gunslinger ever ready to plug a piece of ice or a peanut or pebble at any monkey what steps out of line.  Terrible and cruel?  Sure it is, but at the same time these monkeys run wild in the streets (running, running&#8230;) no natural predators, and they are fatter than any monkey ever has been.  Fearless of all manner of humans, they waddle their fat bodies into the streets where weary cars are looking for them and anticipating having to stop for several minutes honking for the monkey crossing, and they dance for tourists who through them junk food which they devour, plus regular secret feeding provided by the city.  The telephone poles and street lamps are all covered with monkeys.  The air stinks like their wet fur, many people cross the street to avoid some areas of the sidewalk to give wide birth to the monkeys, others simply whip out the sling shot on the little fuckers.  POP!<br />
No, I wouldn&#8217;t really say that the local residents of Lopburi display the spirit of smiling Buddhist tolerance.  But they do know their place, sling shots or no, this here is monkey town, and the humans knew it.  Cars waiting at traffic lights were bombarded by the rain of monkeys falling from trees like leaves in autumn.  certain areas of the city are crammed with people, others are empty because that is the monkey territory, a line which is respected.  This was monkey town, the people knew it.<br />
And the many packs of dogs that populate Lopburi seemed to know it too, they huddled in corners across from the major monkey areas, always wearing fearful skiddish expressions, always looking over their backs, often barking suddenly and running the other way.  And the monkeys knew it, they strutted with fuck off autonomy.  The only thing they had to worry about were scuffles with other monkeys, which broke out frequently between what I later learned to be the two major warring monkey clans.  The skirmishes I witnesses all seemed brief and explosive, not really about anything more than scarring the rival and establishing dominance over some small turf, the victor taking a prime street corner or choice telephone pole for him and his mates.<br />
I found a hotel with air con and CNN, which was swank.  The window had bars which served as a Simeon jungle gym which provided quite a view.  That night I had diner at a fold out table from a street vendor, I forget what I ordered.  The owner sat at my table, he wanted to know where I was from and all that and we struck up an almost non verbal conversation.  I asked him if he hated the monkeys and he said no, he loved the monkeys, and I asked if they ever were trouble and he agreed that sometimes the monkeys made a lot of trouble, his English wasn&#8217;t good enough for specifics.  I got a huge beer and he started bringing me small sample dishes and plates of Thai food, spicy vegetables, fish, super tasty curry, amazing things I had never heard of before.  I insistently refused as he was being too nice which made him laugh and bring me more.  He was a swell guy and had decided for whatever reason that I was no longer his customer but now his guest.  He was just like they say about Thai people, super nice and all huge smiles.  After about a beer and a half a sweaty fat man with no shirt and a dangling cigarette stood and switched on the TV, it was the start of a boxing which pitted one slugger from Thailand and one from Japan, serious business.  The street corner started filling with men sitting around drinking beer and discussing the fight.  This could have been any smokey bar room in any city in the world, just a bunch of guys sitting and watching a good fight.  Hell yes, and nobody seemed to care or notice the one white guy in the middle of the group, so long as I was rooting for Thailand I was in like Flynn.  So when the Thai boxer got in a good jab or unanswered combo I made sure to clap and we all stamped our feet, and it was a good fight and the longer it went the louder we got and the drunker we got.  The others lept from their seats and screamed in Thai at the television, veins bulging and eyes bugging, their friends laughing.  In the 12th our champ from Thailand delivered a devastating one, two, three which landed the Japanese fighter flat on his ass, if only for a second.  Not enough to start a count, but easily enough to get every ass out of the seat, it built and built to a raucous kerfuffle.  Then the bell rang at the end of the 12th, and for a tense moment every man there stood silent waiting for the decision.  Then the ref walked over and held to the air the glove of the man from Japan, the bad guy had won, and the fat man with no shirt stood up and turned it off.  With a few shrugs and slowly shaking lowered (but still smiling) heads filed out to the street, trying their best to walk tall, trying their best to avoid the goddamn monkeys.  Me and the owner argued about the bill, I wanted to give him more and he wouldn&#8217;t let me, he just wanted to charge me for the first dish I ordered and for the beer, which I paid, all the other food he brought me was on him he insisted, which was cool of him.<br />
Later that night I went out wandering.  I went deep into the monkey zone, it was like some lance a lot link film noir of the crazy dark city street, heavy shadows, hip looking monkeys who all knew the score looking to get theirs.<br />
In the town center surrounded by a fence is an ancient Khmer temple which served as the base for all the monkeys.  There must have been a thousand monkeys concentrated on that temple, I assume that is where they get feed.  It was late and I went to the gate and asked if I could have a look.  The guard asked for more money than the daily admission (as I am sure he wasn&#8217;t supposed to let anyone in there at night) I started to leave and then I asked him if he wanted beer, which he did.  So I ran around the corner and picked up a bunch of Thai beer and bribed my way into the monkey temple.<br />
It was darker than pitch but the walls seemed to have constant motion from the monkeys, the odd shriek and howl rang here and there, black eyes glinting in the moonlight.  The guard and I sat maybe ten feet from the monkey covered wall of the temple, some of the braver ones ventured away from the walls and sat near us and looked confused by our presence.   The guard spoke almost no English but was able to explain to me that the hundreds of monkeys crawling all over the buildings across the street surrounding the temple square were members of the enemy clan, so our monkeys where the strongest, for they held the temple.  This temple was like the Gaza strip to the monkeys of Lopburi, and the war was endless.  After a while the guard left for his little guard house by the gate and returned with a hot bowl of spicy vegetable soup, which we shared.  And we ate the soup and watched the monkeys under the stars and moon and drank beer into the night silently, everything worth saying was already understood.</p>
<p>I guess that was 2 weeks ago now, I made it through Cambodia and am now in Laos on a small island (Don Det) which has no electricity at night time.  This morning I found myself sharing a speed boat up the Mekong in Cambodia heading to the border of Laos and it occurred to me once again how happy I am.  I hope everyone else is good too.  I love all of you.<br />
w
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?feed=rss2&amp;p=47</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meanwhile&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=44</link>
		<comments>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=44#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 05:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will</dc:creator>
		
		<category>Uncategorized</category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=44</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dr. Zira: What will he find out there, doctor?
Dr. Zaius: His destiny.
 Hey good friends, blog believers, and family, your wayward prodical son just quickly checking in, if you didn&#8217;t see already I have a new post about my week in Beijing and I have new exciting WOW pictures up, more soon I think.  I will [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="left"><a href="http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/name/nm0001375/"><font color="#003399"><strong>Dr. Zira</strong></font></a><strong>: What will he find out there, doctor?<br />
</strong><a href="http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/name/nm0263052/"><font color="#003399"><strong>Dr. Zaius</strong></font></a><strong>: His destiny.</strong></p>
<p align="left"> He<font face="Times New Roman" size="3">y good friends, blog believers, and family, your wayward prodical son just quickly checking in, if you didn&#8217;t see already I have a new post about my week in Beijing and I have new exciting WOW pictures up, more soon I think.  I will try anyways.  The post is endless, I am sorry about that too.  It may take a while to sit down and read, for those of you with lots of time on your hands (in between arts and crafts and yard time at the Fulton corectional, put down the shank and give the blog a look) it maybe a good time killer.  Sometimes I got a lot to say and I don&#8217;t readers digest myself, I worry if I ever did leave anything out, maybe in a few years I will forget, which I think defeats the core purpass for writting it down in the first place.  So if you do read it let me know what you think and if it is too much of a chore than I dig that too.  Amy Bugg  and Carson said they liked it.  They are never wrong about anything.  Well, hardly ever wrong.  I am never wrong.</font></p>
<p><font face="Times New Roman" size="3">Meanwhile, I am enjoying the last week of class this semester.  This means saying goodbye to all my kids, I will miss a good 900 out of 1000 of the little Chinese ragamuffins, and although I have been here such a short while, I find myself getting a little chokey in the back of the throat when I tell them how wonderful the time teaching them has been, best thing I ever did I tell them.</font></p>
<p><font face="Times New Roman" size="3">Meanwhile, today they gave me my own water cooler.  It is the coolest!</font></p>
<p><font face="Times New Roman" size="3">Meanwhile, my mom sent me a bunch of junk food from America, I will call her before she reads this, it is almost 1 am there now, she is asleep.  She just retired a few weeks ago by the way.  I hear she is adjusting to life without work nicely.  I think that will be my calling if I ever live that far.  I hope I do.  If not, Mom I love you.</font></p>
<p><font face="Times New Roman" size="3">Meanwhile, my sister Kate is getting more and more pregnant, well, I mean to say fat.  So she says anyway.  They are up in the air because they don&#8217;t know when Adam (my brother in law) will get assigned a job in Memphis, and they arn&#8217;t allowed to switch docters mid pregnancy, so there is a good chance they will have the baby and  then have to pick up stakes and move to Memphis, or he&#8217;ll have to pick up stakes and head North and she will be birthin the baby solo.  Aparently the air trafic control game involves a slight lack of understanding to employee person needs, but he will be making a ton of money off the bat I think.  The cool thing is that I will have family in Memphis so I see a lot more Graceland in my future.  Seriously, I am heading up there to see them when I can, I love them and I love that city.  Of coarse I will have to wait until they move there and I am back states side again.</font></p>
<p align="left"><font face="Times New Roman" size="3">Meanwhile, I am planning a big trip to Thailand and Laos for next month, still trying to work out the last minute kinks and bugs that arrise in my plans, but so far, OK.  I will be going alone and will be gone for 2 months.  After going by train all the way South, I have a flight leaving Macou (next to Hong Kong) and I will land in Bangkok and will head North to trek through tribal, elephant infested hill country.  There is a place my buddy (US SGT.) Doug Brown told me about, a town called Lopburi near Bangkok where everyone is too Buddhist to hurt anything so they let the monkeys run the town.  They are fat nasty evil monkies, they collect in hordes and do mischief (as monkies do best) and people throw them junk food by the fist full just to leave them be.  I can&#8217;t wait to see evil monkey town.    Here is a good address that has pictures of the monkeys, one of which has the monkeys patrolling what apears to be human beings trapped in a cage.  <a href="http://thailandforvisitors.com/central/lopburi/monkeys/index.html">http://thailandforvisitors.com/central/lopburi/monkeys/index.html</a></font></p>
<p align="center"><font face="Times New Roman" size="3">&#8220;Take your stinking paws off me, you damned dirty ape!&#8221;</font></p>
<p><font face="Times New Roman" size="3">When I get to the Northern border I will cross into Laos and spend a few days on the Mekong floating in a raft and drinking.  In the South of Laos live a very rare, very endangered bread of river dolphins.  Good tubing I hear, too.  Then at the bottom of Laos I head West back into Thailand maybe dip into Cambodia to see Angkor Watt, then back to Bangkok and then to China.  If I have time I will head south along the Thai pennesula to dig on the beaches and do some snorkeling and drink on the beach.  I hope I have time.</font></p>
<p><font face="Times New Roman" size="3">Meanwhile, the short documentary on the subject of Richard Nixon&#8217;s one day trip to Alabama when he met George Wallace made by Carson and Marcus has been accepted into the Southern circuit film festival, it will travel a tour of 8 cities, 50/50 at this point if one of them will be Atlanta, it sounds like the festival has 2 curcuits and one swings by A-town and one does not.  If it does and I hear I will let you know.  Either way in the last post (my beijing week) is a link to the movie, give it a look I think highly of it.  Honest.</font></p>
<p><font face="Times New Roman" size="3">Meanwhile, Han Xiao Yin called me today, I will go have diner with his family, I wonder if they will serve dog again.  I hope you won&#8217;t think less of me if I sort of hope so.  I haven&#8217;t seen him in a while, he has been busy with school in Zhengzhou, I have missed my friend.  Robert Paraguasu recently emailed me about a snippet of news he had found involving a student riot in Zhengzhou, I hadn&#8217;t heard a thing about it over here, even though I am only a few short hours away from there.  Not the kind of news they report in China.  If anyone hears or sees any news of civil unrest, especially in the Henan province of China let me know.  There is a good chance Xiao Yin will be able to tell me the low down tonight, I doubt he had anything to do with it, he isn&#8217;t the riot type.</font></p>
<p><font face="Times New Roman" size="3">Meanwhile, I think that&#8217;s all I got.  All the news I feel like sharing at the moment anyway (wink).  If you make it through the whole post on Beijing I thank you for taking the time.  Check out my new pictures, I will try to get more up this week.  I have so many.  </font></p>
<p align="center"><font face="Times New Roman" size="3"><strong>&#8220;Its a mad house!  A mad house!&#8221;</strong></font></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?feed=rss2&amp;p=44</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
