<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.5" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Living the dream</title>
	<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13</link>
	<description>Won't you join me for a crazy crazy China adventure?</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 19:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.5</generator>

	<item>
		<title>by: Mariya</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-49</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 17:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-49</guid>
					<description>Hey Will, that's really fucking hilarious - we're here in France gettin' paid to do the same effin' thing, but without the singing and dancing, or any cute Asian kids.  Bill and I are 'assistants' of English at two different high schools and just like you we have no materials whatsoever to go on.  We just have to invent lessons to fill up 12 classes a week and pretend we know how to speak the language.  Anyway, it's funny to read about your experiences, cause we sure as hell have been there.  Making an insignificant bit of nonsense serve as a subject for a 50 minute class is now my forté and Bill can gesture and gesticulate his way out of any jam.  I have some worksheets I can totally forward you if you're interested, they're on stuff like stereotypes, thanksgiving, the melting pot, Nancy Pelosi, the blues, slang, some more slang, Friends the TV show, and other random shit.  All of that will leave your students blank-faced and kinda like zombies, in my experience.   We've had to improvise under the scrutinizing all-seeing eye of the snooty French beaurocracy and so far we're ok.  Much luck, keep posting stories, and check out my blogitty-blog @ www.fig-from-thistle.blogspot.com</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey Will, that&#8217;s really fucking hilarious - we&#8217;re here in France gettin&#8217; paid to do the same effin&#8217; thing, but without the singing and dancing, or any cute Asian kids.  Bill and I are &#8216;assistants&#8217; of English at two different high schools and just like you we have no materials whatsoever to go on.  We just have to invent lessons to fill up 12 classes a week and pretend we know how to speak the language.  Anyway, it&#8217;s funny to read about your experiences, cause we sure as hell have been there.  Making an insignificant bit of nonsense serve as a subject for a 50 minute class is now my forté and Bill can gesture and gesticulate his way out of any jam.  I have some worksheets I can totally forward you if you&#8217;re interested, they&#8217;re on stuff like stereotypes, thanksgiving, the melting pot, Nancy Pelosi, the blues, slang, some more slang, Friends the TV show, and other random shit.  All of that will leave your students blank-faced and kinda like zombies, in my experience.   We&#8217;ve had to improvise under the scrutinizing all-seeing eye of the snooty French beaurocracy and so far we&#8217;re ok.  Much luck, keep posting stories, and check out my blogitty-blog @ <a href="http://www.fig-from-thistle.blogspot.com" rel="nofollow">www.fig-from-thistle.blogspot.com</a>
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: marcus</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-45</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2007 07:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-45</guid>
					<description>Will you should write some space epic TV show kind of script and have your students act it out for you in english. Maybe you could break it into 5 acts and have them read a different act every day of the week. and if you are going to write a script about space. Can you put me in it because I really want to be in space. I had a dream I went to Mars and it was real.</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Will you should write some space epic TV show kind of script and have your students act it out for you in english. Maybe you could break it into 5 acts and have them read a different act every day of the week. and if you are going to write a script about space. Can you put me in it because I really want to be in space. I had a dream I went to Mars and it was real.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: james</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-44</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2007 18:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-44</guid>
					<description>Dude talk about things like favorite foods, pets, family, friends, anatomy, colors, fuck idon't know shit like that
j</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dude talk about things like favorite foods, pets, family, friends, anatomy, colors, fuck idon&#8217;t know shit like that<br />
j
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Matthew Swann age 8</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-43</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 03:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-43</guid>
					<description>Sounds like things are lookin' up bra (as Dog tha Bounty Hunter would say).   Good job with the class, if you're lookin' for conversation topics, I say use your imagination with action flicks and stuff.   I bet you can get some bootleg copies of Commando or Action Jackson and use them as examples of American culture.  Their idea of America is wapred anyway...</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sounds like things are lookin&#8217; up bra (as Dog tha Bounty Hunter would say).   Good job with the class, if you&#8217;re lookin&#8217; for conversation topics, I say use your imagination with action flicks and stuff.   I bet you can get some bootleg copies of Commando or Action Jackson and use them as examples of American culture.  Their idea of America is wapred anyway&#8230;
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: robert</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-42</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2007 17:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-42</guid>
					<description>my friend kelly says when she was teaching in China, the sing and dance question was a frequent one. apparently that's what they think we are good for.</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>my friend kelly says when she was teaching in China, the sing and dance question was a frequent one. apparently that&#8217;s what they think we are good for.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: elenore</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-40</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2007 04:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-40</guid>
					<description>yet again your life is amazing and i am proud to be along for the ride!!!!!!!!!!!
miss ya</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>yet again your life is amazing and i am proud to be along for the ride!!!!!!!!!!!<br />
miss ya
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Amy Bugg</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-39</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2007 00:52:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=13#comment-39</guid>
					<description>Dude, where are the pictures?!  Let's see em!</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dude, where are the pictures?!  Let&#8217;s see em!
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
</channel>
</rss>
