<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.5" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Boys are strong, Rabbits can jump</title>
	<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53</link>
	<description>Won't you join me for a crazy crazy China adventure?</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 19:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.5</generator>

	<item>
		<title>by: Michelle Allerdice</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53#comment-400</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2007 16:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53#comment-400</guid>
					<description>I also scroll down to the bottom of the new blogs to see how long they are.  Although, instead of deciding how many sessions it will take to read them, I try to figure out when I will have time to sit and read the entire thing at once.  

Sorry it didn't work out with Jane, but glad you had a great time dating her.

Thanks for making my Saturday morning awesome with your new blog!</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I also scroll down to the bottom of the new blogs to see how long they are.  Although, instead of deciding how many sessions it will take to read them, I try to figure out when I will have time to sit and read the entire thing at once.  </p>
<p>Sorry it didn&#8217;t work out with Jane, but glad you had a great time dating her.</p>
<p>Thanks for making my Saturday morning awesome with your new blog!
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Vanessa</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53#comment-387</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 17:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53#comment-387</guid>
					<description>Oops, I totally commented on this after a different post.  Oh well, your blog still rocks and I'm glad that this is a porn-free site that I can read at work when I should be, you know, working.</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oops, I totally commented on this after a different post.  Oh well, your blog still rocks and I&#8217;m glad that this is a porn-free site that I can read at work when I should be, you know, working.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: marcus</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53#comment-383</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 02:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53#comment-383</guid>
					<description>Will I am very glad to get your blog. Every time I see a new blog. I scroll to the bottom to see how long it is, and then I decide how many sessions it will take me to read it. So far I have not been able to walk away from a single one.

Thanks for taking me along on your Will Sanders China Adventure.

P.S. I think it is amazing what you are doing with the kids.</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Will I am very glad to get your blog. Every time I see a new blog. I scroll to the bottom to see how long it is, and then I decide how many sessions it will take me to read it. So far I have not been able to walk away from a single one.</p>
<p>Thanks for taking me along on your Will Sanders China Adventure.</p>
<p>P.S. I think it is amazing what you are doing with the kids.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Carson</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53#comment-374</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 09:17:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53#comment-374</guid>
					<description>once again, amazing, Will-in-a-Chinashop. Every new entry is my new favorite. 

I'm very sorry to hear about Jane, but you seem to be taking it standing up, so I won't go on about it. 

And I'm very glad to hear about Jamison, which you seem to be taking falling over, so I won't go on about it. 

And for the love of Mike, take care of your health. By your accounts, I wouldn't trust those Chinese doctors to tend my wounds on a battlefield in the Civil War. Have they not heard of Lister? Jesus, that's scary.</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>once again, amazing, Will-in-a-Chinashop. Every new entry is my new favorite. </p>
<p>I&#8217;m very sorry to hear about Jane, but you seem to be taking it standing up, so I won&#8217;t go on about it. </p>
<p>And I&#8217;m very glad to hear about Jamison, which you seem to be taking falling over, so I won&#8217;t go on about it. </p>
<p>And for the love of Mike, take care of your health. By your accounts, I wouldn&#8217;t trust those Chinese doctors to tend my wounds on a battlefield in the Civil War. Have they not heard of Lister? Jesus, that&#8217;s scary.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Gale</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53#comment-373</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 17:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53#comment-373</guid>
					<description>Great to read another story. I still keep expecting to see you at the Dekalb Farmers Market. Sorry you got dumped, but at least we will get you back in Atlanta some day.</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Great to read another story. I still keep expecting to see you at the Dekalb Farmers Market. Sorry you got dumped, but at least we will get you back in Atlanta some day.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Amy Bugg</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53#comment-371</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 19:57:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=53#comment-371</guid>
					<description>So now you have to teach all the boys to dance and the girls to play soccer.  They'll love it!

Thanks Will Sanders....what a great birthday I am having!! =)</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So now you have to teach all the boys to dance and the girls to play soccer.  They&#8217;ll love it!</p>
<p>Thanks Will Sanders&#8230;.what a great birthday I am having!! =)
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
</channel>
</rss>
