<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="wordpress/2.0.5" -->
<rss version="2.0" 
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: one item one should never find one&#8217;s self for want of when paying a visit to the docter in Zhengzhou</title>
	<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9</link>
	<description>Won't you join me for a crazy crazy China adventure?</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 19:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.0.5</generator>

	<item>
		<title>by: Will</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-34</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2007 10:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-34</guid>
					<description>Actually that's true, Gale.  After ten long years of work, all of my 'children' as I call them are in the finally in the last stages before world domination.  This is why I had to return to the remote test sight to oversee the last steps.  And I would have gotten away with it too if it wasn't for you peskey kids and your talking dog!

Raelle</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Actually that&#8217;s true, Gale.  After ten long years of work, all of my &#8216;children&#8217; as I call them are in the finally in the last stages before world domination.  This is why I had to return to the remote test sight to oversee the last steps.  And I would have gotten away with it too if it wasn&#8217;t for you peskey kids and your talking dog!</p>
<p>Raelle
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: wende</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-33</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 23:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-33</guid>
					<description>ps i now carrry my camera with me everywhere i go, even to work. yes, even after a year and a half here. i will never make that sort of mistake again.</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>ps i now carrry my camera with me everywhere i go, even to work. yes, even after a year and a half here. i will never make that sort of mistake again.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: wende</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-32</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 23:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-32</guid>
					<description>the first time i went to a temple here, the breathtaking beomosa temple in busan, i did cry, and i was all alone, too. it sounds like beomosa is a lego temple compared to this one, but that is generally the case. i was also fed dried squid and roasted chestnuts and given dong dong-ju (kind of a milky rice wine) by an old gramma sitting on a rock while we watched her children and grandchildren frolic in the creek. the grammas here are among my favorite people in the universe. 

also: nothing in korea is much more than 25 years old, including the temples. this is because everything has been burned to the ground so many times, by the chinese, the mongolians, the japanese, and finally by the north koreans. everything is a replica built from memory. this makes me very, very sad, but it doesn't seem to bother the koreans too much. they love new stuff.</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>the first time i went to a temple here, the breathtaking beomosa temple in busan, i did cry, and i was all alone, too. it sounds like beomosa is a lego temple compared to this one, but that is generally the case. i was also fed dried squid and roasted chestnuts and given dong dong-ju (kind of a milky rice wine) by an old gramma sitting on a rock while we watched her children and grandchildren frolic in the creek. the grammas here are among my favorite people in the universe. </p>
<p>also: nothing in korea is much more than 25 years old, including the temples. this is because everything has been burned to the ground so many times, by the chinese, the mongolians, the japanese, and finally by the north koreans. everything is a replica built from memory. this makes me very, very sad, but it doesn&#8217;t seem to bother the koreans too much. they love new stuff.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Gale</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-30</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 18:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-30</guid>
					<description>I bet the reason they did all those tests in China was for cloning. They totally want to make a master race including your DNA! Soon there will be millions of Will Sanderses running around China.</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I bet the reason they did all those tests in China was for cloning. They totally want to make a master race including your DNA! Soon there will be millions of Will Sanderses running around China.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Kate</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-29</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 14:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-29</guid>
					<description>Hey Will!  Yay for news!! Everyone is loving the blogs.  They are very funny!  Have you mastered Chop sticks yet?   I miss you!

XOXO - Kate</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey Will!  Yay for news!! Everyone is loving the blogs.  They are very funny!  Have you mastered Chop sticks yet?   I miss you!</p>
<p>XOXO - Kate
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Art history &#187; one item one should never find one&#8217;s self for want of when paying a visit to the docter in Zhengzhou</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-28</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 09:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-28</guid>
					<description>[...] Original post by Will Sanders China Adventure Blog and software by Elliott Back    Posted 17 Jan, 2007 &#124;  Categories: Uncategorized&#160; [...]</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] Original post by Will Sanders China Adventure Blog and software by Elliott Back    Posted 17 Jan, 2007 |  Categories: Uncategorized&nbsp; [&#8230;]
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: marcus</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-27</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 04:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-27</guid>
					<description>Sanders. Good to see you understand how to use the Title feature of the Blog. HTML rules!.
I am hoping to get the photo thing going but early next week. I will email you and let you show you the ropes. Hopefully it will work out on your computer. In the mean. Two days ago I was walking in front of my house which is right next to candler park and a motorcycle cop pulled me over, (yes I was walking and yes he pulled me over!) and asked me where candler park was??? uh... 

I have been checking your blog everyday waiting for the next. please keep it up.

I am going to archive the two early blogs to clean up the page a little.</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sanders. Good to see you understand how to use the Title feature of the Blog. HTML rules!.<br />
I am hoping to get the photo thing going but early next week. I will email you and let you show you the ropes. Hopefully it will work out on your computer. In the mean. Two days ago I was walking in front of my house which is right next to candler park and a motorcycle cop pulled me over, (yes I was walking and yes he pulled me over!) and asked me where candler park was??? uh&#8230; </p>
<p>I have been checking your blog everyday waiting for the next. please keep it up.</p>
<p>I am going to archive the two early blogs to clean up the page a little.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Matthew Swann age 8</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-26</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 03:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-26</guid>
					<description>Jezzumz crow, I'm totally envious/not envious of your journey.  So cool, so amazing, and so VERY uncomortable.  Your internal monologue must be going crazy.  I can't help but think that this will take you into a totally different part of your "so called life".  It's gotta make you feel on edge, but it usually makes people stronger.  Thank god not out of my comfort zone.  I'm getting drunk and watching Futurama.  Life is SUCH a mixed blessing.

Regards,
Matt

PS.  Keep bloggin'.  It's really cool.</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jezzumz crow, I&#8217;m totally envious/not envious of your journey.  So cool, so amazing, and so VERY uncomortable.  Your internal monologue must be going crazy.  I can&#8217;t help but think that this will take you into a totally different part of your &#8220;so called life&#8221;.  It&#8217;s gotta make you feel on edge, but it usually makes people stronger.  Thank god not out of my comfort zone.  I&#8217;m getting drunk and watching Futurama.  Life is SUCH a mixed blessing.</p>
<p>Regards,<br />
Matt</p>
<p>PS.  Keep bloggin&#8217;.  It&#8217;s really cool.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Carson</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-25</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 03:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-25</guid>
					<description>http://www.cs.ualberta.ca/~ading/Travel/kaifeng.jpg
probably one of the walls you were talking about (with a cool guy in front of them)

http://www.muztagh.com/images/kaifeng/kaifeng-5.jpg
the temple, i think. looks like it might have those stairs you described.</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.cs.ualberta.ca/~ading/Travel/kaifeng.jpg" rel="nofollow">http://www.cs.ualberta.ca/~ading/Travel/kaifeng.jpg</a><br />
probably one of the walls you were talking about (with a cool guy in front of them)</p>
<p><a href="http://www.muztagh.com/images/kaifeng/kaifeng-5.jpg" rel="nofollow">http://www.muztagh.com/images/kaifeng/kaifeng-5.jpg</a><br />
the temple, i think. looks like it might have those stairs you described.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>by: Will</title>
		<link>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-24</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 02:12:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid>http://willsanderschinaadventure.com/wscablog2/?p=9#comment-24</guid>
					<description>This computer is not fast enough for pictures.  I am lucky if it will pull up a page in under ten minutes without going yo yo's.  I plan to get more memory soon but in the meantime I will email you interesting facts about where I am if you like.</description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This computer is not fast enough for pictures.  I am lucky if it will pull up a page in under ten minutes without going yo yo&#8217;s.  I plan to get more memory soon but in the meantime I will email you interesting facts about where I am if you like.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
				</item>
</channel>
</rss>
